<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hardware</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Hardware</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Castle Heterodyne</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We built an Escape Room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious props to Bianca Homberg and her amazing talented group of friends for making this happen.
I was just a small piece of this epic endeavor. Bianca was the organizer and driving force for a really impressive piece of puzzle craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise for the escape room is based on the webcomic 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Girl Genius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escape-castle-heterodyne&#34;&gt;Escape Castle Heterodyne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a castle, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://girlgenius.wikia.com/wiki/Castle_Heterodyne&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Castle Heterodyne&lt;/a&gt;, which is a living, breathing, &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt; entity. In our escape room, the Castle is voiced by Mark Velednitsky. The castle&amp;rsquo;s personality is damaged, and you and your team (4 people total) have been sent into the castle to see if you can repair it. The castle, in it&amp;rsquo;s damaged state, doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand that you&amp;rsquo;re here to help. Quite the opposite in fact; it considers you hostile! At your entrance, Castle Heterodyne slams its doors shut behind you. It cuts power to the lights and activates its 30 minute self-destruct countdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you repair the castle, thereby bringing it back to its senses? Can you escape your impending doom? You must solve puzzles and make your way through four decorative challenge-filled rooms if you wish to live to see another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-engine-room&#34;&gt;The Engine Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for just the first room of the escape room (as well as, I later learned, anything requiring height). This first room was the Engine Room. When you enter the Engine Room, der Castle promptly kills the lights and initiates the castle&amp;rsquo;s self-destruct sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your challenge: get the lights up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do this by first locating a blacklight flashlight on the table in the room. You use this blacklight flashlight to read clues written in invisible ink on colored paper hidden around the room. These clues in turn allow you to figure out which of the nearly 50 switches you need to flip in order to turn all the lights on without overheating any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the puzzle looks like partial solved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;engine-room-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Engine Room: Lights Out Puzzle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the physical puzzle is no longer operational, you can have a go at the software-only version of the puzzle: &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/engine-room-demo&#34;&gt;Click here to try the puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-closet&#34;&gt;Storage Closet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you successfully turn the lights back on in the Engine Room, the castle realizes your utility, and presents you with the key to the next room: the Storage Closet. It&amp;rsquo;s too late to turn off the self-destruct sequence though, and so your only way out is forward, through the Storage Closet and the rest of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Storage Closet is in my opinion the coolest room in the Castle. I will refrain from spoiling it here (for now), and simply tell you that I was very impressed with the work that went into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escaping-the-castle&#34;&gt;Escaping the Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making your way through the Storage Closet, you must next navigate the Secret Lab, the Pink Torture Chamber (no puzzles here), and lastly the Crypt. Only after solving the puzzles in each of these rooms with the help can you escape der Castle and avoid a ghastly death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The source code for the Engine Room puzzle (both the physical version and the software-only version) is available on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bhomberg/heterodyne/blob/master/engine-room/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teach at Scale</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-07-teach-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-07-teach-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn is to teach. It&amp;rsquo;s also, most of the time, the most fun way to learn. And as an added bonus, the person you&amp;rsquo;re teaching learns too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that you, as someone who has found themselves reading strange blogs on the internet, have a lot to offer the world in the way of teaching. So I want you to teach at scale. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you Mom and Dad, former Facebook and Twitter interns, my fellow interns here at Khan Academy. I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, my Princeton and Nisky friends, and my former MathCounts students. Yes, even you, HackerNews readers and Google searchers and friends of friends. I want you to give teaching at scale a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard. Don&amp;rsquo;t mislead yourself into thinking this is an easy task that I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out for you. It takes courage and confidence. When you teach at scale, you make yourself vulnerable. You have to be ready for people to catch your mistakes and challenge your teachings. People will out-think you, and you should be ready to embrace that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, then, should you teach? I offer two suggestions. 1) Teach what you want to learn, and 2) teach what you know best. Sometimes the best teachers are not those with 10 years of teaching experience in a subject, but rather the people who remember what it&amp;rsquo;s like not to know. Teach something while the Aha! moment that helped you understand it is still fresh in your mind. The second suggestion, teach what you know best, sounds obvious, but the reason behind it has some subtlety. Don&amp;rsquo;t teach what you know best because you&amp;rsquo;ll probably avoid mistakes on that topic &amp;ndash; do it because it&amp;rsquo;s something you can speak passionately about. If your teachings get a student genuinely excited about a topic, that is worth so much more than having them quickly master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how should you get started? The simplest way is to blog. You can set up a blog and be started writing in minutes by signing up at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tumblr.com&lt;/a&gt;. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve written something educational, share it with your friends and with online communities. Related to technology? Post it on HackerNews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIY method two of teaching at scale is to make YouTube videos. I gave this a try making videos teaching Item Response Theory and Bloom Filters. Here&amp;rsquo;s my setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Personal ping-pong recording studio at the Khan Academy office&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a piece of cardboard with a hole cut out of it for a camera to look through, mounted above some paper. I used my iPhone as the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the resulting Bloom Filter videos, mistakes and stuttering and blurriness and all. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty embarrassed by them, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping future videos I produce will come out better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTFg4cPjhl-2nrkIR1z_MSTcxNeyPk4PO&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTFg4cPjhl-2nrkIR1z_MSTcxNeyPk4PO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue to make videos as I learn awesome things over the years, and I hope you do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you teach at scale is up to you. Blog. Make videos. Post code. Start a math circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be creative. The most effective teachers-at-scale are not always those who leverage technology to reach a wide audience. They are those who teach passionately, and in doing so infect others with a love for learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
