<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hardware</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Hardware</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re driving to your campsite, listening to Tiago Forte discuss Sönke Ahrens&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;How to Take Smart Notes&amp;rdquo;, when a brilliant idea strikes you. Do you pull over, pull out your phone or moleskin, and write it down? Nay. Go Note Go to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While driving, simply press the large handheld red push button and speak your idea aloud. It will be automatically transcribed and added to your notes once an internet connection becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is the latest in my line&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of headless keyboard technologies, the successor to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell (2014)&lt;/a&gt;. As with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt;, no visual components are required to operate Go Note Go. You control the system only via audio or, optionally, by typing. Unlike with shh shell, it is inadvisable to keep your eyes closed while you use it, particularly if you are driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper now into what is Go Note Go, and what it brings to the note-taking space beyond shh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-go-note-go&#34;&gt;What is Go Note Go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physically, Go Note Go is a lightweight portable keyboard with a microphone and speaker, with a beautiful handheld button attached. The keyboard is a Raspberry Pi 400 &amp;ndash; so, it&amp;rsquo;s also a full computer with WiFi, Bluetooth, and a friendly Linux operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be powered by USB-C either from a small battery pack that velcros to the back, from a port in your car, a port on your main computer, or a standard outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-go-note-go-do&#34;&gt;What does Go Note Go do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go allows audio and text note-taking, as well as arbitrary audio and text command execution. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on note-taking first. We&amp;rsquo;ll return to command execution later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main ways to enter notes with Go Note Go (audio and text), corresponding to the two main use cases (driving and camping). The use cases of shh shell (sleeping and showering) are both still supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter notes via &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt;, simply press the large red handheld push button. Then speak your notes. The recording will be saved. When internet connectivity becomes available, your audio will be automatically machine transcribed and included in your note-taking system of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter notes via &lt;em&gt;text&lt;/em&gt;, type them. Press enter to commit a note. Press shift-backspace to clear the currently typed text. When internet connectivity becomes available, your notes will be uploaded to your central note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking notes by audio is great for driving, or for whenever speaking better suits your way of thinking than typing. Being able to seamlessly go back and forth between speaking and typing can be liberating, allowing for alternating different kinds of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is compact and portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go illustrating it is compact and portable.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It velcros to the passenger side of the car dashboard. It can be used there, or placed on a passenger’s lap during use, or even on the driver’s lap at a rest stop, waiting in line at a drive-thru, or while parked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be powered by the car by USB-C, or by battery pack for use on the go (or from a laptop or outlet USB port, if that better suits your use).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-dashboard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go on the passenger side of the car dashboard.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lie down with it and type or talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-soft.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go on a sofa.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or throw it in your sports bag to take notes on the game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-gym-bag.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go in a gym bag.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-use-go-note-go-in-the-shower&#34;&gt;How do you use Go Note Go in the shower?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use Go Note Go in the shower, acquire a waterproof Bluetooth enabled keyboard, and pair it with your Go Note Go Raspberry Pi 400. Go ahead and leave that waterproof keyboard in your shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an improved experience, also acquire a waterproof Bluetooth speaker for your shower, and pair this with the Pi as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, your Pi simply has to be in range of your shower for you to use Go Note Go when generating your most groundbreaking insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No additional setup is required. Run the &amp;ldquo;:status&amp;rdquo; command to verify everything is working before typing a note to ensure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;improvements-over-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Improvements over Shh Shell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go supports audio notes and audio commands, whereas shh shell only supported text entry. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to fall asleep, text is less likely to wake up your mind, but if you&amp;rsquo;re driving, typing is incredibly dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go works offline and without a laptop nearby. To use shh shell, your keyboard needs to be connected wirelessly to a nearby computer running the shh shell software. Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s keyboard &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a computer, and it can be powered by battery pack, from a laptop, from an outlet, or from the car. Your notes will be uploaded to your main note-taking system as soon as internet connectivity becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need for &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo;. Anyone who sleeps near you will be pleased to hear Go Note Go is always in focus. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to announce &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo; for you to know if it&amp;rsquo;s OK to type. LED status indicators are also available for you to confirm it&amp;rsquo;s working (or you can run the &amp;ldquo;:status&amp;rdquo; command to get an auditory &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go integrates with external note-taking systems. I use Dropbox to store the audio clips, and Roam Research to store the notes and display the audio. This allows Go Note Go to directly contribute to my Spaced Repetition system, my notes on other projects, my notes on life, etc, and for my Go Note Go notes to be accessible anywhere, even on the go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go still supports all the old capabilities of shh shell. All the old commands still work, but now they work everywhere. Entering notes by text still works, but now it&amp;rsquo;s easier to search through them and return to them later. You can still use Go Note Go as you drift off to sleep, and you can still use Go Note Go when you shower, but now you can also use it as you drive or when you camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supported-note-taking-systems&#34;&gt;Supported Note-taking Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio clips are uploaded to Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text notes are uploaded to Roam Research, where the audio is also embedded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is extensible to support other storage systems and note-taking systems. I aim to have Go Note Go work with all popular note-taking systems. If you want to add a new note-taking system, get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;issuing-commands&#34;&gt;Issuing Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go comes with an extensible command system. Like with shh shell, you can issue a textual command by starting a note with a colon &amp;ldquo;:&amp;rdquo;. Examples of supported commands include setting alarms with &amp;ldquo;:at 9am : alarm&amp;rdquo;, or getting the time read aloud to you with &amp;ldquo;:time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell write up&lt;/a&gt; for more on text commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go supports voice commands too. I use the keyword &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo; to issue an audio command. &amp;ldquo;go go time&amp;rdquo; will cause the system to read the time aloud. And &amp;ldquo;go go read back&amp;rdquo; will have the system read back your last typed note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-it-called-go-note-go&#34;&gt;Why is it called Go Note Go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go. Like any good note-taking system, it can help you make decisions. This includes but is not limited to go/go-no decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is not implemented in Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-note-just-take-notes-on-your-computer-or-phone-or-with-a-voice-recorder&#34;&gt;Why note just take notes on your computer or phone, or with a voice recorder?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is great at reducing friction. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice to not having to switch to a note-taking app. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch tabs or windows. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anything to load. If the keyboard is there and on, you can type on it and know your notes are being recorded (there are LED status indicators for peace of mind.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also of course nice not having to do any manual uploading or transcription that other approaches might require. And being integrated with your central note-taking system is a big plus over some alternate app approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for extensible commands (e.g. for sending messages, reading emails, whatever&amp;hellip;) is a nice plus too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course my favorite feature is that there is no monitor, and so no distractions. There&amp;rsquo;s no endless scrolling on Facebook, no accidentally visiting Reddit or Twitter. Just a keyboard, a button, and your brain at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-is-go-note-go-extensible&#34;&gt;How is Go Note Go extensible?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways. You can bring your own note-taking system, and you can add arbitrary voice and textual commands to Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note-taking systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go can support uploading notes to any note-taking system. The first system we have support for is Roam Research, but adding new ones isn&amp;rsquo;t difficult. If you want to use Go Note Go with a different note-taking system, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to help you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go also supports voice and text commands. You can add your own commands as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-need-to-push-a-button-instead-of-a-wake-word&#34;&gt;Why need to push a button instead of a wake word?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m always being listened to. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want it recording conversations. I only want it to record when I tell it to, and the physical switch is quite satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two points define a line, right? &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Castle Heterodyne</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We built an Escape Room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious props to Bianca Homberg and her amazing talented group of friends for making this happen.
I was just a small piece of this epic endeavor. Bianca was the organizer and driving force for a really impressive piece of puzzle craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise for the escape room is based on the webcomic 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Girl Genius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escape-castle-heterodyne&#34;&gt;Escape Castle Heterodyne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a castle, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://girlgenius.wikia.com/wiki/Castle_Heterodyne&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Castle Heterodyne&lt;/a&gt;, which is a living, breathing, &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt; entity. In our escape room, the Castle is voiced by Mark Velednitsky. The castle&amp;rsquo;s personality is damaged, and you and your team (4 people total) have been sent into the castle to see if you can repair it. The castle, in it&amp;rsquo;s damaged state, doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand that you&amp;rsquo;re here to help. Quite the opposite in fact; it considers you hostile! At your entrance, Castle Heterodyne slams its doors shut behind you. It cuts power to the lights and activates its 30 minute self-destruct countdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you repair the castle, thereby bringing it back to its senses? Can you escape your impending doom? You must solve puzzles and make your way through four decorative challenge-filled rooms if you wish to live to see another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-engine-room&#34;&gt;The Engine Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for just the first room of the escape room (as well as, I later learned, anything requiring height). This first room was the Engine Room. When you enter the Engine Room, der Castle promptly kills the lights and initiates the castle&amp;rsquo;s self-destruct sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your challenge: get the lights up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do this by first locating a blacklight flashlight on the table in the room. You use this blacklight flashlight to read clues written in invisible ink on colored paper hidden around the room. These clues in turn allow you to figure out which of the nearly 50 switches you need to flip in order to turn all the lights on without overheating any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the puzzle looks like partial solved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;engine-room-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Engine Room: Lights Out Puzzle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the physical puzzle is no longer operational, you can have a go at the software-only version of the puzzle: &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/engine-room-demo&#34;&gt;Click here to try the puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-closet&#34;&gt;Storage Closet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you successfully turn the lights back on in the Engine Room, the castle realizes your utility, and presents you with the key to the next room: the Storage Closet. It&amp;rsquo;s too late to turn off the self-destruct sequence though, and so your only way out is forward, through the Storage Closet and the rest of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Storage Closet is in my opinion the coolest room in the Castle. I will refrain from spoiling it here (for now), and simply tell you that I was very impressed with the work that went into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escaping-the-castle&#34;&gt;Escaping the Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making your way through the Storage Closet, you must next navigate the Secret Lab, the Pink Torture Chamber (no puzzles here), and lastly the Crypt. Only after solving the puzzles in each of these rooms with the help can you escape der Castle and avoid a ghastly death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The source code for the Engine Room puzzle (both the physical version and the software-only version) is available on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bhomberg/heterodyne/blob/master/engine-room/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teach at Scale</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-07-teach-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-07-teach-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn is to teach. It&amp;rsquo;s also, most of the time, the most fun way to learn. And as an added bonus, the person you&amp;rsquo;re teaching learns too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that you, as someone who has found themselves reading strange blogs on the internet, have a lot to offer the world in the way of teaching. So I want you to teach at scale. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you Mom and Dad, former Facebook and Twitter interns, my fellow interns here at Khan Academy. I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, my Princeton and Nisky friends, and my former MathCounts students. Yes, even you, HackerNews readers and Google searchers and friends of friends. I want you to give teaching at scale a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard. Don&amp;rsquo;t mislead yourself into thinking this is an easy task that I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out for you. It takes courage and confidence. When you teach at scale, you make yourself vulnerable. You have to be ready for people to catch your mistakes and challenge your teachings. People will out-think you, and you should be ready to embrace that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, then, should you teach? I offer two suggestions. 1) Teach what you want to learn, and 2) teach what you know best. Sometimes the best teachers are not those with 10 years of teaching experience in a subject, but rather the people who remember what it&amp;rsquo;s like not to know. Teach something while the Aha! moment that helped you understand it is still fresh in your mind. The second suggestion, teach what you know best, sounds obvious, but the reason behind it has some subtlety. Don&amp;rsquo;t teach what you know best because you&amp;rsquo;ll probably avoid mistakes on that topic &amp;ndash; do it because it&amp;rsquo;s something you can speak passionately about. If your teachings get a student genuinely excited about a topic, that is worth so much more than having them quickly master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how should you get started? The simplest way is to blog. You can set up a blog and be started writing in minutes by signing up at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tumblr.com&lt;/a&gt;. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve written something educational, share it with your friends and with online communities. Related to technology? Post it on HackerNews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIY method two of teaching at scale is to make YouTube videos. I gave this a try making videos teaching Item Response Theory and Bloom Filters. Here&amp;rsquo;s my setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Personal ping-pong recording studio at the Khan Academy office&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a piece of cardboard with a hole cut out of it for a camera to look through, mounted above some paper. I used my iPhone as the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the resulting Bloom Filter videos, mistakes and stuttering and blurriness and all. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty embarrassed by them, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping future videos I produce will come out better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTFg4cPjhl-2nrkIR1z_MSTcxNeyPk4PO&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTFg4cPjhl-2nrkIR1z_MSTcxNeyPk4PO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue to make videos as I learn awesome things over the years, and I hope you do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you teach at scale is up to you. Blog. Make videos. Post code. Start a math circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be creative. The most effective teachers-at-scale are not always those who leverage technology to reach a wide audience. They are those who teach passionately, and in doing so infect others with a love for learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
