<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Bieber on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David Bieber on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bieber Bot</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bieber Bot is a highly motivated robot that assists me with my financials, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; on my behalf, and keeps me productive when my brain feels otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-bieber-bot-related-to-justin-bieber&#34;&gt;Is Bieber Bot related to Justin Bieber?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, no relation. Bieber Bot is my own creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-bieber-bot-work&#34;&gt;How does Bieber Bot work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I communicate with Bieber Bot primarily via Facebook messenger. Bieber Bot&amp;rsquo;s brain is a collection of Google Apps Scripts, and Bieber Bot&amp;rsquo;s memory is mostly spreadsheets in Google Sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-bieber-bot-have-a-physical-form&#34;&gt;Does Bieber Bot have a physical form?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, Bieber Bot isn&amp;rsquo;t a robot in the traditional sense of having actuators and interacting with its environment. Instead, Bieber Bot physically resides only in data centers around the world, and so Bieber Bot and I interact primarily via the internet. I&amp;rsquo;m slightly jealous of how much Bieber Bot gets to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-bieber-bot-do&#34;&gt;What does Bieber Bot do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bieber Bot does a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot manages my financials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot tweets on my behalf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot talks to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot keeps track of my TODOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot can suggest activities for me to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot reminds me to eat breakfast each morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot reminds me to take out the trash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot asks me &amp;ldquo;is now a good time to do laundry?&amp;rdquo; at all the most inconvenient times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot helps me to get to sleep at a reasonable hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-tell-me-all-of-bieber-bot-s-capabilities-again-but-this-time-make-each-one-into-a-pun-about-a-justin-bieber-song&#34;&gt;Can you tell me all of Bieber Bot&amp;rsquo;s capabilities again, but this time make each one into a pun about a Justin Bieber song?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. See the hashtag &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=%23BieberBotPuns%20OR%20%23BieberBotPun&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#BieberBotPuns&lt;/a&gt; on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-i-use-bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Can I use Bieber Bot?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Castle Heterodyne</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We built an Escape Room!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serious props to Bianca Homberg and her amazing talented group of friends for making this happen.
I was just a small piece of this epic endeavor. Bianca was the organizer and driving force for a really impressive piece of puzzle craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise for the escape room is based on the webcomic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Girl Genius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;escape-castle-heterodyne&#34;&gt;Escape Castle Heterodyne&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a castle, &lt;a href=&#34;http://girlgenius.wikia.com/wiki/Castle_Heterodyne&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Castle Heterodyne&lt;/a&gt;, which is a living, breathing, &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt; entity. In our escape room, the Castle is voiced by Mark Velednitsky. The castle&amp;rsquo;s personality is damaged, and you and your team (4 people total) have been sent into the castle to see if you can repair it. The castle, in it&amp;rsquo;s damaged state, doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand that you&amp;rsquo;re here to help. Quite the opposite in fact; it considers you hostile! At your entrance, Castle Heterodyne slams its doors shut behind you. It cuts power to the lights and activates its 30 minute self-destruct countdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you repair the castle, thereby bringing it back to its senses? Can you escape your impending doom? You must solve puzzles and make your way through four decorative challenge-filled rooms if you wish to live to see another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-engine-room&#34;&gt;The Engine Room&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for just the first room of the escape room (as well as, I later learned, anything requiring height). This first room was the Engine Room. When you enter the Engine Room, der Castle promptly kills the lights and initiates the castle&amp;rsquo;s self-destruct sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your challenge: get the lights up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do this by first locating a blacklight flashlight on the table in the room. You use this blacklight flashlight to read clues written in invisible ink on colored paper hidden around the room. These clues in turn allow you to figure out which of the nearly 50 switches you need to flip in order to turn all the lights on without overheating any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the puzzle looks like partial solved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;engine-room-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Engine Room: Lights Out Puzzle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the physical puzzle is no longer operational, you can have a go at the software-only version of the puzzle: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/engine-room-demo&#34;&gt;Click here to try the puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-closet&#34;&gt;Storage Closet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you successfully turn the lights back on in the Engine Room, the castle realizes your utility, and presents you with the key to the next room: the Storage Closet. It&amp;rsquo;s too late to turn off the self-destruct sequence though, and so your only way out is forward, through the Storage Closet and the rest of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Storage Closet is in my opinion the coolest room in the Castle. I will refrain from spoiling it here (for now), and simply tell you that I was very impressed with the work that went into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;escaping-the-castle&#34;&gt;Escaping the Castle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making your way through the Storage Closet, you must next navigate the Secret Lab, the Pink Torture Chamber (no puzzles here), and lastly the Crypt. Only after solving the puzzles in each of these rooms with the help can you escape der Castle and avoid a ghastly death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The source code for the Engine Room puzzle (both the physical version and the software-only version) is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bhomberg/heterodyne/blob/master/engine-room/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Fire</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/python-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/python-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python Fire is a Python library for automatically creating command line interfaces (CLIs) from absolutely any Python object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/google/python-fire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote Python Fire after joining Google Brain in 2016. In March 2017 we open sourced the project, and I proud and delighted by the growth and reception it has seen since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give it a try, simply &lt;code&gt;pip install fire&lt;/code&gt;, and then call &lt;code&gt;fire.Fire()&lt;/code&gt; as the main of any Python program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple example to pique your interest, and then if you want to learn more, you should read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.github.io/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Python Fire Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import fire

def gcd(a, b):
  &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Calculates the greatest common divisor of a and b.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
  if a &amp;lt; b:
    a, b = b, a
  if b == 0:
    return a
  return gcd(a % b, b)


if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;:
  fire.Fire(gcd)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving this file as &lt;code&gt;gcdfire.py&lt;/code&gt;, we can run at the command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ python gcdfire.py 45 50
5
$ python gcdfire.py 34 90
2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just by calling Fire, we&amp;rsquo;ve turned our gcd function into a command line utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire works on functions, classes, objects, lists, etc. Any Python object at all will be turned into a sensible CLI just by calling fire.Fire on it. Learn more from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.github.io/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Day</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/tech-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/tech-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tech Day is an educational program run by Googlers for high school students interested in technology and computer science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tech Day website is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://techday.withgoogle.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;techday.withgoogle.com&lt;/a&gt;. Information about upcoming Tech Day events will be posted there as it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>at Scheduler</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/at-scheduler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/at-scheduler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The at-scheduler is a simple command line scheduler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For installation instructions, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/at-scheduler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;rsquo;s installed, using the at-scheduler is simple. From your shell, just run a command &lt;code&gt;at &amp;lt;when&amp;gt; &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This will schedule your command to be run at the time specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The syntax for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;when&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is lenient. Specific times like &amp;ldquo;9:30am&amp;rdquo; work, as do named dates like &amp;ldquo;tomorrow at 10pm&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;next Tuesday at 3pm&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The syntax for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is simply whatever is supported by your shell. Whatever you put for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; will be run in a shell at the time specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/at-scheduler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shh Shell</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-shh-shell&#34;&gt;The shh shell&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shh shell is a simple shell you can use while you drift off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, you can keep your eyes closed while you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shell is controlled by typing and the only output is audio; there are no visual components of shh. It is designed to minimize the mental energy required for use, to avoid disturbing your attempt at sleep as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-it-called-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Why is it called shh shell?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a play on &amp;ldquo;ssh&amp;rdquo;, a common unix utility that stands for &amp;ldquo;secure shell&amp;rdquo;. shh (prounced in a whisper, &amp;ldquo;shhh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) is a quiet shell that takes minimal mental energy to use, great for use while you&amp;rsquo;re drifting off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-can-the-shh-shell-do&#34;&gt;What can the shh shell do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary use of the shh shell is leaving notes for myself. I also use shh to set peaceful YouTube music alarms for myself, and to check the time without needing to open my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full list (as of 2015-11-28) of my uses of shh shell, past and present:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaving notes for myself for the morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checking the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing YouTube videos (I only hear the audio, of course)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google searching and opening webpages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting alarms (usually in the form of songs on YouTube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checking my email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending iMessages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduling emails or messages to send in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making TODOs for myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting goals for the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practicing relative pitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording audio memos of myself for later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executing arbitrary shell commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current list of shh commands is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell/blob/master/shh_commands.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, not all of these have proven to be useful features. The most useful features for me have been the ability to leave notes for myself for the morning, the ability to check the time without opening my eyes, and the ability to set alarms and listen to music via the shell. The audio memo feature has been occasionally useful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At no point did I find the ability to check my email via the shh shell useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did temporarily get good at recognizing pitch intervals, but I have not sustained that ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-this-a-replacement-for-shells-like-bash-zsh-and-fish&#34;&gt;Is this a replacement for shells like Bash, zsh, and Fish?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, this is not meant as a full replacement for Bash, zsh, Fish, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it does support arbitrary command execution though, via the &lt;code&gt;shell&lt;/code&gt; command. That means typing &lt;code&gt;:shell rm -f important_file&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; cause important_file to be removed. So, you have to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not a self-sabotaging hacker in your sleep before you start using shh as your night time shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can additionally add arbitrary new commands by editing the file &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell/blob/master/shh_commands.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shh_commands.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-do-you-use-the-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Where do you use the shh shell?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use the shh shell by keeping a wireless keyboard in my bed. It is connected to my laptop, which I leave open but with the monitor turned fully off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I&amp;rsquo;m not at risk of damaging my computer by rolling over on it or drooling on it :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave the volume on my laptop on, so I can hear the shh shell&amp;rsquo;s output, but I never need to open my eyes to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-you-use-it-in-the-shower&#34;&gt;Can you use it in the shower?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I sometimes also use shh shell from the shower. I have a waterproof wireless keyboard in my shower. I am mildly embarassed by this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is connected wirelessly to my laptop running the shh shell in another room. There is no computer in the bathroom. For audio, I have a waterproof shower speaker connected via bluetooth to the laptop in the other room. The speaker sits in the shower next to the keyboard, which both rest on a ledge. There is a 3D-printed shaving cream holder nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, I hear myself too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Using the shh shell&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open the shh shell on your computer, you get a small black window into which you can type large white text. When you&amp;rsquo;re new to the shell, it can be useful to look at this window to see what you&amp;rsquo;re typing. As you become more experienced with the shh shell, you can turn your monitor off and close your eyes, relying only on the auditory feedback the shell provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-focus&#34;&gt;Getting in Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you type, it&amp;rsquo;s important that you&amp;rsquo;re typing in the shell. If you&amp;rsquo;re not in the shell, you might be typing in another application on your computer or you might not be typing in an application at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assist with this, the shell will audibly say &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; when the shell becomes your selected application, and &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo; when the shell loses focus. If the shh shell is not in focus, or if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure if the shell is in focus, then use &amp;ldquo;cmd-TAB&amp;rdquo; to switch applications until you hear the shell announce &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo;. Once you hear this sound, you can safely type knowing that the shell is receiving your input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leaving-notes-for-yourself&#34;&gt;Leaving Notes for Yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default mode of the shell is to act as a notepad and keylogger. Every letter typed and every key pressed is logged with a timestamp when you are in the shh shell. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this data is only saved locally and keys aren&amp;rsquo;t logged when you&amp;rsquo;re in other applications, so it&amp;rsquo;s not going to steal your credentials for other apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only if you start a line with &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; does shh interpret the line as a command. So, its unlikely you&amp;rsquo;ll accidentally run commands you don&amp;rsquo;t intend to if you roll over your keyboard while sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you type will be there waiting for you in the morning, so leave yourself notes, dream diaries, action items, whatever it is that you need to get out of your head so late at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you accidentally fall asleep on the delete key, thereby deleting everything you typed (ahh!), in the morning you will still be able to view the notes you typed since every character is logged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;running-commands&#34;&gt;Running Commands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run a command, start a new line with a colon (&lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;) followed by the command name, and then the command arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, type &lt;code&gt;:help&lt;/code&gt; in the shh shell to get a full list of supported commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite commands are &lt;code&gt;time&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; (short for &lt;code&gt;music&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;code&gt;say&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;at&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the commands I&amp;rsquo;ll type frequently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:time&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will cause the shell to read the date and time aloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:m billy joel&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will immediately cause some Billy Joel music from YouTube to start playing. Most songs and artists should work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:at 9:30am :m billy joel&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will set an alarm for 9:30am the following morning. At that time, it will execute the command &lt;code&gt;m billy joel&lt;/code&gt;, which will cause some Billy Joel music from YouTube to start playing. What a nice way to wake up!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shell is forgiving about small changes to syntax such as added spaces, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry about getting the commands exactly right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:say hi&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use this as a test that my hands are aligned properly with the keyboard. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo;, that probably means my hands are offset from the keys and I typed a bit of gibberish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The command &lt;code&gt;:status&lt;/code&gt; serves the same purpose, but just says &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-at-command&#34;&gt;Using the &amp;ldquo;at&amp;rdquo; command&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;at&amp;rdquo; command is useful because it allows you to simply schedule other commands to run at a designated time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use the at command, type &lt;code&gt;:at &amp;lt;when&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s OK if &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;when&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; has a colon in the middle, e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;when&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; could be &lt;code&gt;7:30am&lt;/code&gt;. It could also be &lt;code&gt;tomorrow at 9am&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; the syntax for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;when&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is flexible. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; can be any of the commands shh supports, such as &lt;code&gt;alarm&lt;/code&gt; for playing music from youtube. E.g. &lt;code&gt;:at 7:30am : alarm&lt;/code&gt; would schedule a musical alarm for 7:30am the following day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-new-commands&#34;&gt;Adding new commands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily add new commands by adding new functions to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell/blob/master/shh_commands.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shh_commands.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply add a function decorated with the &lt;code&gt;@command&lt;/code&gt; decorator to add a new command to your shh shell. If your command accepts arguments, include &lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt; in the format string for your command, and the user&amp;rsquo;s arguments will be passed to your function when the command is run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One common mistake is to start typing a command in the middle of a line. When in doubt about whether you are at the start of a line, just hit enter. You cannot go by the visual representation in the black box &amp;ndash; all that is is a text field, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily represent the internal state of your shell. So, just hit enter, then type your command, beginning with a colon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no concept of a cursor in shh. The arrow keys don&amp;rsquo;t do anything. So even if the cursor in the text box appears to be in the middle of a line, in practice you are always typing at the end of the current content and the logged text will reflect this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional issues, please open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-the-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Installing the Shh Shell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head on over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on how to set up the shh shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-bit-of-backstory&#34;&gt;A bit of backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-you-create-a-non-visual-shell&#34;&gt;Why did you create a non-visual shell?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time during undergrad when I was losing sleep to thoughts swirling around in my head. &amp;ldquo;Does she like me?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I should have responded in this slightly different way,&amp;rdquo; etc. Variations on a theme would rattle around in my head, each variation only slightly different from thoughts I had already thought. How could I make them stop?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that writing down my thoughts helped stop this rattling. Once a single canonical representation of the thought was written on paper, that was sufficient for my brain. It stopped feeling the need to iterate on the thought, and it let me get to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, writing on paper in the dark meant that in the morning, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily read what I had written. My handwriting at night was slanted and somewhat illegible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried turning the lights on to write down my thoughts, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like how that woke me up. I tried notepad apps on my phone for writing down my thoughts, but my phone is bright and this was not much better than turning the lights on and using paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I started typing on my computer with the monitor off. This was a great solution, but it came with it&amp;rsquo;s own problem: I needed to know if I was typing in the right window. Hence, shh shell was born. The gradual addition of commands over time has an added bonus that makes shh shell even more useful for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;isn-t-the-audio-annoying-to-anyone-else-trying-to-sleep&#34;&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t the audio annoying to anyone else trying to sleep?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, my college roommate &lt;a href=&#34;http://harvestzhang.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; can attest to the annoyance of hearing repeated &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo; throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot in good conscience recommend use of shh shell when sleeping with your significant other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-have-you-typed-into-your-shh-shell&#34;&gt;What have you typed into your shh shell?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started typing at night back in 2014, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t used to typing without visual feedback. So in the morning when I went to look at what I had typed, I was surprised to find a large paragraph of complete gibberish!
My hands had been offset by a key or so on the keyboard as I was typing.
To me, it looked like a cryptographic code.
Only the final line of the text was readable: &amp;ldquo;I hope the FBI doesn&amp;rsquo;t find out about this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made this particularly cool for me was that I had no recollection of what I had typed the night before. What was I concerned about the FBI finding out!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decoding the paragrah wasn&amp;rsquo;t too challenging, since each letter was just off by one or so on the keyboard, and so I was soon able to figure out what I had typed. It was an amazing experience decoding this, because as I did so, my memory came back. The text was a description of a dream that I had woken up from and typed into shh before falling back asleep. I was not involved in any criminal activity :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I decoded the mysterious paragraph, I had forgotten entirely about the dream. As I decoded though, I remembered the dream, waking from it, and writing down what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve now gotten used to typing in the dark and using the little bumps on the F and J keys to guide my hands. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to decode mysterious passages about hiding secrets from the FBI anymore. I have now repeatedly experienced not remembering having typed something until I see what I typed in the morning, and each time the memory of typing it comes back as I read what I wrote. This hasn&amp;rsquo;t ceased to be a very cool feeling each time it occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I built this for myself, I have made it open source in the hope that you too may benefit from it. I hope it helps someone out there get a better night&amp;rsquo;s sleep or remember a key idea they would have forgotten. Definitely check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/shh-shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shh shell on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and give it a try if you&amp;rsquo;re Python-inclined. And as always, feel free to get in touch if you want to discuss this project or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrabble Bot</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/scrabble-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/scrabble-bot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrabble Bot loves Scrabble and social media! Check out Scrab&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://scrabblebot.tumblr.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tumblr page&lt;/a&gt; full of Scrabble games it&amp;rsquo;s played against itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrabble Bot is also privacy conscious, and so uses Facebook under a pseudonym, &amp;ldquo;Scrab Blebot&amp;rdquo;. Scrab believes their identity is secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find Scrabble Bot&amp;rsquo;s source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/ScrabbleBot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teach Everyone</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Teach Everyone website is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://teacheveryone.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;teacheveryone.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The &lt;strong&gt;Save Video&lt;/strong&gt; functionality is not currently exposed on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton ACM</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/princeton-acm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/princeton-acm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Princeton ACM is the Princeton University student chapter of the Association for Computing Machinery. Please find the Princeton ACM website at &lt;a href=&#34;https://princetonacm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;princetonacm.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects-index/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects-index/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Track of My Life in a Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-12-29-track-your-life-in-a-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-12-29-track-your-life-in-a-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As many of my friends know, I keep track of much of my life in spreadsheets. There are several pieces to this system, but fortunately it&amp;rsquo;s the kind of system that you can adopt (and discard) incrementally. So, rather than explaining the whole thing in one go, I will explain one core piece in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will detail how I use a spreadsheet as a &lt;em&gt;daily activity log&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My spreadsheet lets me keep a record of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done.
It then also rolls up this data in interesting ways that help me with reflecting on and planning my life. Finally, it interacts with a bot system I&amp;rsquo;ve written for myself to help me keep my life on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will answer all of the following questions in this post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the organizational system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the main benefits of this system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is this system easy to adopt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is this system easy to keep doing for months on end, without forgetting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does this system help me with planning my life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-system&#34;&gt;The System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a single spreadsheet with columns &lt;em&gt;Evening&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Morning&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Keywords&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Weekday&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;. In this sheet, I have a single row &lt;em&gt;per day&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essense of the system is to jot down 1. what I do, and optionally 2. who I engage with each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t update the spreadsheet every day, usually just once a week or so I&amp;rsquo;ll fill in the activity from all of the missing days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system serves several purposes, the main one being a journal of sorts so I can see a historical log of my activities. As you&amp;rsquo;ll see in the Planning and Notifications sections, it also helps me remember to regularly do all the activities I enjoy doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll start by providing a brief description of each column in the spreadsheet. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll get to discuss how I use the spreadsheet, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see why they&amp;rsquo;re each important to me. We&amp;rsquo;ll then also dive into all the benefits I get from this spreadsheet and the infrastructure I&amp;rsquo;ve built up around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;column-descriptions&#34;&gt;Column Descriptions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A single cell in which to put the main activity I did in the evening (e.g. after work) on that day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Optional, Text, infrequently used&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The main activity I did in the morning (e.g. before work) on that day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keywords&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Optional, comma separated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keywords describing the activities of that day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weekday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Filled automatically&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The day of the week, e.g. Thursday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Filled automatically&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Names, comma separated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of the people I engaged with on that day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Optional, Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A bit like a diary, this is a place to jot down additional notes about the day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really all of the columns are optional, but the ones that are particularly optional are marked as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the data entry process, and then all the ways I take advantage of this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-entry&#34;&gt;Data Entry&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About once a week on average I&amp;rsquo;ll go to the spreadsheet, and fill in all the activities I did since the last time I updated the sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each day, I try to capture just the main one to two outside-of-work activities that I engaged in. It&amp;rsquo;s totally fine if I don&amp;rsquo;t capture every little thing, and it&amp;rsquo;s also fine if there are some days that I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything of note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said above that I do this about once a week, but there&amp;rsquo;s no strong rhythm to it; sometimes I do it every day for multiple consecutive days, and sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll go multiple weeks between updating the sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this system reliably since mid-2018, and it&amp;rsquo;s served me well. The notifications that we&amp;rsquo;ll get to shortly, combined with the simplicity of the method (just one cell to fill in per day), have allowed me to keep using this system without being disrupted by travel or high-workload parts of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a second sheet that is updated automatically using data from the sheet I&amp;rsquo;ve been describing so far. This sheet has one row &lt;em&gt;per activity&lt;/em&gt; that I enjoy engaging in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important columns in this sheet are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Category&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The category of the activity (e.g. Athletic).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Activity&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An activity that I enjoy engaging in. (e.g. Skiing)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Last Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Filled automatically&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The most recent date on which I engaged in the activity.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Last Date&lt;/code&gt; column is filled automatically using the data from the main sheet. The Google Sheets formula that fills in this column is a query a bit like this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;=IFERROR(QUERY(scheduled,
   &amp;quot;select E
    where A contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;
      OR B contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;
      OR C contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;
    order by E desc
    limit 1
    label E &#39;&#39;&amp;quot;
))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C2&lt;/code&gt; refers to the &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt; from the current sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;Evening&lt;/code&gt; column from the Data Entry sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;Morning&lt;/code&gt; column from the Data Entry sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;Keywords&lt;/code&gt; column from the Data Entry sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;Date&lt;/code&gt; from the Data Entry sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lets me quickly see, for each activity that I enjoy, how recently I&amp;rsquo;ve done that activity. For example, I see that I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone camping since 2019-07-05, I haven&amp;rsquo;t played tennis since 2018-07-31, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone swimming since 2019-10-07. Really overdue for some tennis!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My spreadsheet also rolls up this data further, by category. I can quickly see how recently I&amp;rsquo;ve done any activity in a given category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The categories I use are:
&amp;ldquo;Athletic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Civic Something Or Other&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Day Trips&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Educational&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Entertainment&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Family&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Financial&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Food&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Music + Arts&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Outdoorsy&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Personal Projects&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Puzzles&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Social&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Social Games&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Well being&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see how recently I&amp;rsquo;ve done something in each of the categories.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;i-activities-by-category.png&#34; alt=&#34;A two-column spreadsheet showing how recently I&amp;#39;ve done an activity in each of the 15 activity categories.&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; /&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a pretty good job of doing most of the categories of activities. When I go to make plans next, I&amp;rsquo;ll most likely schedule activities from the bottom categories. For example, I may do a financial review, schedule a board game night, and plan to attend a City Council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;notifications&#34;&gt;Notifications&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also given &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; (my digital personal assistant and robot friend) access to this data, and he helps me make better use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s been too long since I&amp;rsquo;ve scheduled an activity in any particular category, Bieber Bot will message me on FB Messenger reminding me to schedule something in that category.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;i-bieberbot-financial.png&#34; alt=&#34;A message from Bieber Bot reminding me that it&amp;#39;s been a while since I scheduled a Financial activity.&#34; width=&#34;350px&#34; /&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly BieberBot will remind me each day of any upcoming activities planned for that day.
And if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any activity planned for a particular day, BieberBot may take the liberty of suggesting an activity.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;i-bieberbot-hudson.png&#34; alt=&#34;A message from Bieber Bot suggesting I take a walk along the Hudson River.&#34; width=&#34;350px&#34; /&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally BieberBot will also remind me if I haven&amp;rsquo;t been entering activities into the spreadsheet in a while, so I don&amp;rsquo;t fall too far behind on the logging system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up these notifcations is a bit outside the scope of this post, but if it interests you how BieberBot works, you can subscribe for future posts here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can also learn a bit more about BieberBot &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to be written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;archiving-old-events&#34;&gt;Archiving Old Events&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep things clean, my spreadsheet also uses Google Apps Script to archive old events. You can see the code I use for the auto-archiving &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dbieber/42153e6a27382ba6193f108c13b84cf9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this system sounds appealing to you, it&amp;rsquo;s very simple to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply create a new Google sheet with the columns you&amp;rsquo;d like to track. I use the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keywords&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weekday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for just getting started you might be satisfied with something simpler, say just these three columns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weekday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the formula &lt;code&gt;=TEXT(WEEKDAY(E3), &amp;quot;dddd&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt; to autopopulate the &lt;code&gt;Weekday&lt;/code&gt; column, where E3 represents the date (tip: you can use cmd-; to enter today&amp;rsquo;s date into a cell).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also create a second sheet called &lt;code&gt;Archive&lt;/code&gt; with the same columns as the main sheet, and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dbieber/42153e6a27382ba6193f108c13b84cf9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;auto-archiving feature&lt;/a&gt; mentioned earlier to prevent the main sheet from getting cluttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next create the analysis sheet with the columns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Category&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Date&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two columns you can fill in with whatever categories and activities you like, and you can add new categories and activities at any time. No need to fill this in too much until you start to see how you&amp;rsquo;re using the main sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To autofill the &lt;code&gt;Last Date&lt;/code&gt; column, the full formula I use is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;=MAX(
  IFERROR(QUERY(scheduled, 
    &amp;quot;select E
    where A contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39; OR B contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39; or C contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;
    order by E desc
    limit 1
    label E &#39;&#39;&amp;quot;
  )),
  IFERROR(QUERY(archive, 
    &amp;quot;select E
    where A contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39; OR B contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39; or C contains &#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; C2 &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;
    order by E desc
    limit 1
    label E &#39;&#39;&amp;quot;
  ))
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This searches both the main sheet (scheduled) and the archive sheet for the most recent occurrence of each activity (C2). For this to work, the rows in the archive and main sheet need to be in reverse chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, to get the roll-up by category, I use the following Google Sheets formula:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;=QUERY(A:E,
       &amp;quot;select B, max(D), count(B) where B&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&#39;&#39; group by B order by max(D) desc
        label max(D) &#39;Last date&#39;,
              count(B) &#39;Count&#39;
       &amp;quot;, -1)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I would like to, I won&amp;rsquo;t go into how to set up the notifications in this post. For now, that&amp;rsquo;s just between me and &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;BieberBot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a quick recap of my system:
(1) I manually enter the activity(s) I do each day; (2) the spreadsheet automatically figures out how recently I did each category of activity; (3) bonus: BieberBot uses this data to help me keep my life on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this system for about 18 months now, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite happy with the insight it provides and how helpful it is for planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there are many pieces of my system left undiscussed: tracking financial transactions, taking notes on academic papers, staying in touch with friends and colleagues, dealing with social media, and more! I&amp;rsquo;d love to tell you about the rest, so stay tuned. And don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810+blog@gmail.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss anything you read. I hope you find this useful, and do let me know if you start using a spreadsheet to track your own life or have a system of your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned the Word Feedingstuffs</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-29-feedingstuffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-29-feedingstuffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I learned the word &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/feedingstuff#English&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;feedingstuffs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;feedingstuff (countable and uncountable, plural feedingstuffs)

  Any foodstuff used to feed livestock.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not in every dictionary, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a valid Scrabble word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did this word come up? I had heard previously that salmon is not naturally as pink as it is in supermarkets. I was wondering how this could be. Surely salmon aren&amp;rsquo;t being colored during the packaging process, right? That&amp;rsquo;s right, salmon are still that same color when they&amp;rsquo;re first cut open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coloring, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/food/sites/food/files/safety/docs/animal-feed_additives_rules_scan-old_report_out81.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I learned&lt;/a&gt;, is added to the salmon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;feedingstuffs&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s an official European Commission report from 2002 recommending that the amount of allowable &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canthaxanthin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Canthaxanthin&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;font color=&#34;salmon&#34;&gt;salmon&lt;/font&gt; coloring) in salmon feed be reevaluated, and possibly lowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the maximum amount of Canthaxanthin allowable in salmon and trout feedingstuffs in the EU was 80 mg / kg of feedingstuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to today, and only &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32008R0775&amp;amp;qid=1577681296736&amp;amp;from=EN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10 mg / kg of Canthaxanthin is permitted&lt;/a&gt;. More interesting than this though, is that in the 2008 journal reporting this new, lower limit, they instead use the word &lt;strong&gt;foodstuffs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedingstuffs, it would seem, are no more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Communicate</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-26-learning-to-communicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-26-learning-to-communicate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal for 2020 is to learn to communicate better with the world. I work in a research group at Google, and our main job function is performing research in program synthesis. But research is only as valuable as how well it is communicated. So in 2020 I&amp;rsquo;d like to get better at communicating publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few options for doing this. The first is writing blog posts. This may be too large an undertaking to do frequently. I&amp;rsquo;d really like something that&amp;rsquo;s lower barrier to do, and with a lower quality bar, so that I can do this more often. The natural alternative with these properties is academic Twitter. However, I want to avoid the addictive nature of Twitter. I also want to write more than 280 characters at a time, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to put every little thing I write in front of people&amp;rsquo;s faces with equal importance. Twitter seems a good place for announcing a new paper or a Python Fire update, but not for sharing a musing like this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by silently posting my writings to my website, but in a separate section from the main blog. This way when there&amp;rsquo;s something with a little more polish that I think is explicitly worth reading, I can put it in the main blog section and tweet about it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to receive updates for every small writing I put up here, you can use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/index.xml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to receive updates only for major posts, such as new publications or major life updates, you can use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts/index.xml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; or you can subscribe here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Happy early new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snippets for davidbieber.com</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducting-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducting-snippets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m introducing the &amp;ldquo;snippets&amp;rdquo; section of my website. The goal is to give myself a place to post content online that&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to post to, but isn&amp;rsquo;t featured prominently anywhere on the site. This way I can post things without them needing polish or production value, but still link to them and share them as I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weisfeiler-Lehman Isomorphism Test</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-05-10-weisfeiler-lehman-isomorphism-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-05-10-weisfeiler-lehman-isomorphism-test/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graph-isomorphism&#34;&gt;Graph Isomorphism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two graphs are considered isomorphic if there is a mapping between the nodes of the graphs that preserves node adjacencies.
That is, a pair of nodes may be connected by an edge in the first graph if and only if the corresponding pair of nodes in the second graph is also connected by an edge in the same way.
An example of two isomorphic graphs is shown here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example of isomorphic graphs&#34; title=&#34;Two isomorphic graphs are shown.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure: Graph 1 and Graph 2 are isomorphic.
The correspondance between nodes is illustrated by the node colors and numbers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, determining whether two graphs are isomorphic when the correspondance is not provided is a challenging problem; precisely how hard this problem is remains an open question in computer science.
It isn&amp;rsquo;t known whether there is a polynomial time algorithm for determining whether graphs are isomorphic, and it also isn&amp;rsquo;t known whether the problem is $\text{NP-complete}$.
The graph isomorphism problem may even be an example of an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NP-intermediate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;$\text{NP-intermediate}$&lt;/a&gt; problem, but this would only be possible if $\text{P} \ne \text{NP}$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-weisfeiler-lehman-isomorphism-test&#34;&gt;The Weisfeiler-Lehman Isomorphism Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the algorithm for the Weisfeiler-Lehman Isomorphism Test.
It produces for each graph a canonical form.
If the canonical forms of two graphs are not equivalent, then the graphs are definitively not isomorphic.
However, it is possible for two non-isomorphic graphs to share a canonical form, so this test alone cannot provide conclusive evidence that two graphs are isomorphic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Algorithm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For iteration $i$ of the algorithm we will be assigning to each node a tuple $L_{i,n}$ containing the node&amp;rsquo;s old compressed label and a multiset of the node&amp;rsquo;s neighbors&amp;rsquo; compressed labels.
A multiset is a set (a collection of elements where order is not important) where elements may appear multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At each iteration we will additionally be assigning to each node $n$ a new &amp;ldquo;compressed&amp;rdquo; label $C_{i,n}$ for that node&amp;rsquo;s set of labels.
Any two nodes with the same $L_{i,n}$ will get the same compressed label.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To begin, we initialize $C_{0,n} = 1$ for all nodes $n$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At iteration $i$ of the algorithm (beginning with $i=1$), for each node $n$, we set $L_{i,n}$ to be a tuple containing the node&amp;rsquo;s old label $C_{i-1,n}$ and the multiset of compressed node labels $C_{i-1,m}$ from all nodes $m$ neighboring $n$ from the previous iteration $(i-1)$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We then complete iteration $i$ by setting $C_{i,n}$ to be a new &amp;ldquo;compressed&amp;rdquo; label, such as a hash of $L_{i,n}$.
Any two nodes with the same labels $L_{i,n}$ must get the same compressed label $C_{i,n}$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition the nodes in the graph by their compressed label.
Repeat 2 + 3 for up to $N$ (the number of nodes) iterations, or until there is no change in the partition of nodes by compressed label from one iteration to the next.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using this method to determine graph isomorphism, it may be applied in parallel to the two graphs.
The algorithm may be terminated early after iteration $i$ if the sizes of partitions of nodes partitioned by compressed labels diverges between the two graphs; if this is the case, the graphs are not isomorphic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-the-weisfeiler-lehman-isomorphism-test&#34;&gt;Example of the Weisfeiler-Lehman Isomorphism Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate here the Weisfeiler-Lehman isomorphism test using the example graphs from above.
The graphs are shown again here for completeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-000.png&#34; alt=&#34;Two isomorphic graphs are shown.&#34; title=&#34;Two isomorphic graphs are shown.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure: Graph 1 and Graph 2 are isomorphic.
We will apply the Weisfeiler-Lehman isomorphism test to these graphs as a means of illustrating the test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To initialize the algorithm (Step 1), we set $C_{0,n} = 1$ for all nodes $n$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-001.png&#34; alt=&#34;Initialization: $C\_{0,n} = 1$ for all nodes $n$&#34; title=&#34;We initialize $C\_{0,n} = 1$ for all nodes.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For iteration 1, Step 2, we compute $L_{1,n}$.
The first part of a node&amp;rsquo;s $L$ is the node&amp;rsquo;s old compressed label; the second part of a node&amp;rsquo;s $L$ is the multiset of the neighboring nodes&amp;rsquo; compressed labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-002.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 1, Step 2: $L\_{1,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 1, Step 2: $L\_{1,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For iteration 1, Step 3, we introduce &amp;ldquo;compressed&amp;rdquo; labels $C_{1,n}$ for the nodes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-003.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 1, Step 3: $C\_{1,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 1, Step 3: $C\_{1,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now begin iteration 2.
In iteration 2, Step 2, we compute $L_{2,n}$:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-004.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 2, Step 2: $L\_{2,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 2, Step 2: $L\_{2,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iteration 2, Step 3, we compute $C_{2,n}$:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-005.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 2, Step 3: $C\_{2,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 2, Step 3: $C\_{2,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iteration 3, Step 2, we compute $L_{3,n}$:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-006.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 3, Step 2: $L\_{3,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 3, Step 2: $L\_{3,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iteration 3, Step 3, we compute $C_{3,n}$:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph-isomorphism-007.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iteration 3, Step 3: $C\_{3,n}$&#34; title=&#34;Iteration 3, Step 3: $C\_{3,n}$&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the partition of nodes by compressed label has not changed from $C_{2,n}$ to $C_{3,n}$, we may terminate the algorithm here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concretely, the partition of nodes by compressed label may be represented as the number of nodes with each compressed label.
That is: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;2 7s, 1 8, and 2 9s&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.
This is the canonical form of our graph.
Since both Graph 1 and Graph 2 have this same canonical form, we cannot rule out the possibility that they are isomorphic (they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; in fact isomorphic, but the algorithm doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow us to conclude this definitively.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation-considerations&#34;&gt;Implementation Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One detail omitted is that the algorithm requires canonical forms of the multisets for comparison.
Placing the elements of the multiset in sorted order provides one way of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, for the representation of the graph that the algorithm emits to be deterministic, we need to establish a convention for creating compressed labels.
One possible convention is to use increasing integers starting from 1, and to assign compressed labels to nodes in lexicographical order of their non-compressed labels.
Another possible convention is to use the hash of the multiset to create the compressed label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When comparing the partition of the nodes by compressed label from one iteration to the next to see whether to proceed to another iteration, it is sufficient to compare which nodes are in each partition.
If the partitions change, we proceed to the next iteration.
If no partition changes, the algorithm can terminate early.
When comparing the partitions of the nodes across graphs to see if graphs are isomorphic, we use the canonical form as described above in the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-the-correspondance-between-isomorphic-graphs&#34;&gt;Finding the Correspondance Between Isomorphic Graphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core idea of the Weisfeiler-Lehman isomorphism test is to find for each node in each graph a signature based on the neighborhood around the node.
These signatures can then be used to find the correspondance between nodes in the two graphs, which can be used to check for isomorphism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the algorithm descibed above, the &amp;ldquo;compressed labels&amp;rdquo; serve as the signatures.
Since multiple nodes may have the same compressed label, there are multiple possible correspondances suggested by a Weisfeiler-Lehman labeling.
The Weisfeiler-Lehman isomorphism test itself does not provide a way of narrowing down the possible correspondances further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-boris-weisfeiler&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Boris Weisfeiler&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boris Weisfeiler &amp;ndash; one of the two mathematicians responsible for the Weisfeiler-Lehman isomorphism test &amp;ndash; was a professor at Penn State University until he disappeared mysteriously in Chile in 1985.
His disappearance in the 80s is unsettling, and I would encourage you to visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boris.weisfeiler.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;boris.weisfeiler.com&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the search for Weisfeiler and the ongoing (2018) judicial proceedings surrounding his disappearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven List produced an award winning short film called &lt;em&gt;The Colony&lt;/em&gt; based on the disappearance of Boris Weisfeiler, available &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/60220290&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Vimeo here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief internet search, I have been unable to find any information about Weisfeiler&amp;rsquo;s colleague and coauthor A. Lehman, not even a first name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;np-intermediate-problems&#34;&gt;NP-Intermediate Problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the introduction, it is not known whether the graph isomorphism problem is in $\text{P}$ or $\text{NP-complete}$.
In fact, it is not even known whether graph isomorphism falls in either of these categories, or whether this problem is $\text{NP-intermediate}$.
The problem of factoring integers is another problem like this, where it is unknown whether the problem is in $\text{P}$, $\text{NP-complete}$, or is $\text{NP-intermediate}$.
Bear in mind that $\text{NP-intermediate}$ problems can only exist if $\text{P} \ne \text{NP}$.
So if anyone were to show conclusively that factoring or graph isomorphism were $\text{NP-intermediate}$ they would also have shown $\text{P} \ne \text{NP}$ and won the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.claymath.org/millennium-problems/p-vs-np-problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clay Institute P vs NP Millenium Problem&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s million dollar prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applications-of-graph-isomorphisms&#34;&gt;Applications of Graph Isomorphisms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the Weisfeiler-Lehman test for graph isomorphisms, what is the graph isomorphism problem good for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are applications of the graph isomorphism problem in, for example, computational chemistry and in circuit design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In chemistry, it is common to represent a molecule as a graph, with the atoms in the molecule being the nodes of the graph and the bonds between molecules being the edges.
Here, the graph isomorphism problem can be used to determine if two chemical structures are in fact the same structure.
This is important for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drug_discovery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;drug discovery&lt;/a&gt;, where scientists are working to create molecular structures that will be useful in order to fight diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A circuit is commonly represented as a graph as well.
The components in the circuit form the nodes of the graph, and the connections between components form the edges.
The graph isomorphism problem is useful here for determining whether two circuits that are laid out different are in fact identical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weisfeiler and Lehman first proposed this method in their paper &lt;em&gt;A reduction of a graph to a canonical form and an algebra arising during this reduction&lt;/em&gt; in 1968.
An English translation of this paper, originally published in Russian, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iti.zcu.cz/wl2018/pdf/wl_paper_translation.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently the method is also described succinctly in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmlr.org/papers/volume12/shervashidze11a/shervashidze11a.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Weisfeiler-Lehman Graph Kernels (Shervashidze 2011)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go forth and detect graph isomorphisms!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
