<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snippets | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/snippets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Snippets</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://davidbieber.com/img/portrait.jpg</url>
      <title>Snippets</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mostly-Complete List of BieberBot&#39;s Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-02-04-bieber-bot-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-02-04-bieber-bot-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BieberBot has an ever-growing list of capabilities. I&#39;ve tried to capture that complete list here. Feel free to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/ask-me-anywhere&#34;&gt;Ask Me Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; to inquire about any of these features and leave some contact info if you&#39;d like me to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timer-triggered-capabilities&#34;&gt;Timer-triggered capabilities:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greetings, encouragement, and love!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piano and violin reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen time monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders to reconnect with old friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders to exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is now a good time to do laundry?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoodReads updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FocusMate session planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TODOs of various kinds (&lt;em&gt;TODO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;tonight&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders of the importance of eating soon after waking up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook event tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assert Baton reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise Baton reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transaction logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yearly payroll tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After work activity planning and reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After work activity suggestions when nothing is already planned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chat-triggered-capabilities&#34;&gt;Chat-triggered capabilities:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending messages between David and Adriana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Violin, Piano, and Exercise tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food suggestions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggests people or activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assert Baton and Exercise Baton passing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baton status checking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budget status checking (Why is this not on a timer too?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get BieberBot&#39;s version number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play Jeopardy (individually or against Adriana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play Jeopardy in Croatian (individually or against Adriana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add financial transaction details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add TODOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send or schedule Tweets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACK! Any ol&amp;rsquo; text back to you (Great conversationalist!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-capabilities&#34;&gt;Other capabilities:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs financial transactions (triggered by credit-card swipes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&#39;s all! May have missed some, and there are more planned, but this is a mostly-comprehensive list as of Feb 4, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Next for Ask Me Anywhere?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-26-next-steps-for-ama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-26-next-steps-for-ama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I put up an early version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/&#34;&gt;Ask Me Anywhere&lt;/a&gt;. You&#39;ll notice it&#39;s in the snippets section of the website, rather than part of the main blog. This gives me the freedom to post it even though I know it&#39;s not as polished as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that this first pass is published, it&#39;s time to start thinking about where to go next with Ask Me Anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-term-stylistic-improvements&#34;&gt;Short Term: Stylistic Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mobile, the &amp;ldquo;Click to React&amp;rdquo; text shows up and is improperly styled. I didn&#39;t intend for it to show up at all. On certain mobile devices and browsers, it seems there are even larger issues than this, such as double tapping sometimes not working at all. Let me know if it doesn&#39;t work with your browser so I can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Click to React&amp;rdquo; text also sometimes causes the flow of the text to change, which interrupts the reading experience somewhat. I would like to fix this so that the text flow is never changed by the presence of this message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also would like to tweak the styling to minimize the friction someone feels in deciding to leave a message. I think adding a question-mark icon, which when moused-over gives an explanation of why this feature is there in the first place could be useful. This could strike a good balance between being non-intrusive and letting people know that their thoughts are warmly welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;longer-term-socratic-tutorials&#34;&gt;Longer Term: &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; is really an MVP that came out of a larger idea: &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea is that a &lt;em&gt;Socratic Tutorial&lt;/em&gt; is a blog post structured in a very particular way. It begins with a brief introduction to a topic, followed by a series of questions you might want to ask about that topic. Click a question to reveal an answer to that question, followed by additional questions you might have about the topic. In this way, you can explore the contents of the post in the order that best suits your interests. I also hope that by having to click questions to view the answers, it will help motivate what you&#39;re reading, since you&#39;ll be actively wondering about the question when you read the response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a reader of a &lt;em&gt;Socratic Tutorial&lt;/em&gt; doesn&#39;t understand something, or has a question that isn&#39;t already addressed, they can choose to ask that question. The author can then add it to the list of questions available during reading if they choose to do so. In that way, &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; is almost a subset of the features planned for Socratic Tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_example&#34;&gt;
My very first blog post ever was about &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Collapsible Blog Posts&lt;/a&gt;. The premise was that you could click on a paragraph, and it would be replaced with a summary of that paragraph. This paragraph is an example; click on it, and it will be replaced with a summary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_example&#34;&gt;
This was a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Collapsible Blog Post&lt;/a&gt; paragraph. Click to un-collapse.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned early on from this experiment that the reverse process actually is more useful. Present the user with a short summary, and let them click if they want to read additional details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_reverse&#34;&gt;
Here&#39;s an example of a short paragraph that you can click to reveal additional details.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_reverse&#34;&gt;
The reason it makes more sense to show the summary first is that it empowers the user to choose how to spend their time. If they are interested in understanding more about a topic, they can choose to expand the paragraph and read the details. If instead they read the extended paragraph first, there isn&#39;t much value to them also reading the summarized version. And if they just want the summarized version, having them see the full version first isn&#39;t too useful either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways the idea for &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo; is a spiritual descendent of Collapsible Blog Posts. They both share a goal: give the user control over the information they&#39;re consuming, as they&#39;re reading. Socratic Tutorials and Ask Me Anywhere take an additional step though, giving the user the ability to communicate directly with the author while they&#39;re reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll likely have noticed that this post uses &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo;. That means you can double click any paragraph, or click between two paragraphs, in order to send a note directly to the author.
I hope you do this, as I&#39;d love to hear any thoughts you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anywhere</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With this post, I&#39;m demoing a new work-in-progress feature for my blog called &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo;.
The feature lets you leave a comment or ask a question at &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; point while reading my writing.
The goal is to encourage readers to respond to my writing, because I&#39;m interested in having a conversation and hearing what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try it right now. Either &lt;strong&gt;double click&lt;/strong&gt; (double-tap on mobile) on any paragraph, or click between two paragraphs, to open a comment box. Enter your thoughts, click submit, and &lt;em&gt;voila!&lt;/em&gt;, comment submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re welcome to enter your email address, name, Twitter handle, Facebook ID, or any other form of contact info if you&#39;d like me to respond. And if you do, there is high likelihood that I will respond. If you don&#39;t, you&#39;re anonymous, and you certainly won&#39;t receive a private response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and questions that you submit are not posted publicly anywhere. This isn&#39;t a comments section for public discussion. If you want to discuss my posts publicly, submit them on Hacker News or Reddit, or head to Twitter to engage. While this website isn&#39;t the place for public discussions, I am curious to know about such a discussion if it&#39;s happening. So, feel free to let me know about such a discussion via &amp;ldquo;AMA&amp;rdquo; if you&#39;re starting one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you leave a comment? This part&#39;s still a work in progress, but ideally my digital personal assistant &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; will notify me of the new comment at the next convenient time. If there are many comments coming in, Bieber Bot will try to be smart about batching the notifications together, and so the notification may be delayed, but I&#39;ll soon read your message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Ask Me Anywhere is only activated for this one post. Once I&#39;ve tested it out a bit, and perhaps made some changes, I&#39;m hoping to then activate it for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;rest of my posts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;and snippets&lt;/a&gt; as well. So I&#39;m particularly keen to get feedback early so I can iterate and improve it soon. Give it a try, let me know what you think. You know how to reach me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in learning more about the internals, the source is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/davidbieber.com/blob/772b5dd87da532357a1cdf04a8caa027268bfbac/hugo/assets/js-src/ask-me-anywhere.jsx&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to have a poke around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the project &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; reflects my intention to enable readers to ask questions as they&#39;re reading. However, I welcome all types of reactions: questions, comments, feedback, corrections, new ideas, etc. I look forward to hearing what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much time has humanity spent on different areas of science?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-24-time-spent-on-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-24-time-spent-on-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much time has humanity, collectively, spent researching physics?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about chemistry? Neuroscience? Algorithms? (etc&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How has this rate of study changed over time?
How much of it is duplicate work (e.g. two nations or organizations independently working toward the same milestones before sharing their findings)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fraction of this is done by professors, post docs, PhD students, etc?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly in the last 100 years, what have these numbers been?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m interested in visualizing some of these metrics, because I think they would be useful for putting the work that I see happening around me in machine learning and in neuroscience into perspective. I also think this data would tell a fascinating story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, one plot that I think would be compelling would be person-hours-per-year spent thinking about physics plotted as a function of time over the last 100 years, with important physics milestones shown on the same plot (e.g. as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/berkeleyischool/how-to-create-a-visualization-showing-events-on-time-series-data-in-excel-96abbc1475e0&#34;&gt;time series plot with events&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One worry with such a visualization is that the population is growing rapidly, and so the interesting story of how humanity&#39;s attention has shifted between fields over time may be lost to a visualization that simply shows population growth. It may be necessary to normalize by population to tell such a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem infeasible to precisely collect this data, as there is no public registry of who is thinking about what. However, I think the data is perhaps more readily available than appears at first blush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where would the data come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University enrollments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication counts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surveys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search trends are of course a more recent source of data, only going back one or two decades. The pre-1990s version of search trends might be library records, or book sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University enrollments and degrees granted tells a significant story about how many people are studying different areas. You can roughly estimate how much time a student majoring in physics puts into their studies, and if course enrollments are available that estimate can be even more precise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific fields make their mark on the world by publishing their research. Counting publications can provide an estimate of one piece of humanity&#39;s effort studying science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for contemporary data, and maybe even a little historical data, one could uses surveys / polling techniques to estimate where scientific mindshare is going today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among this data I&#39;d be curious to see when historically there have been large swings in mindshare toward a particular topic. Right now, anecdotally, machine learning research is engaging a quickly increasing number of people, including drawing people away from other fields. I&#39;d love to see this anecdotal evidence backed up (or refuted) by data. And I expect there are plenty of similar historical precidents that I would be quite interested in learning more about as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t forsee collecting this data or performing these visualizations myself in the near future. This post is just an opportunity to think aloud, not a plan for my own action. But if you have data like this, or know of someone who has done a related analysis, I&#39;d be quite interested to hear about it. Don&#39;t hesitate to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say One Thing Well</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-14-say-one-thing-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-14-say-one-thing-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blog posts written by amateurs are often interesting and entertaining; they can offer perspectives not seen elsewhere. However, they often fall into the trap of trying to do too much. The best blog posts do one thing, and do it well. If you&#39;re writing a blog post, you should choose a single, narrow point that you want to make, and make it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this may seem like obviously good advice, in practice the temptation to broaden the scope of a blog post can be very real. So it is important to actively practice discretion in limiting the scope of any post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does scope creep come about? Authors may have a temptation to write about tangentially related topics. Sometimes this will be in order to provide justification or context. Other times the author simply has multiple lessons on the same topic they wish to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any one of these scenarios will lead the author to increase the scope of their writing. Even in the face of these situations, however, it is important to keep a narrow scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, for example, the core message is that &amp;ldquo;when writing a blog post, you should have a narrowly scoped thesis.&amp;rdquo; It is tempting for me to then also write about how to choose that thesis. After all, this seems a natural discussion to have while explaining the importance of a narrow scope. However, this would be a dangerous move, because a good discussion about how to choose a thesis well requires giving advice like &amp;ldquo;ask yourself: what are you interested in and knowledgeable about?&amp;quot;, and &amp;ldquo;think about what your audience is likely to care about&amp;rdquo;, etc. These suggestions don&#39;t help make the core point, that your scope should be exceedingly narrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this post, it is tempting to write about how &amp;ldquo;trying to do too much can lead to doing multiple things poorly&amp;rdquo; applies in other, non-writing, contexts too. This has the potential to be an insightful discussion. However, this would only serve to detract from the main point: in &lt;em&gt;writing blog posts specifically&lt;/em&gt;, you should choose a single main point and make it well. Trying to broaden this to other contexts would weaken the argument, because the wider the context is, the more exceptions there are. If I had said &amp;ldquo;in all of life, do one thing and do it well&amp;rdquo;, people would correctly protest: that&#39;s no way to live a life, you should aim to be well-rounded. So, I strengthen my argument by narrowing its scope: in writing a blog post, pick a single thesis and defend it convincingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important to have just one main point? To start, having a single well defined main point improves the clarity of your writing. It is easier to be persuasive when you have a well-defined objective you are trying to impress upon your readers. Stray too far from this main point and it distracts the reader and weakens your piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the age of online writing and sharing, the importance of a single clear thesis is increased. Having a well-scoped piece increases its sharability. There is no risk that the recipient of the shared article will mistake the reason for its sharing. Having a well-scoped piece also makes it easier to reference that piece in the future. One can simply link to the article if they want to leverage its argument, rather than needing to specify &amp;ldquo;in the third section of David&#39;s piece on online writing&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally readers have limited time and attention. So, don&#39;t bury the lead. Don&#39;t make readers have to dig deep to uncover a point that can be stated succinctly. Show your readers your respect for their time and attention by making your point immediately clear. Then they can make an informed choice about whether they&#39;d like to learn more. It&#39;s their time. Don&#39;t trick them with ambiguous or click-bait headlines. Let them invest it well by telling them upfront what it is you want to convince them of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there are exceptions to the rule. For educational pieces, teaching a curriculum of topics, it may be appropriate to have multiple lessons. And if you&#39;re writing for literary value, then the core takeaway may not be the central reason for your writing. In the general case though, critical for the vast majority of blogs being written today, it is wise to stick to a single thesis. State it clearly and defend it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve learned just one thing from this article, it&#39;s that the best articles should leave you with just one thing to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Assistant Tool Idea</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-writing-is-hard&#34;&gt;Background: Writing is Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I find writing feels easy &amp;ndash; e.g. when &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;writing for no audience&lt;/a&gt;, when writing something you&#39;ve already thought extensively about, when telling a story in a logical order that you&#39;re deeply familiar with. Other times, I find writing very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&#39;m writing a paper, I am writing explicitly for an audience, the story is not always clear immediately, and the material is something I&#39;m becoming familiar with over time, not something about which I&#39;m already deeply familiar.
So, I find paper writing hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an idea that I think will help me write more effectively. It&#39;s a software tool that structures the time you spend writing. I&#39;ll describe the tool, but I don&#39;t anticipate building it. Perhaps we can come up with a low-resource version of this idea, e.g. with paper and pencil, that I can try even without building this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-writing-system&#34;&gt;The Writing System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool presents you with a prompt, a textbox, and a timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial prompt is &amp;ldquo;What do you want to write about?&amp;quot;, and the initial timer is for 5 minutes. Subsequent prompts will be determined from what you&#39;ve entered in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the textbox, you are encouraged to respond to the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of your response, you can issue some commands / keywords.
If you start a line with &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;, then that line will get used as a future prompt.
You can specify the relative importance of a future prompt by including a priority.
This will determine the order in which you are presented with the prompts.
E.g. &lt;code&gt;!0&lt;/code&gt; is highest priority, and so such a line will become the next prompt you receive, unless there are other priority 0 prompts already queued up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;! &amp;lt;topic&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I want to write about later&amp;rdquo;
&lt;code&gt;? &amp;lt;question&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;question&amp;gt; is a question I want to answer later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should also be a way to indicate &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I&#39;ll need to do more research on&amp;rdquo;, and then for one of the prompts to be about spending time researching a topic, rather than writing about it. Then the next prompt may be to write about what you just learned in the research section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other available commands include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:pause&lt;/code&gt; to stop the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:unpause&lt;/code&gt; to start the timer again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:extend&lt;/code&gt; to add additional time to the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:next&lt;/code&gt; to skip to the next prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is easily extensible, so a writer with a programming background can easily add new commands, or modify the logic that determines when prompts are shown and when breaks are taken. A programming-proficient writer will also have programmatic access to everything they write, as well as the corresponding prompts and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the timer reaches 0, a short break is initiated, and then the next prompt is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to move quickly, and get all your thoughts onto the page, without getting bogged down in a DFS traversal of information about a single line of the overall text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-details&#34;&gt;Additional details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every keystroke is logged, so if you write something, and then switch to a new version of it, you will still be able to see the original version. No need to worry about pasting in a password though, since the keylogging data is readily accessible in a plaintext format and you can edit it directly e.g. if anything sensitive does leak in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has a decent amount of overlap with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt; project that I&#39;ve already built,
and perhaps a version of this new idea could be easily added to the shh shell. Alternatively, the shh-shell could be forked to build this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar integration would be cool, so that it times your prompts nicely if you have a meeting coming up so you get to a good break point in time for your meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation-thoughts&#34;&gt;Implementation Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to build this onto an existing text editor, rather than writing my own. E.g. using Google Docs would be good.
However, the disadvantage of this is that it makes the keystroke logging feature more difficult. Fortunately, Google Docs does have good history tracking. Google Docs also provides good programmatic access. So, an agent running in the background while you write could be taking periodic snapshots too. Such an agent could also be extracting the commands and prompts you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it wouldn&#39;t be able to execute the commands immediately, the way shh shell does. For some commands this may be a real disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like the idea of the agent giving the prompts being Bieber Bot &amp;ndash; that is, being the same &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; as my personal digital assistant. I can picture it asking me &amp;ldquo;you&#39;ve been writing continuously for over an hour; is it time for a break?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it looks like you stopped writing abruptly there, did you get distracted?&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-experimentation&#34;&gt;Initial Experimentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying the idea out in a low-tech way (manually timing things, manually looking up what the next prompt should be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the main issue I&#39;ve seen so far in the first half hour of testing. When the time runs out for a prompt, I&#39;m still in the middle of the prompt. I&#39;ve usually started expounding on some idea relevant to the prompt, and there are actually several ideas remaining that I haven&#39;t even started exploring for the prompt yet. So what should have happened / what should I do next time? Maybe I could have done a higher level discussion of the prompt and made new future sub-prompts along the way. Or at the end of a section, I could have the system give me a bit of time to create sub-prompts of things I&#39;d like to address in the section but didn&#39;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see having a limited time to create new prompts be a good forcing function for coming up with structured high level thinking after a moderate amount of time of lower level writing. So in my next round of testing, I&#39;ll try this, and continue to iterate on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning by Teaching in Online Education</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-09-learning-by-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-09-learning-by-teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long ago (2013) I spent a summer interning at Khan Academy.
Also long ago (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harvest_zhang&#34;&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; and I built a tool for creating educational videos online, in the browser (&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone&#34;&gt;Teach Everyone&lt;/a&gt;; warning, bit rot ahead).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to see these two methodologies combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want it to become common practice that after you spend significant time learning something online, you make a quick-and-dirty video explaining what you just learned.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-vision&#34;&gt;The Vision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&#39;ve just completed a series of organic chemistry lessons on Khan Academy. The KA website pops up a modal recommending that you &amp;ldquo;Make a video teaching what you learned to help solidify your understanding of Organic Chemistry!&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You click through to a browser based video creation tool &amp;ndash; a cross between Google Slides, Illustrator / Teach Everyone, and OBS / a video editor.
In minutes, you&#39;re able to assemble a video teaching the material you&#39;ve spent the last hours or days wrapping your head around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You combine text, images, drawings, video, and audio to create your video. And when you&#39;re done, you have the option to save it privately, share it on YouTube or social media, or to make it visible to others studying the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main benefits from this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get to learn by teaching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching is a super effective way to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinforce the material so that you remember it longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help you notice gaps in your understanding and fill them in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So by preparing this little video after spending all that time learning, you&#39;ll be left with a better and longer lasting understanding of the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others can learn from &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times the best teachers are those who remember what it&#39;s like not to understand. Since you&#39;ve just gone through the process of learning the material, you know exactly which parts were difficult to grasp and what it took for you to grasp them. So your video may end up helping others more than the KA videos in some cases!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;video-creation-tool&#34;&gt;Video Creation Tool&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&#39;t a design doc, but I will briefly sketch out what I imagine for the video creation tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main interface is a video preview above a timeline, similar to what you would see in Davinci Resolve or any professional video editing tool. You additionally have the option to create clips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create clips from text, images, KA-style drawings, audio, or video. Importantly, you can record audio and video clips, or create a KA-style drawing, directly in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve created some clips, you can position them both in time (on the timeline), and in space (on the video preview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to write more about the details of this vision for video creation tool at a later point, but for now the most important thing about it is that it prioritizes being quick to use over being fully featured and professional, and that it can be used directly in the browser. This way it can be used by online learners as part of their online learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-notes&#34;&gt;Additional Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main premise is that students, young and old, should have a light-weight way to create educational videos immediately after learning something online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve framed this discussion around a hypothetical tool for students to use on Khan Academy, but it applies equally well to educational videos on YouTube and elsewhere. &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone&#34;&gt;Teach Everyone&lt;/a&gt; was an early prototype showing that you can create Khan Academy style animated drawings (i.e. virtual writing on a blackboard) with accompanying audio directly in the browser. Since then, Teach Everyone has suffered some bit rot and unfortunately isn&#39;t operational today. However, I&#39;m hopeful that some new project will step up, and provide an even better in-browser experience for educational video creation. And then beyond that, I&#39;m hopeful that this tool becomes common place for students to use as part of their everyday online learning routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss these ideas, don&#39;t hesitate to get in touch: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810+learning-by-teaching@gmail.com&#34;&gt;david810+learning-by-teaching@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does &#34;Ordinary&#34; mean in Ordinary Least Squares?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-08-ordinary-least-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-08-ordinary-least-squares/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ordinary Least Squares&amp;rdquo; regression, or OLS for short, is a method for finding a best-fit line, given a set of data points. When people refer to linear regression without additional context or qualifiers, they&#39;re probably referring to ordinary least squares regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; mean in this context? Is it a mathematical term with a precise technical meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, no. In this case &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; means exactly what you might expect: standard, vanilla, lacking any bells and whistles. Since least squares regression is so common, there are lots of variants. Weighted Least Squares (in which each data point is given its own weight) is a such a variant. So, in OLS, the O for ordinary simply means we&#39;re not referring to one of these variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about &amp;ldquo;ordinary differential equations&amp;rdquo; (ODEs)? What does ordinary refer to there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that context, ordinary refers to ordinary derivatives, as opposed to partial derivatives. So again, it&#39;s not a mathematical term like a reference to ordinal numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, ordinary seems to take on its ordinary English definition &amp;ndash; its OED, if I may.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s pronounced just like it&#39;s spelled (&amp;ldquo;pied, swite, cuff, buh-din&amp;rdquo;). It&#39;s my life motto.
And I think these are good principles to live by. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persue your dreams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say what you think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate friendships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think each of these is self-explanatory. Briefly though, let&#39;s consider each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pursue-your-dreams&#34;&gt;Pursue Your Dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work toward long term goals you think are worthwhile. It&#39;s easy to fall into the trap of chasing promotions and paychecks, so the &amp;ldquo;pyd&amp;rdquo; in pyd-swyt serves as a reminder to never lose sight of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;say-what-you-think&#34;&gt;Say What You Think&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easier to go along with thae status quo that to voice dissent.
It can be easier to assume others are correct than to voice confusion.
Usually though, it is better to express your dissent / confusion / support.
The &amp;ldquo;swyt&amp;rdquo; in pyd-swyt serves as a constant reminder to speak your mind, especially when it would be more comfortable not to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cultivate-friendships&#34;&gt;Cultivate Friendships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reach out to people you care about, and to people you want to know better.
Reconnect with those you haven&#39;t seen in a long time, rather than losing touch with them gradually.
Time spent with friends is time well-spent, so the &amp;ldquo;cf&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;cf-bh-din&amp;rdquo; stands as a reminder to cultivate friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-happy&#34;&gt;Be Happy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the things you love, and do them often. Spend time with the people you care about. Do what makes you happy.
Don&#39;t sacrifice these things for your other values. &amp;ldquo;bh&amp;rdquo;; be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-it-now&#34;&gt;Do It Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are principles for now. Don&#39;t wait to pursue your dreams. Don&#39;t wait to say what you think. Don&#39;t wait to cultivate friendships. Certainly don&#39;t wait to be happy. Do each of these things every day, starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Do in Moments of Internet Addiction</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-moments-of-internet-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-moments-of-internet-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often feel addicted to YouTube, TV shows, browsing HackerNews, or social media.
When I do, I&#39;m tempted to just keep scrolling or watching, and I can waste hours on the internet.
Afterward, and even during, I may feel an inclination to stop, but I continue consuming content anyway.
It feels unhealthy, and I generally regret when I spend my time this way.
For some reason, I do it anyway though, and so I think of this habit like an addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re like me and fall into these unhealthy attention-consuming rabbit holes, here is a list of things we can do instead of continuing the addictive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing; doing &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; is a perfectly valid option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say hi to a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go for a walk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monologue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make plans for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate HALT (hungry? angry? lonely? tired?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history&#34;&gt;toying with&lt;/a&gt; the idea of getting Bieber Bot to notice when I&#39;m exhibiting addictive behavior. If I can get that working, I&#39;d love for Bieber Bot to notice when I&#39;m addicted to YouTube, Hacker News, or Twitter and suggest one of the above activities for me to perform instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing for No Audience</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;snippets&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; section of my website just a few days ago with the intention of being able to write without needing to put polish on a piece before publishing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking was that I would be able to put small notes there, and half-baked ideas, and not have to worry about diluting the quality of the content of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;. I could put high quality posts on the main site, and a whole range of both good and bad posts in the snippets section. This way, assuming I do a good job, readers could come to expect that any post on the main website would be high quality. Curious people looking for additional content could come here to the snippets section if they wanted to, but more often posts here would either (1) almost never get read, or (2) be linked to directly, e.g. if they were relevent in some other context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been surprised and delighted by the effect that having this &amp;ldquo;No Audience&amp;rdquo; section of the website has had on my writing. Writing for no one is so much easier than writing for someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a few occasions (and it&#39;s only been a few days since I started this section), I&#39;ve started writing snippets intending for them to be brief thoughts meant for no one but myself. Then, after starting, it has felt natural to expand the post into something more substantial than I originally intended, e.g. answering questions that a hypothetical reader might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-12-29-track-your-life-in-a-spreadsheet&#34;&gt;occasion&lt;/a&gt; I even decided to bump the post up in importance after getting started, placing it in the main section of the website rather than relegating it to the mostly hidden snippets section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To anyone out there who does end up reading this, and there may very well be none of you: if you&#39;re having trouble getting started with writing, write for no audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-different-degrees-of-no-audience&#34;&gt;The Different Degrees of &amp;ldquo;No Audience&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually write for No Audience in two different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) The &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;snippets&lt;/a&gt; section of my website\&lt;br&gt;
(2) Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh-shell&lt;/a&gt; at night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snippets section of my website is public, but with no built-in broadcasting. People can read it if they choose to, but I&#39;m not putting it in people&#39;s faces (by default; I will if it&#39;s appropriate in context). Contrast this with the writing I do with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh-shell&lt;/a&gt;. This is more personal writing that I do half-asleep as I drift off at night, and so I don&#39;t make it public; I expect almost no one will ever read it. This writing, I suppose is for No Audience to an even more extreme degree. I recommend both practices: public writing for no audience, and private writing for no audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-media-doesnt-cut-it&#34;&gt;Social Media Doesn&#39;t Cut It&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&#39;ve discovered this practice and am quite fond of it, I think it could be a promising addition to social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No social media platform, to my knowledge, has given people a place to write public posts with an option to publish but not share them. The absense of such a feature makes sense; social media platforms need you to share for them to succeed, so how would giving you a space to publish-but-not-share help them? The answer lies in the psychology of the many social-media lurkers. There is a significant market segment of people who perhaps consume, but do not post, on social media. An option to publish-but-not-broadcast might help to convert some of that segment into sharers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a social media consumer, but infrequent producer, I can tell you I am hesitant even to Like something on Twitter, because I know Twitter often treats Likes like Retweets, and will put the content I hearted in front of my followers with my name attached, and that&#39;s not something I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a feature for publishing-without-sharing were added to Facebook or Twitter, perhaps others would have an experience like mine over the last few days. Having the option to publish-but-not-share has significantly reduced the barrier to start writing for me. Then, once I&#39;ve started writing, I&#39;ve often changed my mind and decided I want to share what I&#39;ve written after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If other social-media lurkers are like me, a feature enabling this behavior could help &amp;ldquo;break the ice&amp;rdquo; so to speak, and could make social media platforms more relevant to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to continue building this snippets section for myself, with the default behavior being no-broadcasting as I add snippets. For snippets I&#39;m fond of, I may choose to broadcast (e.g. by posting about the post on social media). Contrast this with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;main posts section&lt;/a&gt; of my website; for new posts there, I will generally always broadcast the post, at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to receive such broadcasts, e.g. when I write a post that I&#39;m particularly keen on sharing, please consider subscribing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, you are also welcome to follow the snippets section with &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Don&#39;t tell me if you do though, since I would like to continue to feel like I&#39;m writing for No Audience. You can follow the posts section with &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning to Analyze My Browsing History</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve learned recently that programmatically accessing your browsing history is rather straightforward. Really exciting! This is rich data, from which I think I&#39;ll be able to learn a lot and hopefully combat unwanted distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let me describe what information is available, and how you can access it. Then, let&#39;s discuss what you can do with this data. As I&#39;ve written about previously &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-12-29-track-your-life-in-a-spreadsheet/&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;, I already have a chat bot system in place, which will be able to take advantage of this data to e.g. help me stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;accessing-your-browser-history&#34;&gt;Accessing Your Browser History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to GitHub user &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dropmeaword&#34;&gt;dropmeaword&lt;/a&gt; for compiling &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dropmeaword/9372cbeb29e8390521c2&#34;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt; explaining how to access your browser history via sqlite3. The gist covers Safari, Chrome, and Firefox. In this post, I&#39;ll just focus on Chrome on OSX, since that&#39;s my primary mode of browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Chrome browsing history is located at &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Default/History&lt;/code&gt;. Since I use multiple profiles in Chrome, each profile gets its own browsing history, e.g. located at &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Profile 1/History&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each browsing history is stored as a sqlite3 database. Before analyzing the data, I recommend making a copy of it (&lt;code&gt;cp ~/Library/Application\ Support/Google/Chrome/Default/History my-history&lt;/code&gt;); this way your history database (a) wont be locked by Chrome while you&#39;re trying to access it, and (b) wont change while you&#39;re looking at it, which could cause confusion and inconsistencies in your results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you can browse it interactively using the sqlite3 REPL by running &lt;code&gt;sqlite3 PATH_TO_DATABASE&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also libraries available for accessing sqlite3 databases in just about every language. For Python, there&#39;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/sqlite3.html&#34;&gt;sqlite3&lt;/a&gt; library. Go has &lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/github.com/mattn/go-sqlite3&#34;&gt;go-sqlite3&lt;/a&gt;. JavaScript has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlitetutorial.net/sqlite-nodejs/&#34;&gt;this sqlite3 module&lt;/a&gt;. However you most like scripting, you&#39;ll have a familiar way of accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-available-data&#34;&gt;The Available Data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running sqlite3 macro &lt;code&gt;.tables&lt;/code&gt;, we see the following tables are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;meta&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;urls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads_slices&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segment_usage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_source&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads_url_chains&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;keyword_search_terms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;typed_url_sync_metadata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll be most interested in the &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;visits&lt;/code&gt; tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; table has these columns (found with &lt;code&gt;.schema urls&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the URL in the database.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;url&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The URL of the website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;title&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The title of website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The number of times you&#39;ve visited the URL.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;typed_count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The number of times you&#39;ve visited the URL by typing in the address (as opposed to by following a link.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;last_visit_time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (milliseconds since the epoch)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The time of the most recent to the URL.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;hidden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boolean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&#39;m not sure what this is about.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;code&gt;visits&lt;/code&gt; table has these columns (obtained via &lt;code&gt;.schema visits&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the visit in the database.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;url&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the url in the &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; table.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (milliseconds since the epoch)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The time of the visit.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;from_visit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the visit that lead you to this one.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;transition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bit vector&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Represents the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/history#transition_types&#34;&gt;transition type&lt;/a&gt; (how you got to the URL)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segment_id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the segment in the database. I&#39;m not quite sure what a segment is, but there is a &lt;code&gt;segments&lt;/code&gt; table you can look at.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_duration&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (microsecodns)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The amount of time spent at the website, or 0 if not available.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;incremented_omnibox_typed_score&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boolean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I do not know what this is about.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, we can access every visit to every website that we&#39;ve made since the last time we cleared our browsing history. We can see what website we visited (&lt;code&gt;visits.url&lt;/code&gt;), when we visited it (&lt;code&gt;visits.visit_time&lt;/code&gt;), how many times we&#39;ve visited it (&lt;code&gt;urls.visit_count&lt;/code&gt;), and how long each visit was for (&lt;code&gt;visits.visit_duration&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can even use &lt;code&gt;visits.from_visit&lt;/code&gt; to figure out what website linked us to each url, if that interests us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-can-we-deduce&#34;&gt;What Can We Deduce?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can (1) perform a historical analysis on the data, as well as (2) do real-time monitoring of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I brainstorm some of the historical trends we will be able to uncover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most frequently visited websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites where we spend the majority of our time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites that frequently lead to known-distractor websites (e.g. Reddit, Hacker News, Twitter, YouTube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can do an analysis by time of day (or day of week), to figure out what sites occupy my time late at night vs during daylight hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are somewhat interesting, but what I&#39;m particularly excited for is the ongoing analysis that &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; can provide by accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a brainstorm of the more real-time actionable insights we might extract from this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot could ping me if it looks like I&#39;m spending too much time on a distraction website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He could try to detect if I went to a website with a particular purpose, but ended up getting distracted and not completing the purpose I set out to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if I&#39;m on a productive website and then switch to a distraction website for more than a few minutes, particularly during work hours, Bieber Bot might message asking if I got distracted. Think you could do that for me Bieber Bot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could signal that I want to view a website later by opening it and immediately closing it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps we could detect if I&#39;m researching a particular topic, and then Bieber Bot could try to help me with my research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-idea&#34;&gt;Related Idea&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reduce distractions, I&#39;d like to be able to switch my browsing mode from &amp;ldquo;clicking opens links&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;clicking saves a link for later&amp;rdquo;. When in this new mode, whenever I click a link it wouldn&#39;t open that link; instead, it would save the link to a list of deferred links.
Then I would be able to view my &amp;ldquo;saved for later&amp;rdquo; links when I have time that I&#39;ve explicitly set aside, rather than during the time that I would rather be doing something more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&#39;ve done a little bit of manual exploration of my browsing history data. I&#39;ve set up a little Python script to be able to access the data programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I&#39;ll do more manual analysis, and then I&#39;ll see if I&#39;m able to give Bieber Bot the real-time access to the data that I described above. I&#39;m particularly excited to see if I can get the &amp;ldquo;looks like you&#39;ve gotten distracted&amp;rdquo; messages set up with Bieber Bot. As a bonus, since Bieber Bot can message other people too, this system could help me leverage social accountability to stay on task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see where this project leads? You can subscribe for infrequent email updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned the Word Feedingstuffs</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-29-feedingstuffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-29-feedingstuffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I learned the word &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/feedingstuff#English&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;feedingstuffs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;feedingstuff (countable and uncountable, plural feedingstuffs)

  Any foodstuff used to feed livestock.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not in every dictionary, and it&#39;s not a valid Scrabble word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this word come up? I had heard previously that salmon is not naturally as pink as it is in supermarkets. I was wondering how this could be. Surely salmon aren&#39;t being colored during the packaging process, right? That&#39;s right, salmon are still that same color when they&#39;re first cut open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coloring, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/food/sites/food/files/safety/docs/animal-feed_additives_rules_scan-old_report_out81.pdf&#34;&gt;I learned&lt;/a&gt;, is added to the salmon&#39;s &lt;strong&gt;feedingstuffs&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&#39;s an official European Commission report from 2002 recommending that the amount of allowable &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canthaxanthin&#34;&gt;Canthaxanthin&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;font color=&#34;salmon&#34;&gt;salmon&lt;/font&gt; coloring) in salmon feed be reevaluated, and possibly lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, the maximum amount of Canthaxanthin allowable in salmon and trout feedingstuffs in the EU was 80 mg / kg of feedingstuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to today, and only &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32008R0775&amp;amp;qid=1577681296736&amp;amp;from=EN&#34;&gt;10 mg / kg of Canthaxanthin is permitted&lt;/a&gt;. More interesting than this though, is that in the 2008 journal reporting this new, lower limit, they instead use the word &lt;strong&gt;foodstuffs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedingstuffs, it would seem, are no more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Communicate</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-26-learning-to-communicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-26-learning-to-communicate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal for 2020 is to learn to communicate better with the world. I work in a research group at Google, and our main job function is performing research in program synthesis. But research is only as valuable as how well it is communicated. So in 2020 I&#39;d like to get better at communicating publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few options for doing this. The first is writing blog posts. This may be too large an undertaking to do frequently. I&#39;d really like something that&#39;s lower barrier to do, and with a lower quality bar, so that I can do this more often. The natural alternative with these properties is academic Twitter. However, I want to avoid the addictive nature of Twitter. I also want to write more than 280 characters at a time, and I don&#39;t want to put every little thing I write in front of people&#39;s faces with equal importance. Twitter seems a good place for announcing a new paper or a Python Fire update, but not for sharing a musing like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead I think I&#39;m going to start by silently posting my writings to my website, but in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;separate section&lt;/a&gt; from the main blog. This way when there&#39;s something with a little more polish that I think is explicitly worth reading, I can put it in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;main blog section&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; about it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to receive updates for every small writing I put up here, you can use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to receive updates only for major posts, such as new publications or major life updates, you can use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; or you can subscribe here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy early new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snippets for davidbieber.com</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducing-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducing-snippets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&#39;m introducing the &amp;ldquo;snippets&amp;rdquo; section of my website. The goal is to give myself a place to post content online that&#39;s extremely easy to post to, but isn&#39;t featured prominently anywhere on the site. This way I can post things without them needing polish or production value, but still link to them and share them as I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
