<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coworking on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/coworking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coworking on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/coworking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ugh Task Night</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-10-24-ugh-task-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-10-24-ugh-task-night/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boo! 👻 Ugh Task Night is coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second year I&amp;rsquo;m hosting Ugh Task Night, the scariest night of the year. Ugh Task Night takes place in late October, right around that other spooky holiday.
At Ugh Task Night, friends come together for an evening to do the scariest thing of all, their Ugh Tasks. We gather (virtually, on GatherTown) and, interspersed with chatting, do the things we dread most of all, generally to a feeling of significant relief. By doing our Ugh Tasks with friends, in a setting of care and support, we can face our inner beasts and try to tame them.
At UTN, people perform their Ugh Tasks independently, together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s an Ugh Task? An Ugh Task is something you have to do, but which you&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off, such that now even the thought of it causes you to recoil a little with dread.
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s an email you need to send, or an appointment you need to schedule. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a text you fear even reading, or something you said you&amp;rsquo;d have done long ago that you still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished. Often the ugh feeling that an Ugh Task elicits causes you to put off the task further, worsening the ugh feeling that it elicits &amp;ndash; an ugly downward cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your Ugh Task may be, it&amp;rsquo;s welcome at Ugh Task Night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more notes on the hosting of Ugh Task Night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should people RSVP? There is no &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo;. And I don&amp;rsquo;t ask people to RSVP. The point isn&amp;rsquo;t to create more work for them. I do enjoy knowing who&amp;rsquo;s coming though, so RSVPing is totally optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can people invite their friends? This year I went with yes! I told folks they are welcome to invite others, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; anyone they&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to see for years but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to reaching out to yet. i.e. In the spirit of the night, they can use Ugh Task Night as a tool to complete a possible social Ugh Task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Your Co-Working Sessions to the Next Level</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-05-01-coworking-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-05-01-coworking-sessions/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy hosting co-working sessions.
Pre-pandemic I used to just go to a coffee shop and invite people to join me.
Now, trying to limit exposure to strangers, I&amp;rsquo;m having working sessions at my apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These working sessions are gatherings intended for people to independently work on hobbies, side projects, work, homework, future startups, catching up on emails, reading, whatever. Having other people around can make working more fun and make it easier to stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of ideas about how to take these co-working sessions to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cords and cables for charging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food prepared in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go Note Gos everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro timers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for people to declare what they&amp;rsquo;re working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated time for chitchat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A firm stance on allowing people to get to work if chitchat lingers more than several minutes outside of a planned time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a shared chat room for people to send non-interrupting messages to the whole group.
Useful for coordinating going out for lunch taking breaks etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear policy on inviting others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adequate comfortable space for everyone, including spaces just move around and switch positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to make coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do some taxonomizing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas are about providing technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cords and cables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go Note Gos everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat room for non-interrupting messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about providing nutrition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food prepared in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to make coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about establishing social norms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro timers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for people to declare what they&amp;rsquo;re working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated time for chitchat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A firm stance on allowing people to get to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat room for non-interrupting messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear policy on inviting others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about making people comfortable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adequate comfortable space for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the food ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors and Cords and cables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sold these are &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; good ideas
(e.g. pomodoro timers can be disruptive, and I considered putting &lt;em&gt;light music&lt;/em&gt; on the list but decided against it),
but I think that by implementing several of these ideas I can make my working sessions a little more welcoming and enjoyable for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inviting people in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having about 6 people in total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inviting people around a theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing updates at the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning a working session in conjunction with another activity like a hike or dinner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>