<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aspirational-intent on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/aspirational-intent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aspirational-intent on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/aspirational-intent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Less Twitter. Less Facebook. Less HackerNews.</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2024-01-08-less-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2024-01-08-less-twitter/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-18-attention-strategies/&#34;&gt;dozens of strategies&lt;/a&gt; for managing my attention, including amazing Chrome extensions from Namu like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/intention-stop-mindless-b/dladanhaondcgpahgiflodhckhoeohoe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hidefeed.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hide feed&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, I continue to get sucked into the Internet&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/&#34;&gt;six infinite distractions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today (well, yesterday really), I&amp;rsquo;m taking matters into my own hands, and building some Chrome extensions to help me manage these distractions on my own terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter and Facebook.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that when I&amp;rsquo;m scrolling on Twitter or Facebook, and I want to stop, I sometimes find it difficult because &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;just one more post&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;that looks interesting&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. That is, I&amp;rsquo;ll see a half-visible post at the bottom of my screen, and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell myself I&amp;rsquo;ll just look at that one post, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll be done. But by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at that post, a different post is now half-visible, and it&amp;rsquo;s captured my attention as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my proposal is: I&amp;rsquo;ll only make posts visible once they are fully on the screen. No more half-visible Tweets. No more half-visible Facebook posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out making such a Chrome extension is remarkably easy, especially with language models available to assist with the boilerplate. Let me show you some before and after photos&amp;hellip; actually, just the after; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get any practice disabling this thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2024-01-08-less-twitter/less-twitter.gif&#34; alt=&#34;I am scrolling on Twitter. Posts only appear once they are fully visible in the browser&amp;rsquo;s view port.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the gif, I am scrolling on Twitter, and posts only appear once they are fully visible in the browser&amp;rsquo;s view port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect; I still will scroll just to bring something closer to my eye level, which can cause additional posts to appear. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s a big improvement on the default. Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that by not having partially visible posts at the bottom of the screen, it will be less addicting, and easier to get off the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the same for Facebook. For HackerNews, I took a different tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HackerNews.&lt;/strong&gt; On HackerNews, my obvervation is that I will sometimes continue digging, 5+ pages into HackerNews, looking for something interesting. This is silly; I don&amp;rsquo;t need five pages of HackerNews content. If I don&amp;rsquo;t satisfy my itch for news in thirty articles, 120 articles isn&amp;rsquo;t likely to do any better. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be heavy handed; blocking the site or removing the more button might simply cause me to learn workarounds for my blocker. For a gentler touch, I&amp;rsquo;m going to change the More link to link back to the first page. My habit is to click the more link, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to tab into that habit to help break it, gently. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to post this snippet as is so I can get it out and get some sleep. But I intend on releasing the Chrome extensions too. Each one is just a small amount of JavaScript, trivial to create but hopefully significant in impact. There are three in total, called Less Twitter, Less Facebook, and Less HackerNews respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll also note Kudos / Gratitude to Unhook for making a YouTube-management Chrome extension that I&amp;rsquo;ve started using as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good browsing and good night!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say What You Think</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-12-02-say-what-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-12-02-say-what-you-think/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is the SWYT in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din/&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/a&gt;: say what you think.
We&amp;rsquo;ve already covered what it means to me to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-11-pursuing-your-dreams/&#34;&gt;BH (&amp;ldquo;be happy&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/a&gt; and to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-07-31-pursue-your-dreams/&#34;&gt;PYD (&amp;ldquo;pursue your dreams&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/a&gt;. Today we dive into SWYTing &amp;ndash; saying what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is easily the toughest one for me.
I often self-censor. So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start this exploration with a quick brainstorming of why this might be. Expand the text below to see the full brainstorm. I include my complete initial thoughts here, though upon review I think the actual explanations behind some of these &amp;ldquo;System 1 rationales&amp;rdquo; differ from the System 1 rationales themselves in a handful of instances. We can dive into that more after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Expand this to see the full brainstorming.&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
- Love / expectations of the other person
- Concern for how something will be received
- Whether it would make someone uncomfortable
- Whether it would... yeah, make them uncomfortable or be hurtful or be rude
- Reshaping things to say the same thing but in a kinder less violent way takes time
- But this is something that I can get faster at with practice
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Other reasons for not saying what I want to include:
- Concern about putting things on the permanent record; let&#39;s explore that one in more depth
- Concern about creating additional comms overhead (having to deal with replies, requests, disagreements, etc)
    - Even if ignoring and not responding to these, they still come with significant mental overhead.
- Concerns about confidentiality also stifle my saying what I think in a couple ways:
    - One is confidentiality for my employer
    - If something is a secret then I don&#39;t want to share it publicly
    - Especially since the merger this has been uncomfortable since so much is NTK now
    - And then on a more personal level, there are lots of things that I&#39;d love to discuss that feel like they aren&#39;t mine to tell
    - They might involve saying something that could be perceived as negative about another person, or they might involve something that could be considered private by another person
        - (This could either be something intimate, or something they might not be ready to share like an idea they&#39;re working on in stealth, etc.)
        - Or maybe it just feels like it&#39;s their story, and they might want to tell it themselves on their own time.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
- Another thing that can hold back my saying what I think is private-seeming things; things that are more emotional or intimate don&#39;t necessarily feel appropriate to share in most contexts.
    - Mental health coaching has been great.
    - It&#39;s created an atmosphere in which sharing is the default and so my inhibitions around sharing are dropped substantially there.
- Journalling on Go Note Go has also done wonders for dropping inhibitions toward writing.
    - And the snippets section of my website -- [writing for no audience](/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/) -- has done wonders too.
- Oh, I&#39;m reminded of yet another source of inhibition:
    - A fear of looking stupid (or, to use less judgemental language: a fear of revealing gaps in my knowledge and skillsets.)
    - I&#39;m pretty good at not succumbing to this inhibition, but it&#39;s certainly there alongside all the rest.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
- So, I&#39;ve given a rather lengthy list of forces working against my desire to say what I think.
- And there are still more perhaps:
    - I&#39;ll reiterate the aversion to making others feel uncomfortable.
    - Conflict avoidance is another.
    - A natural inclination toward trying to help with what I perceive to be others&#39; desires (including e.g. making space if I think someone doesn&#39;t want to talk to me :()
    - I might even have a length penalty, a bias against droning on, leading to compact speech that might lack important context or information.
    - And finally I&#39;ll add a note about vulnerability, which I think is what I was alluding to when I started out the brainstorming with the word &#34;Love&#34;.
&lt;/pre&gt;
And finally some addendums:
&lt;pre&gt;
One I did not mention is thinking before speaking; Let&#39;s add that to the list.
Let&#39;s also add the difficulties (1) of knowing what I want to say and (2) of actually saying it.
And avoiding seeming petty or overly critical.
Rereading while writing (aka perfectionism or overthinking the details) can impede thinking about the high level / can be a form of self-censorship.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons I discovered for not saying what I think were more numerous than I expected!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoiding vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An automatic draw towards meeting expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conflict avoidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoiding making other people uncomfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fear of permanence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fear of consequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An aversion to creating a communications overhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respecting confidentiality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to be helpful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A natural inclination toward brevity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right. So now that we&amp;rsquo;ve run through so many reasons that my brain produces against saying what I think, I must reiterate that I hold &lt;em&gt;saying what I think&lt;/em&gt; among the five most important things for me to do in life. (The five of course being 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din/&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/a&gt; (Pursue your dreams, say what you think, cultivate friendships, be happy, do it now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it would behoove me to think explicitly about the value of saying what you think.
And maybe to think more critically about each of the reasons against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons my brain gives against are legitimate reasons, so while I do want to knock them down a peg, I also want to take them seriously and give them due consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will write about why I want to say what I think, and why I value this enough to include it in my pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din guiding mantra. Then, after, we can return to the negatives / to the brainstormings above and think critically about them. So, let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;As with the negatives above, I start with a brainstorming; click to expand it.&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
There are so many reasons to say what you think. What are they?
First major category is that then people know what you think!
They can&#39;t give you want you want or respect your preferences or stop doing annoying things that bother you
  if they don&#39;t know what you want, what your preferences are, or that they&#39;re doing an annoying thing that bothers you.
It can be easy to assume that people know these things about you.
But even when someone does know these things about you, they might not be top of mind.
Saying these things explicitly therefore serves at least two purposes:
(1) conveying the information, and
(2) bringing the information to the forefront of the other person&#39;s mind.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
This brings us to benefit of saying what you think number (3):
  saying what you think helps you clarify what you think.
If you&#39;re merely thinking the thing, then it can remain a fuzzy neural idea.
Saying it forces you to concretize it into words, and words that make sense to other human beings to boot!
This is standard advice about writing: by forcing you to articulate your ideas they become more precise.
The same is true for conversation too.
And not only do the ideas get better through the internal processes of formulation for speech and articulation itself,
you get benefit number (4):
  other people think about what you&#39;ve said.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Really hard to overstate the value of number (4).
One way to frame it is that you&#39;re putting other people&#39;s computation to work on your own problems.
I guess I&#39;m writing as a software engineer now.
It&#39;s parallelization!
By saying what you think to someone else, you might immediately double the processing power being devoted to the idea expressed.
Give a talk to a group of ten, and you&#39;re now using human processing power unobtainable even in a week&#39;s timeframe if working alone. Wild!
A less computation-centric way to frame this is that you get feedback from others.
That&#39;s really valuable for honing your ideas, deciding on future directions, finding collaborators, figuring out what makes others tick, etc.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
To recap we&#39;ve already uncovered a trove of benefits to SWYT:
* communicating information
* people can know/meet/actively-consider your needs/wants/etc
* clarify your own thinking
* getting other people&#39;s insights.
But there&#39;s so much more! Let&#39;s brainstorm onward.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
* Practice: By saying what you think, you get better at saying what you think! This means you can get all those other benefits we&#39;ve listed out more readily.
* Storytelling, forming connection with others, getting to know one another and learning new things. Being vulnerable and opening up might be difficult and scary at first, but can be rewarding too!
* Not implicitly projecting agreement through silence.
* Inspiring others
* Earning people&#39;s respect and trust
* Shaping the focus and attention of the audience and their circles
* Feeling connection, staving off loneliness
* Cheering someone up, expressing gratitude
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
I worry the brainstorm might have broadened too much;
  there sure are a lot of reasons to *communicate*,
but I&#39;m specifically interested in reasons for saying what you think when it might otherwise be difficult.
There are times when I might naturally choose not to say what I think and instead stay quiet
(or worse, implicitly suggest something opposed with what I actually think, e.g. to avoid conflict!).
My goal with this brainstorm is to enumerate the reasons in favor of saying what I think in these situations.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
* Honesty; staying true to myself
* Not being a pushover, not conceding ground simply because someone else is louder or more confident
* Promoting intellectual discussions, and an honest battle of ideas
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
I think I can sometimes assume people see things the same way I do even when that is not actually the case,
  e.g. because I assume my own belief is an obvious one.
But I&#39;ve learned since that when someone says they disagree, they generally actually do.
They aren&#39;t usually being silly or joking or sarcastic. And so it can be valuable to explore that disagreement.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
* Avoiding being misleading (see &#34;Not implicitly projecting agreement through silence&#34;; perhaps this is a generalization of that.) E.g. it can include not seeming like you&#39;re agreeing to do something when you actually don&#39;t intend to do it.
* In the case of expressing a preference about someone&#39;s behavior, it can be tempting not to say what you think because the situation seemingly has already passed.
But saying what you think can prevent future situations that bother you in the same way from coming about again.
&lt;-- This brings up a reason against saying what you think that I didn&#39;t think of in the first brainstorm: avoiding seeming petty or overly critical. I&#39;ll go up and add that there now.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid brainstorm! Moving on.&lt;br/&gt;
Well, not quite yet. After some additional writing, I resumed brainstorming mode for a moment longer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
* Getting my needs met?&#39;
  (I never did understand the idea of &#34;needs&#34;. Update: I&#39;ve learned the term universal motivators and may prefer that.)
* Letting people know what I&#39;m thinking about
  -&gt; Then people can share related ideas, introduce me to people who might be thinking about or working on related things, invite me to things I might enjoy
Can also establish connection between me and the other person.
It also makes it so much easier for people to respect my preferences if they know what they are.
(And doubly so if they&#39;re top of mind; a preference known but not present in the attention is little better than a preference unknown at all.)

I&#39;ve oft had an aversion to the notion of &#34;the squeaky wheel gets the grease&#34;, especially in situations when the grease is something evenly desirable to all wheels. What if a wheel isn&#39;t being squeaky out of respect for the needs of the other wheels, and for a belief in the fairness of the grease distributor? This was my thinking, but I&#39;m slowly moving away from this as I realize the truth of this aphorism might be out of our control. I don&#39;t know. On the one hand, we could teach all the wheels to be squeaky, and that would resolve the fairness concerns. But there is a long tail of wheels, and surely some wheels needing grease or other attention simply won&#39;t squeak. And all that extra squeaking doesn&#39;t sound super desirable to begin with.
Perhaps far better than teaching the wheels to squeak is to teach them what we can about the grease distributor. Then if beliefs in the fairness of the grease distributor are unsound, perhaps such beliefs won&#39;t develop as readily.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that concludes the brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that brainstorm I identified quite a host of benefits to saying what I think. Let&amp;rsquo;s recap with a list, and then expand on a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People can know/meet/actively-consider your needs/wants/motives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify your own thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get feedback or thoughts from others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice saying what you think so you&amp;rsquo;re better at it later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect with others, for yourself and for the others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid implicitly agreeing -&amp;gt; stay honest and true to yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspire others; shape the dialog!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn something new and promote dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice.&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s start off with a bit of a self-referential one. In combination with all the others, it ends up being quite important. Saying what I think now is key for making it easier to say what I think later. I.e. saying what I think when it is less important or less pressing (e.g. a dinner preference) might set me up well to say what I think in a hospital at some point, or in a courtroom, or a meeting with an executive etc. There are all these situations where the ability to stand up for one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs and to do so in a timely efficient manner is really important. And saying what you think &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt; is a key step toward being able to say what you think when it really matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not implicitly projecting agreement through silence.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few situations recently where someone has expressed an interest in working together, and I don&amp;rsquo;t explicitly say no, but I don&amp;rsquo;t say yes either, and while I say something indicative of hesitation, the other party seems to assume I&amp;rsquo;ve said yes. Similarly, I&amp;rsquo;ve had situations where someone expresses an idea, and I disagree, but I nod along so as to hear the rest of the idea and better understand it; this has also been mistaken for agreement as well. I&amp;rsquo;d love to project an accurate reflection of my beliefs, and this all starts with saying what I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting insights from others.&lt;/strong&gt; This can be the most satisfying one because it is by definition surprising.
When you get others&#39; thoughts on your ideas, you obtain new information, stuff you hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought of. Perhaps ideas you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know you weren&amp;rsquo;t considering! What a beautiful gift! If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and find yourself subconsciously falling prey to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-07-efficient-minds-fallacy/&#34;&gt;Efficient Minds Fallacy&lt;/a&gt;, this is a key benefit to remind yourself of. (I say &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;m clearly writing all this for myself&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting your needs met.&lt;/strong&gt; I think this is probably the most important one. The important kind of SWYTing that I want to encourage in myself is stating my boundaries clearly, expressing my emotions and opinions, and both knowing and expressing my preferences with confidence (all while remaining easy-going!). When a weakly-held (though possibly important) preference meets gentle conflict avoidance, by default the conflict avoidance can win out; this is where the SWYT mantra is critical!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarifying your thinking.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course saying what you think is a great way to develop your thoughts. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I write these snippets! It&amp;rsquo;s eye-opening how, while this benefit is tremendous and is a critical reason to SWYT, it feels like it pales in comparison to the previous one: getting your needs met. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because using SWYT to clarify my thinking is (comparatively) easy for me; e.g. I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing these snippets for three years now. Using SWYT in the face of conflict avoidance, on the other hand, is a challenge where having the SWYT mantra is really important for me. Nevertheless, the benefits of using SWYT to clarify my thinking both myself, as well as through the feedback and insights of those I share with, is a welcome reason to practice SWYT. I hope that by practicing SWYT here, I can become more comfortable with it in the more challenging situations where it arises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve identified about ten reasons against saying what you think, and about ten reasons in favor as well.
Since SWYT is part of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din/&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/a&gt;, you already know that I believe the benefits outweigh the reasons against pretty heavily.
But believing that consciously is not the same as living it, and there are still plenty of situations where SWYT is a challenge for me.
Primarily, the challenge arises when the SWYT principle butts heads with conflict avoidance, and I shirk from stating a preference. I hope that through the process of this reflection, as well as through practicing SWYT in both the easy and challenging situations, the challenging situations get ever easier to SWYT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Aspirations</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-09-17-musical-aspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-09-17-musical-aspirations/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I picked up violin again, after a 15 year hiatus. I&amp;rsquo;d played throughout fourth grade, but then put the instrument down to focus on my studies.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now plodding away at learning guitar and violin, and playing bits on the keyboard. It would be good to have some goals so I can direct my studies. One candidate goal based on my recent playing would be to produce You&amp;rsquo;ve Got a Friend in Me on all of these instruments: piano, violin, guitar, and I could even do vocals. I could record each of these separately and put them together in Ableton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing this on piano and violin seems well within reach. However, the number of new chords and speed of switching required to play it on guitar (at least from the arrangement I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far) doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel super within reach right now. And as for the vocals&amp;hellip; well, I can at least get the words out, even if not the notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the last time I thought about musical goals, I had some smaller ambitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On piano, I wanted to be able to play all the scales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On violin, You&amp;rsquo;ve Got a Friend in Me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even started guitar yet..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, I&amp;rsquo;ve just checked and I&amp;rsquo;d misremembered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My violin goal from Dec 3 2022 was to play scales in every key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My piano goal was also to play scales in every key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And my guitar goal was to play the chords in House of the Rising Sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these goals still seem like proper first goals. So, by putting them in a snippet, perhaps I will encourage myself to pursue them more quickly. Then I can get to my You&amp;rsquo;ve Got a Friend In Me goals sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: is that an instance of double sarcasm? I will have to dedicate a full snippet to double sarcasm at some point. In this instance, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be a joke, but also might literaly be true&amp;hellip; Maybe not sarcasm but something in that vein. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone in the kitchen evaluation</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-22-phone-in-kitchen-eval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-22-phone-in-kitchen-eval/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I decided to start keeping my phone in the kitchen while I&amp;rsquo;m in the house. I said I&amp;rsquo;d evaluate the decision after 6 weeks and decide whether to recommit. It&amp;rsquo;s been six weeks, and I think it was an excellent decision. I will absolutely continue doing this going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find I get more time in the mornings, because scrolling in bed or on the toilet isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option. Similarly in the evenings, scrolling in bed before going to sleep isn&amp;rsquo;t something I can do by accident. I do find I spend more time in the kitchen, in order to use my phone. So, I haven&amp;rsquo;t eliminated mindless scrolling altogether. My phone usage has decreased considerably overall though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oddest thing about it is that I don&amp;rsquo;t always have a way of knowing the itme when I wake up. I may want to put a non-phone clock in the bedroom to compensate for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes over the last six months I would find I accidentally would bring my phone with me to my desk. Usually this would happen after going out of the house for lunch (taking my phone with me). When I would return to the house, I would have my phone in my pocket, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t always remember to put it in the kitchen. Once the phone reached my desk, sometimes I would then inadvertently scroll! Whenever I notice that I&amp;rsquo;ve brought my phone somewhere in the house outside the kitchen, it&amp;rsquo;s clear the right thing for me to do under this silly system I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen for myself, is to bring it back to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be tempting to make only small violations to the rule, but I&amp;rsquo;ve realized it&amp;rsquo;s best not to fall for such temptations. There&amp;rsquo;s a bathroom just outside the kitchen, and I am tempted often to take the phone with me from the kitchen to the bathroom. I stop at the threshold to the kitchen, and do not cross if I&amp;rsquo;m holding my phone. Perhaps I stand in the threshold for a few minutes, finishing my phone usage before leaving. I put the phone down before exiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to take the phone to the bathroom, I know what would happen. I would think, going in, that I will just use the phone for one particular purpose. However, as soon as I turn the screen on I would notice something that would put a different purpose into my mind. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a text message, or an app icon, or a notification. I think, switching tasks, that it&amp;rsquo;s a small diversion and I will momentarily return to the original purpose. However, moments later while completing the secondary task, my mental stack will erode, and the primary task will no longer be at the forefront of my brain. I&amp;rsquo;ll no longer be thinking about the one-and-done approach to phone usage, and now the potential for mindless scrolling has emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the phone stays in the kitchen. I will keep this rule for myself, at least as long as I live here in this house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping my phone in the kitchen</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-08-phone-in-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-08-phone-in-kitchen/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep my phone in the kitchen while I&amp;rsquo;m in the house.
The goal is to reduce scrolling in the morning and evening, and prevent distractions more generally.
By keeping the phone in the kitchen, I&amp;rsquo;ll be unable to scroll mindlessly when I first wake up (unless of course I go to the kitchen to do so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by putting this intention up on my website, by having it in writing, by leaving it in a place where others could theoretically have read it, I am more likely to stick to this intention (both the spirit and the letter of it) for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I don&amp;rsquo;t yet know how this will go, or when I&amp;rsquo;ll first forget about it, I&amp;rsquo;ll pick a date now to check in on it. August 19, 2021. On August 19, 2021, six weeks from today, I&amp;rsquo;ll reevaluate this decision. If I like it, probably I will recommit to it for an additional period of time. If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me, no harm done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resuming habits</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-23-resuming-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-23-resuming-habits/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-17-a-torrent-of-snippets/&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/a&gt; I said I&amp;rsquo;d resume my “Snippets” and the “After Work Activities” habits today.
So, here I am, resuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still aiming to sleep by 10:10 tonight though, so not too much to say right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resuming snippet writing?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-17-resuming-snippet-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-17-resuming-snippet-writing/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About two month ago I encountered a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-21-snippets-dry-spell/&#34;&gt;snippets dry spell&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I didn&amp;rsquo;t foresee writing snippets at the same rate I had been leading up to that point. Sure enough, over the two months that followed I only wrote a handful of snippets. March saw two simultaneous Peer Learning Groups, and April lead into a period of intense virtual ping pong playing and lots of real-life hiking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up the Peer Learning Groups, a largely asynchronous low-commitment activity, with a virtual synchronous meet-up and coworking session. During these I produced these two snippets about what I learned for my PLG sessions: one on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-15-oil-pricing/&#34;&gt;Laser Eye Surgery&lt;/a&gt;, one on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-15-oil-pricing/&#34;&gt;Oil Pricing&lt;/a&gt;. I think this could be the trigger that brings me back into the pattern of writing snippets again, though I&amp;rsquo;m not certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting out to write snippets once more, I have a handful of half-baked ideas about what to write about: sleep, ping pong, virtual reality, hiking, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-21-snippets-dry-spell/&#34;&gt;list of ideas from February&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, yet more snippets about Browserflow and Roam Research, machine learning research, PLG and other online learning ideas, and pandemic coping are all on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sat down today to pen a snippet, I initially thought I would write about my ideas for using virtual reality table tennis for group coaching sessions. It felt funny though; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure why I was writing it. Was snippets a place to collect good ideas I may want to share with people in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This snippet is me taking a moment to reflect on why I write snippets, to reload my old reasoning back into memory, and to see if it still makes sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a few early reasons. Learning to communicate was a big one early on. Avoiding the addicting nature of social media was part of why I chose to write here, rather than on another platform. Feeling like I was writing for no audience, and the freedoms and desires that I found came with that, was a bigger reason for continuing on this platform rather than another. All of these continue to ring true, though there is one key way in which my writing deviates from its stated purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I set out to get better at communicating, one of my motivations was for communicating research. I&amp;rsquo;ve hardly written about my research at all! I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make a big change here; I like the type of topic I tend to select for snippets, and I like the expectation that I&amp;rsquo;ve set for myself that I can write about anything, with the bar set extremely low. That said, I will make a small mental adjustment, and add to my internal Potential Topics List writing about my published research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with this snippet, I hope and intend that I am resuming somewhat more frequent writing. This is a non-promise, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-08-biking-in-the-morning/&#34;&gt;a mere &amp;ldquo;aspirational intent&amp;rdquo; like the one I made about biking back in October&lt;/a&gt;. That one worked out though; I continued biking regularly well into the cold season, so I&amp;rsquo;m optimistic that this one will pan out positively as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crashing Facebook Japan, The “content sharing group”, 2021 goals, The “programmer’s apprentice”, Making decisions for 10,000 people, Roam Primitives: subscribe to changes, and Castles in the clouds (as a mental model for belief systems) &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biking in the Morning</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-08-biking-in-the-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 22:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-08-biking-in-the-morning/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-06-the-snippets-i-dont-publish/&#34;&gt;snippets I did not publish&lt;/a&gt; were about my plans for biking in the morning. For the last several days I&amp;rsquo;ve been biking to East Rock each morning, doing so before starting work on work days. I bring my pocket-sized keyboard and my phone, and when I&amp;rsquo;m at the top of the Rock I use my friend Jacob Cole&amp;rsquo;s app, ThoughtStream, to write about whatever&amp;rsquo;s on my mind. Sometimes this is a potential snippet, and sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just planning for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this routine but I&amp;rsquo;m not confident that I&amp;rsquo;ll continue it. Consistently getting up early for an extended period of time can be challenging, and I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to set an alarm to help. Also, the weather is getting cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly hope that I continue this routine, and I intend to maintain it. I simply don&amp;rsquo;t know that I will, and don&amp;rsquo;t feel confidently enough that I will to make any sort of declaration or commitment to doing so. Is there a name for this type of goal? I think &amp;ldquo;intent&amp;rdquo; is appropriate, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture the aspirational aspect of it. For now lets call it an &amp;ldquo;aspirational intent&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aspirationally intend to keep biking to East Rock most mornings, until the weather gets too cold to permit doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>