<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>go-note-go on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/go-note-go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in go-note-go on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/go-note-go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re driving to your campsite, listening to Tiago Forte discuss Sönke Ahrens&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;How to Take Smart Notes&amp;rdquo;, when a brilliant idea strikes you. Do you pull over, pull out your phone or moleskin, and write it down? Nay. Go Note Go to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While driving, simply press the large handheld red push button and speak your idea aloud. It will be automatically transcribed and added to your notes once an internet connection becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is the latest in my line&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of headless keyboard technologies, the successor to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell (2014)&lt;/a&gt;. As with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt;, no visual components are required to operate Go Note Go. You control the system only via audio or, optionally, by typing. Unlike with shh shell, it is inadvisable to keep your eyes closed while you use it, particularly if you are driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper now into what is Go Note Go, and what it brings to the note-taking space beyond shh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-go-note-go&#34;&gt;What is Go Note Go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physically, Go Note Go is a lightweight portable keyboard with a microphone and speaker, with a beautiful handheld button attached. The keyboard is a Raspberry Pi 400 &amp;ndash; so, it&amp;rsquo;s also a full computer with WiFi, Bluetooth, and a friendly Linux operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be powered by USB-C either from a small battery pack that velcros to the back, from a port in your car, a port on your main computer, or a standard outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-go-note-go-do&#34;&gt;What does Go Note Go do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go allows audio and text note-taking, as well as arbitrary audio and text command execution. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on note-taking first. We&amp;rsquo;ll return to command execution later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main ways to enter notes with Go Note Go (audio and text), corresponding to the two main use cases (driving and camping). The use cases of shh shell (sleeping and showering) are both still supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter notes via &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt;, simply press the large red handheld push button. Then speak your notes. The recording will be saved. When internet connectivity becomes available, your audio will be automatically machine transcribed and included in your note-taking system of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter notes via &lt;em&gt;text&lt;/em&gt;, type them. Press enter to commit a note. Press shift-backspace to clear the currently typed text. When internet connectivity becomes available, your notes will be uploaded to your central note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking notes by audio is great for driving, or for whenever speaking better suits your way of thinking than typing. Being able to seamlessly go back and forth between speaking and typing can be liberating, allowing for alternating different kinds of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is compact and portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go illustrating it is compact and portable.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It velcros to the passenger side of the car dashboard. It can be used there, or placed on a passenger’s lap during use, or even on the driver’s lap at a rest stop, waiting in line at a drive-thru, or while parked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be powered by the car by USB-C, or by battery pack for use on the go (or from a laptop or outlet USB port, if that better suits your use).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-dashboard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go on the passenger side of the car dashboard.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lie down with it and type or talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-soft.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go on a sofa.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or throw it in your sports bag to take notes on the game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gonotego-gym-bag.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Go Note Go in a gym bag.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-use-go-note-go-in-the-shower&#34;&gt;How do you use Go Note Go in the shower?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use Go Note Go in the shower, acquire a waterproof Bluetooth enabled keyboard, and pair it with your Go Note Go Raspberry Pi 400. Go ahead and leave that waterproof keyboard in your shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an improved experience, also acquire a waterproof Bluetooth speaker for your shower, and pair this with the Pi as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, your Pi simply has to be in range of your shower for you to use Go Note Go when generating your most groundbreaking insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No additional setup is required. Run the &amp;ldquo;:status&amp;rdquo; command to verify everything is working before typing a note to ensure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;improvements-over-shh-shell&#34;&gt;Improvements over Shh Shell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go supports audio notes and audio commands, whereas shh shell only supported text entry. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to fall asleep, text is less likely to wake up your mind, but if you&amp;rsquo;re driving, typing is incredibly dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go works offline and without a laptop nearby. To use shh shell, your keyboard needs to be connected wirelessly to a nearby computer running the shh shell software. Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s keyboard &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a computer, and it can be powered by battery pack, from a laptop, from an outlet, or from the car. Your notes will be uploaded to your main note-taking system as soon as internet connectivity becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need for annoying &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo; announcements. Anyone who sleeps near you will be pleased to hear Go Note Go is always in focus. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to announce &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;focus lost&amp;rdquo; for you to know if it&amp;rsquo;s OK to type. LED status indicators are also available for you to confirm it&amp;rsquo;s working (or you can run the &amp;ldquo;:status&amp;rdquo; command to get an auditory &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go integrates with external note-taking systems. I personally use Dropbox to store the audio clips and Roam Research to store the notes and display the audio (and now several other note-taking systems are also supported). This allows Go Note Go to directly contribute to my Spaced Repetition system, my notes on other projects, my notes on life, etc, and for my Go Note Go notes to be accessible anywhere, even on the go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go still supports all the old capabilities of shh shell. All the old commands still work, but now they work everywhere. Entering notes by text still works, but now it&amp;rsquo;s easier to search through them and return to them later. You can still use Go Note Go as you drift off to sleep, and you can still use Go Note Go when you shower, but now you can also use it as you drive or when you camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supported-note-taking-systems&#34;&gt;Supported Note-taking Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio clips are uploaded to Dropbox for storage (support for Google Drive forthcoming). The audio is then embedded alongside your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text notes are uploaded to whatever note-taking system you select; currently we support Roam Research, Notion, Ideaflow, Mem, and RemNote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is extensible to support other storage systems and note-taking systems. I aim to have Go Note Go work with all popular note-taking systems. So, if you want to add a new note-taking system, do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;issuing-commands&#34;&gt;Issuing Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go comes with an extensible command system. Like with shh shell, you can issue a textual command by starting a note with a colon &amp;ldquo;:&amp;rdquo;. Examples of supported commands include setting alarms with &amp;ldquo;:at 9am : alarm&amp;rdquo;, or getting the time read aloud to you with &amp;ldquo;:time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell write up&lt;/a&gt; for more on text commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go supports voice commands too. I use the keyword &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo; to issue an audio command. &amp;ldquo;go go time&amp;rdquo; will cause the system to read the time aloud. And &amp;ldquo;go go read back&amp;rdquo; will have the system read back your last typed note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-it-called-go-note-go&#34;&gt;Why is it called Go Note Go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go. Like any good note-taking system, it can help you make decisions. This includes but is not limited to go/no-go decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is not implemented in Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-not-just-take-notes-on-your-computer-or-phone-or-with-a-voice-recorder&#34;&gt;Why not just take notes on your computer or phone, or with a voice recorder?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is great at reducing friction. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice not having to switch to a note-taking app. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch tabs or windows. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anything to load. If the keyboard is there and on, you can type on it and know your notes are being recorded (there are LED status indicators for peace of mind.) No latency means minimal cognitive load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also of course nice not having to do any manual uploading or transcription that other approaches might require. And being integrated with your central note-taking system is a big plus over some alternate app approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for extensible commands (e.g. for sending messages, reading emails, whatever&amp;hellip;) is a nice plus too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course my favorite feature is that there is no monitor, and so no distractions. There&amp;rsquo;s no endless scrolling on Facebook, no accidentally visiting Reddit or Twitter. Just a keyboard, a button, and your brain at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-is-go-note-go-extensible&#34;&gt;How is Go Note Go extensible?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways. You can bring your own note-taking system, and you can add arbitrary voice and textual commands to Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note-taking systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go can support uploading notes to any note-taking system. We started with just Roam Research, and now also support Notion, RemNote, Ideaflow, and Mem. Adding new systems is easy, and if you want to use Go Note Go with a different note-taking system, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to help you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go also supports voice and text commands. You can add your own commands as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-need-to-push-a-button-instead-of-a-wake-word&#34;&gt;Why need to push a button instead of a wake word?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m always being listened to. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want it recording conversations. I only want it to record when I tell it to, and the physical switch is quite satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-i-try-it-out&#34;&gt;How can I try it out?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware components used are listed on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s no getting started guide yet, so if you are trying it out, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to reach out for guidance around the rough edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two points define a line, right? &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete and Concise List of Go Note Go&#39;s Features</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt; is a computer keyboard with no screen that I use to capture ideas anywhere, even as I drift off to sleep.
This is a complete list of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s features as of January 2023. Expand any of the features for more information about it.
The main use cases for Go Note Go are capturing thoughts while sleeping, driving, camping, and showering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&#34;expand-button&#34; onclick=&#34;expandCollapseAll()&#34;&gt;Expand All&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
details details {
  margin-left: 2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-features-just-the-useful-ones&#34;&gt;Main features (Just the useful ones)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture typed notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main feature of Go Note Go. Anything you type on it will show up in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about whether you have your note-taking app open, or whether your computer is running slowly.
One of the challenges I face with jotting things down when I&amp;rsquo;m at a computer is quickly getting to the place where I can jot things down.
Switching to my notes app can be slow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with a keyboard shortcut or a hot corner for taking notes, this requires switching focus on your computer.
You need to wait until the text field shows up. Once the text field has focus, then you can type, but if for some reason your computer is running slowly, your mind will run slowly too. By this, I mean that when letters show up slowly on a screen, it slows down the speed at which you think.
When typing with a screen, people naturally wait for the screen to catch up before continuing typing a thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Go Note Go, there&amp;rsquo;s no screen to see your notes. You don&amp;rsquo;t spend time waiting for the computer to catch up to you.
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch windows or click in a textbox before you can start typing.
You simply turn to the Go Note Go keyboard, and everything you type will show up in your notes once the Go Note Go gets an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture spoken notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go can also capture spoken notes.
Press the capture key (escape, by default; you can also use a large handheld red button if preferred) and Go Note Go will start recording.
Press the capture key again to stop recording.
The recording will be transcribed and added to your notes once Go Note Go has internet.
The raw audio is also included in your notes alongside the transcription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capturing spoken notes is especially useful for capturing ideas while driving.
Obviously I&amp;rsquo;m not typing on the keyboard while I&amp;rsquo;m driving; that would be unsafe. (The passenger can type though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to take spoken notes can also occasionally come in handy as I drift off to sleep.
Usually, I prefer typing, even as I drift off to sleep. It seems to wake me up less.
But when I&amp;rsquo;m especially tired, speaking can feel like the lower effort method and wake me up less than typing does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio notes are not always transcribed perfectly, and are annotated with &amp;ldquo;unverified transcription&amp;rdquo; by default.
You can verify the transcription is correct, cleaning up any transcription mistakes, and can quickly mark the transcription as verified to help you keep track of which transcriptions have and have not been reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;No screen&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having a screen is one of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s major selling points for me, and it comes with a host of benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost it means that there are no distractions while writing.
As a result my head feels so much clearer when I sit down to write at a Go Note Go compared to writing at a computer.
When writing on a computer, the internet is there with all its 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/&#34;&gt;infinite distractions&lt;/a&gt;, which can make staying focused a challenge.
None of those scroll-inducing websites exist on Go Note Go, making it easier to think and stick to my intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absence of a screen also helps me to write more effectively.
For me, some of the main challenges in writing are losing time to repeatedly rereading what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, and wordsmithing it with relatively inconsequential edits that would be better to hold off until revisions.
Since you can&amp;rsquo;t see typos while working on Go Note Go, you learn to accept them, and you save small amounts of time in significant quantities by not fixing little errors as you write. All of that can be cleaned up in post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the main 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-12-30-go-note-go-story/&#34;&gt;initial motivation&lt;/a&gt; for not having a screen is that it lets me capture thoughts even as I drift off to sleep, without waking me up very much.
Alternatives to capturing thoughts like turning on the lights to write on paper, taking out my phone or computer, or speaking into a voice recorder all wake me (or my partner) up more than just typing on a keyboard in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually find Go Note Go helpful for getting to sleep, since it lets me get thoughts out of my head.
Without it, sometimes an anxious thought will swirl around in my head, showing up repeatedly in dozens of different forms.
Using Go Note Go, I can get a single version of the thought into my notes, and somehow that minimizes the thought swirling.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if by finding a canonical version of the thought and preserving it in Go Note Go, my brain is relieved of its duty to hold onto the thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Works offline&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go works offline. You can bring it into the woods with you if you want to go camping, for example.
Normally, I leave Go Note Go plugged into a standard outlet, but I also have a battery pack I take with me for using Go Note Go on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notes you enter into Go Note Go are uploaded to your notes as soon as internet becomes available.
It&amp;rsquo;s OK if the battery dies before then; the notes are stored on a MicroSD card and will be uploaded later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Go Note Go transcribes your notes once internet becomes available.
Voice notes don&amp;rsquo;t get transcribed on device; we currently use Google Transcription as our transcription provider, which requires an internet connection.
So, voice notes taken in the forest are transcribed and uploaded once you get back to civilization and Go Note Go connects to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working offline is particularly useful for using Go Note Go while driving and camping.
It also makes Go Note Go a good candidate for writing in parks or coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Act as an outliner&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using tab to indent and shift-tab to dedent, you can use Go Note Go as a proper outliner.
This allows you to take properly nested notes, despite not being able to see them while you take them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full list of outliner controls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab to indent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Tab to dedent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Delete to clear the current note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter on an empty note dedents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Delete on an empty note dedents the maximum amount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Enter starts a new session (a separate section of notes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 minutes of inactivity also starts a new session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitting enter on an empty line also causes a dedent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Run commands&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Go Note Go, any note that starts with a colon is interpreted as a command. There are loads of commands, generally they produce audio output (like reading the time aloud). I&amp;rsquo;ve listed the main commands here, and adding new commands with Python is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/command_center/commands.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;easy&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:time&lt;/code&gt; Read the time out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:r&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:read&lt;/code&gt; Read the last note out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:q TEXT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:ask TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Ask a question of the AI assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt; Send the current session of notes to the AI assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:at TIME:DO&lt;/code&gt; Schedule command DO to run at time TIME. TIME can be a natural language time like &amp;ldquo;in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;8am&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ok&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:status&lt;/code&gt; Say &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; out loud; useful for verifying your hands are in the right place and that Go Note Go is on and functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands can also be activated via voice. Press the capture button (escape by default) and say &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo; followed by the command to trigger its execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are additional commands for configuring Go Note Go, as well as more technical commands less useful during common usage.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Expand this for the full list of commands.&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-commands&#34;&gt;System commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:whoami&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:who am i&lt;/code&gt; Read aloud the current user and currently selected note-taking system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:time&lt;/code&gt; Read the time out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:at TIME:DO&lt;/code&gt; Schedule command DO to run at time TIME. TIME can be a natural language time like &amp;ldquo;in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;8am&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:status&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ok&lt;/code&gt; Say &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; out loud; useful for verifying your hands are in the right place and that Go Note Go is on and functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:say TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Say TEXT out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:shell CMD&lt;/code&gt; Run command CMD in a shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:flush&lt;/code&gt; Flush the logs; this is useful for debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:update&lt;/code&gt; Download updates to your Go Note Go; :restart for them to take effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:restart&lt;/code&gt; Restart all Go Note Go processes on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:reboot&lt;/code&gt; Reboot the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:env&lt;/code&gt; Log the environment variables and their values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ip&lt;/code&gt; Read the IP address of the Go Note Go out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:i&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:internet&lt;/code&gt; Say Yes or No out loud, indicating whether Go Note Go has internet access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:wifi SSID PSK&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:wpa SSID PSK&lt;/code&gt; Configure Go Note Go to connect to the wifi with ssid SSID using passkey PSK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;settings-commands&#34;&gt;Settings Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:get KEY&lt;/code&gt; Read out loud the value associated with setting KEY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:set KEY VALUE&lt;/code&gt; Set the setting KEY to VALUE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:clear KEY&lt;/code&gt; Clear setting KEY, reverting its value back to that found in your settings.py file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:clear&lt;/code&gt; Clear all settings entered via the :set command, reverting their values back to those found in your settings.py file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:leds ON/OFF/LOW&lt;/code&gt; Set the brightness of the LEDs. Only relevant if you&amp;rsquo;re using the Adafruit Voice Bonnet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:v ON/OFF&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:volume ON/OFF&lt;/code&gt; Turn the audio volume on or off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:get status KEY&lt;/code&gt; Get status indicator given by KEY. The status indicators are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/common/status.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possible settings are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/settings/secure_settings_template.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note-commands-unnecessary&#34;&gt;Note commands (Unnecessary!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:note TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Add TEXT as a note. (Just type TEXT! No need to use this command.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:subnote TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Add TEXT as an indented note. (Just indent and type TEXT! No need to use this command.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter-commands&#34;&gt;Twitter Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is not a common use case for Go Note Go, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit funny that it has it&amp;rsquo;s own section. These commands are predominantly for configuring Go Note Go to use your Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter user&lt;/code&gt; Read the current Twitter use out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter user USER&lt;/code&gt; Set the current Twitter user to USER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter auth&lt;/code&gt; Start the Twitter auth flow for Go Note Go developers (requires ssh and implementation-details to complete).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter auth EMAIL&lt;/code&gt; Start the Twitter auth flow; instructions for completing the flow will be emailed to EMAIL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter pin PIN&lt;/code&gt; Use this command to complete the auth flow; enter the pin you received in the email from the previous command as PIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter&lt;/code&gt; Switch the current note-taking system to be Twitter. Now all notes will be posted directly to Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To log into Twitter, run &lt;code&gt;:twitter&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:twitter user USER&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:twitter auth EMAIL&lt;/code&gt;, and finally &lt;code&gt;:twitter pin PIN&lt;/code&gt; entering the pin you receive in the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-commands&#34;&gt;Email Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:email TO SUBJECT: TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Send an email to TO with subject SUBJECT and body TEXT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding new commands is always a pleasure, but it&amp;rsquo;s good to keep the capabilities of Go Note Go limited, to prevent potential distractions from creeping onto the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Audio-only clock&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go sports loads of commands (see above), but the one I use most is having Go Note Go read the time out loud. I prefer this to looking at a clock or my phone because I can keep my eyes closed as I use it, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t wake me up as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To trigger this feature, I type &lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;AI assistant&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI assistant is a feature I only added recently to Go Note Go, and I have a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/&#34;&gt;whole snippet&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to my experience with it. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of interacting with the assistant today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:q TEXT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:ask TEXT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I just want to ask a single question of the assistant, I use this command. The assistant&amp;rsquo;s response is read out loud. This is the more private approach as only TEXT is sent to the AI, not any additional notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to have an extended conversation or interaction with the AI assistant, I use this command. I can either run &lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt; after typing my message to the AI, or I can prefix my message with &lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt;. Both work. This command sends the entire session of notes to the AI assistant. The AI assistant&amp;rsquo;s response is read out loud, and is included in the session of notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the AI&amp;rsquo;s responses are included in the notes and are marked as being AI responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/&#34;&gt;read more about my experience talking to the AI assistant as I drift off to sleep here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-wait-theres-more&#34;&gt;But wait, there&amp;rsquo;s more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Use your favorite note-taking system: Roam Research, RemNote, Mem, IdeaFlow, Notion, or even Twitter or Email&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported note-taking systems are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roam Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RemNote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IdeaFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roam Research is the one I use daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are Twitter and Email on this list?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you set your note-taking system to Twitter, every note you take on your Go Note Go will be posted to Twitter. This is an unconventional choice! Perhaps you like thinking in public though. Perhaps you live in a community house and want a place to share quirky quotes that come up. You do you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email is a nice fallback system for people that don&amp;rsquo;t already use one of the others. When I give Go Note Gos as gifts, I generally configure them to use email so. This lets the Go Note Go work out-of-the-box without the recipient needing to configure it with their account credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also switch between note-taking systems at any point with a single command. I recommend making your Go Note Go a single-purpose device with just a single target note-taking system, but you should still note that this is an option. The command to switch note-taking systems is &lt;code&gt;:set uploader NOTE_TAKING_SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;NOTE_TAKING_SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; is one of &lt;code&gt;email&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ideaflow&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;remnote&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;roam&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mem&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;notion&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;twitter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Never miss a note&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you walk away from Go Note Go without hitting enter, your note will be submitted after 3 minutes of inactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go boots in about 15 seconds, after which point it is always ready to receive inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s always ready &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s no tab switching or waiting required before you can start typing &amp;ndash; is a big deal to me.
Compared with writing notes on a computer, writing on Go Note Go feels smoother and more natural.
On a computer, I need to switch tabs to give focus to my note-taking app before I can start typing.
That context switch may sound small, but it is meaningful, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have done away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the option to pause note-taking on your Go Note Go. This is not recommended. To enable this, set the PAUSE_HOTKEY setting.
This creates a trigger for pausing and unpausing note-taking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Send people messages&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending people messages is actually not a core feature of Go Note Go, but it is something that I built for myself on top of Go Note Go.
If I include text like &amp;ldquo;@Person&amp;rdquo; in my notes, then my Messager project will pick up the note and queue up a message to Person.
Notes nested underneath the @-tagged note are also included in the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;a whole post dedicated to this feature&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported messaging systems in the Messager project are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter (both public and private tweets, as well as DMs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacker News submissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iMessage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord - this one unfortunately is not in a working state at this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It supports aliases, so that I can set short-names for people to send messages to their preferred communications platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a message is in the queue, I can clean it up and approve it. I can also specify a time for it to send, with the default being to send now.
Once approved, it sends automatically at the desired time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Mounts on the passenger side of the dashboard&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put Velcro on the bottom of one of my Go Note Gos, and on the passenger side of my car dashboard.
This way I can mount the Go Note Go in the car.
Using the capture button (e.g. a large handheld red button), you can capture audio recordings while driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve largely switched away from using Go Note Go while driving in favor of calling by AI assistant on the phone (implemented via Twilio).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;It&#39;s open source&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code and set up instructions for Go Note Go are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;all freely available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total cost of parts is about $100. I encourage you to make your own! Please 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;go-note-go@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me if you do&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;The right amount of customizability&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing you can configure is which note-taking system you&amp;rsquo;d like to upload your notes to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be any of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roam Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RemNote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IdeaFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw audio files are uploaded to Dropbox and included in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two other areas Go Note Go can be configured are adding new commands, and adding new note-taking systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Your notes are easy to review&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you take notes on Go Note Go, they are divided into sessions.
Each time you sit down at a Go Note Go after a period of inactivity, a new session is created.
You can also start a new session at any time by hitting Shift-Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notes, sessions are timestamped and organized chronologically. All the notes in a session are nested underneath the timestamped session header.
When I review my notes, I like to place a one-line summary of a session in the timestamped session header. I can then collapse the session.
This makes it easy to quickly scan through my notes, looking only at the session headers. I can expand a session to see it&amp;rsquo;s contents for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/01-17-2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Take a look at some example Go Note Go notes here&lt;/a&gt; to see what this looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emergent-benefits&#34;&gt;Emergent benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Focus and Relief&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like how Go Note Go is a single-purpose device.
The absence of a screen and the absence of any distractions on Go Note Go make for a soothing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a desk at home with just a Go Note Go on it.
Sitting down at my Go Note Go desk fills me with an immediate sense of relief.
When writing at a computer, by comparison, I notice a tension in my body.
Go Note Go relieves this tension and clears my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Avoid distracting others (incl. w/ Bluetooth headphones)&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi 400s have Bluetooth support. So, you can connect Bluetooth headphones to Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, I use Go Note Go with my AirPods. When I put the AirPods in, Go Note Go automatically connects.
I can then ask the AI assistant questions on the Go Note Go and get the answers piped directly to my ears,
so my coworkers are not distracted.
If I take the headphones out, Go Note Go outputs to the attached speaker.
So, I can show colleagues Go Note Go without them needing to put headphones in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also consider capturing ideas as you drift off to sleep.
Compared with other options for capturing these ideas, Go Note Go is comparatively non-disruptive.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any bright lights or loud sounds.
It&amp;rsquo;s not perfectly quiet either though, so there&amp;rsquo;s room for improvement here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Check the time without fully waking up&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s commands all work without you ever having to open your eyes.
If you&amp;rsquo;re drifting off to sleep, this is ideal. You can get the time without activating your brain too much, making it easier to continue drifting off to sleep.
Compare this with looking at your phone or at a clock. These options require opening your eyes, possibly subjecting them to bright lights.
No thank you. I prefer Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; command for getting the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Take it camping&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go lasts for about twelve hours on this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07JYYRT7T?th=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3A 10400mAh power bank&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s small and lightweight, easy to toss in the car and take camping.
There are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/5292&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cases&lt;/a&gt; you can purchase to make Go Note Go more portable for this kind of use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camping was one of the original use cases for Go Note Go, and in fact I designed the system and ordered the first batch of parts while camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for camping are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works offline, so you can use it anywhere; it will upload your notes as soon as you get an internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s portable and can run on battery for a decent length of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no screen or bright lights to annoy other campers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture thoughts while drifting off to sleep&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main culmination of the features is that Go Note Go is great for capturing thoughts while you&amp;rsquo;re drifting off to sleep.
This was the primary motivation for Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s predecessor, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;Shh Shell&lt;/a&gt;.
I had some thoughts that were keeping me awake (this is back in 2014!), and I wanted to write them down.
I found that by writing them down, I could get them out of my head, and fall asleep.
However, conventional methods of writing them down would wake me or my roommate up. So, I built Shh Shell to solve that problem.
Today, it has evolved into Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for capturing sleep thoughts are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no screen or bright lights to wake you up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always ready to capture notes; there&amp;rsquo;s no fiddling with getting into notes mode in the middle of the night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That it acts as an audio-only clock as well is just a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Use Go Note Go while driving&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with the idea for Go Note Go while driving to a campground.
When I initially built Go Note Go, I included a large handheld red button you could push to trigger audio recording.
This button made Go Note Go useful while driving.
For example, if I was listening to an audio book and wanted to capture a thought, I could simply push the trigger and speak my thoughts aloud.
Then, when I arrive at the campground, I could take the Go Note Go off the dashboard and toss it in the tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for capturing thoughts while driving are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works offline, so you can use it anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no visual, so you can keep your attention on the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The large red button is easy to push even when you&amp;rsquo;re driving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It captures audio notes and transcribes them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It mounts nicely to the passenger side of the car dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Avoid carsickness&lt;/summary&gt;
As a passenger in a car, it can be tempting to use your phone. Especially if you&#39;re taking an Uber and not engaging with the driver, this temptation can be quite strong; phones are little dopamine boxes, and will happily consume your attention endlessly. In a car, this can leave you feeling carsick.
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this issue. Using Go Note Go in a case, it is truly easy to take on the go. The battery sits in the case and the Go Note Go rests flat on your lap while you use it. The best part? Using Go Note Go doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you carsick, because you&amp;rsquo;re not watching the device as you use it. You&amp;rsquo;re eyes are free to look forward (or wherever) the whole time. Such relief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Great for long flights&lt;/summary&gt;
Using Go Note Go with a case makes it so easy to take on the go. And since it works offline, it&#39;s ideal for use on a long flight. The battery I use lasts 12 hours, so this works even if your flight doesn&#39;t have an outlet. If there is an outlet, 5V is sufficient.
&lt;p&gt;I find I much prefer writing on Go Note Go on a flight compared with hours of back to back movie watching. Not everyone has this predilection; to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture shower thoughts&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of driving, camping, and sleeping, where else are the best ideas generated? That&amp;rsquo;s right, in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can connect a waterproof Bluetooth keyboard to your Go Note Go and bring it into the shower with you to capture these critical insights.
You can also use a Bluetooth shower speaker for audio output.
I have not yet seen a shower microphone suitable for capturing audio thoughts in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo from 2015 of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;Shh Shell (Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s predecessor)&lt;/a&gt; set up in my shower in California.
The keyboard is on the ledge to the right of the shower speaker.
&lt;img src=&#34;shower-keyboard.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of my shower in California from 2015. The Shh Shell keyboard sits on the windowsill next to a Bluetooth speaker. There&amp;rsquo;s a 3D printed shaving cream holder mounted to the soap dish below.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  var expandButton = document.getElementById(&#39;expand-button&#39;);
  var isExpanded = false;

  function expandCollapseAll() {
    var detailsElements = document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;details&#39;);
    for (var i = 0; i &lt; detailsElements.length; i++) {
      detailsElements[i].open = !isExpanded;
    }
    isExpanded = !isExpanded;
    expandButton.textContent = isExpanded ? &#39;Close All&#39; : &#39;Expand All&#39;;
  }
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-go-note-go-usage&#34;&gt;Personal Go Note Go usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have Go Note Gos everywhere! There&amp;rsquo;s one in my kitchen, one in each bed in my home, and one on each of my desks at home and at work.
Unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s a backlog on Raspberry Pis (with US keyboard layouts), or else I&amp;rsquo;d have even more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Total writing volume&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written 150,000 words on Go Note Go in the last 16 months. By way of comparison, my notes in Roam Research from the last four years (counting both Go Note Go and other note-taking) total 507,000 words. My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;snippets&lt;/a&gt; total 123,000 words over two years. My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; total 26,000 words over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Giving Go Note Go as gifts&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want other people to experience the joys of Go Note Go. So I have on a few occasions given them as gifts.
There are about ten Go Note Gos out there to the best of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to put one in a public park one day (connected to Twitter) and see what people type on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also build your own Go Note Go. It&amp;rsquo;s completely open source. The code and set up instructions for Go Note Go are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;all freely available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and the total cost of parts is about $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Typing vs talking&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of my Go Note Go notes I enter by typing, rather than by speaking.
Even when I&amp;rsquo;m fairly tired, I find that typing wakes me up less than speaking does.
There does reach a point for me where this switches though; when I&amp;rsquo;m extremely tired, I will sometimes prefer to speak than to type. In those moments, speaking feels lower effort and like it will wake me up less.
It&amp;rsquo;s nice that Go Note Go supports both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a phone number I can call where my AI assistant picks up, though that project is still early stages.
I use that more than Go Note Go while driving these days, and also prefer that approach when I&amp;rsquo;m just walking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capturing dreams&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started this night typing practice, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet comfortable typing without looking, and so my fingers were not positioned correctly on the keyboard. I woke up and saw I had collected a full paragraph of gibberish, ending with the phrase &amp;ldquo;I hope the FBI doesn&amp;rsquo;t find out about this&amp;rdquo;.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember having written anything at all the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One letter at a time I decoded the gibberish. Roughly, each letter had to be shifted by one on a QWERTY keyboard layout; it was a bit of a puzzle to decode. To my amazement and delight, as I decoded the text my memory of writing it came flooding back to me. I can describe it in no other way than that; it was like a missing piece of my brain had been unlocked, truly a rewarding feeling. I had woken up from a dream the night before, typed the dream into the keyboard, and promptly fallen asleep. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember the dream or that I had typed it until I was decoding the text.
What a relief to find out I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually hiding anything from the FBI!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Thinking differently at night&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find my brain produces different thoughts while I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep as compared with during the day.
(My AI assistant calls this phenomenon either &amp;ldquo;hypnagogia&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;procrastination&amp;rdquo;. I prefer the former.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a period of calm and reflection, where I am alone with my thoughts.
My brain can process topics that it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to get to throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than going against the grain of my brain and trying to induce these thoughts while I&amp;rsquo;m still awake, I use Go Note Go to capture these thoughts without overly interrupting my bed time routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I might think of reaching out to someone while lying awake in bed. Without Go Note Go, I might forget about this in the morning. With Go Note Go, I can write a quick message to them in the moment, and review and send it when I wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Example notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you can get a better picture of what these Go Note Go notes look like, I&amp;rsquo;ve copied 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/01-17-2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a short section of my Go Note Go notes here&lt;/a&gt;. This will give you a brief taste of what the notes look like when I go to review them. You can see how they&amp;rsquo;re divided into time-stamped sessions, how the AI assistant&amp;rsquo;s responses are indented beneath the preceding note, and how I put summaries at the top of some of the sessions. Feel free to take your own notes in that public note-base too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, building and using Go Note Go these last two years has been a joy. I&amp;rsquo;ve met lots of wonderful people through Go Note Go, as there&amp;rsquo;s a lovely community of folks interested in tools for networked thought and audio note-taking. If these topics interest you, definitely 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;go-note-go@gmail.com&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch&lt;/a&gt;, even if just to say you&amp;rsquo;re interested. And finally for the hackers among you, I encourage you to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;try out Go Note Go yourself&lt;/a&gt;. I hope that headless computing becomes more prominent in the years to come, and that you can be a part of that. Let&amp;rsquo;s take away our screens, take back our attention, and live with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping with GPT</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few nights I have been sleeping with GPT, and oh, it has been a joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-capturing-my-thoughts-as-i-drift-off-to-sleep&#34;&gt;Background: Capturing my thoughts as I drift off to sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a note-taking device that I call 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s a computer keyboard without a screen that I type on to capture my thoughts everywhere, even as I drift off to sleep.
I have one in my bed, and I also keep them on my desk at work and in various spots around my apartment; anywhere an idea strikes, I have a Go Note Go keyboard ready to capture that idea.
Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main purpose is to let me quickly jot down these ideas so I can remember them later, e.g. after getting a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
It also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;does other things (click for a concise primer on Go Note Go)&lt;/a&gt; like speaking the time aloud or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;letting me send messages to other people&lt;/a&gt;.
Most recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve added an AI assistant to Go Note Go, and have begun conversing with it as I drift off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before adding the AI assistant, Go Note Go had become a staple in my life.
Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main capability &amp;ndash; capturing my thoughts &amp;ndash; helps me fall asleep more effectively.
If I have an anxious thought swirling in my brain, I can simply type it into Go Note Go.
Instead of dozens of versions of the thought popping up in my head all night, I have just a single canonical version of the thought stored on the device, and I can fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go also supports commands, like reading the time out loud.
Entering a line that starts with a colon (&#39;:&#39;) issues a command.
Typing :r has it read back the last thing I wrote.
Typing :t will have it read the time to me.
I like this because it lets me know the time without having to open my eyes, so getting the time doesn&amp;rsquo;t require being alert&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this lets me drift off to sleep more effectively. I can get ideas out of my head while avoiding things that would wake me up, like looking at my phone or turning on the lights to write down an idea.
Compared with writing on my phone, or a computer, or on paper, writing on Go Note Go is relaxing and doesn&amp;rsquo;t wake me up very much.
So, Go Note Go has become an essential tool in my daily routine, helping me capture and organize my thoughts, and allowing me to relax and fall asleep more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-an-ai-assistant-to-go-note-go&#34;&gt;Adding an AI assistant to Go Note Go&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently, I added an AI assistant to Go Note Go and I absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default when I type on the keyboard the text just shows up in my notes,
but now I have the option of sending the text off to an AI assistant as well.
Since there&amp;rsquo;s no screen on Go Note Go, the assistant&amp;rsquo;s responses are read out loud.
They&amp;rsquo;re also inserted into my notes for future reference, which I can browse later at a computer or on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my Go Note Go usage remains unchanged, but one aspect now feels very different: drifting off to sleep.
This is when having the AI assistant feels most rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sleeping-with-gpt-what-do-we-discuss&#34;&gt;Sleeping with GPT: What do we discuss?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lying there in the bed, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really trying to go to sleep.
I&amp;rsquo;m excited that I have this new AI with me which I can ask anything at all.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to learn organic chemistry but haven&amp;rsquo;t found the time; this seems a perfect opportunity to get started.
On the first night I drift off to sleep peppering the AI with questions about organic chemistry and battery technology.
On subsequent nights I probe new topics, trying to get a deeper understanding of the superficial things I learned the night before, and also introducing new topics to our discussions.
I continue peppering the AI with questions about chemistry and history as I drift off to sleep.
Quickly realizing that this could inhibit my ability to get a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep, I also ask for advice in that regard, and it obliges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clear from the outset that I&amp;rsquo;m going to want to write about this, so I&amp;rsquo;m jotting down notes for this very post. I ask my assistant to turn my notes into an outline. That outline is read out loud, and it&amp;rsquo;s also sitting there for me the next day when I go to start writing in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, when I wake up, I ask for strategies for a morning routine. It makes good suggestions.
Though the response is nothing that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find from a quick Google search for morning routine ideas, the proximity to those ideas as I&amp;rsquo;m just waking up, casually typing to my keyboard, makes them more actionable. The suggestions are things like making my bed right away, drinking a glass of lemon water, and doing some exercise to get my blood flowing. It feels inspiring and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I asked the AI assistant to read me a bedtime story. I gave it some details about my own life first and it used them to construct a story that was personal and meaningful to me, albeit a bit silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Other benefits of the assistant: reading back capturing notes and answering questions about them. --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trust-and-confidence&#34;&gt;Trust and Confidence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An invitation into one&amp;rsquo;s bed requires a certain level of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a common criticism of GPT and language models more broadly is that they are often factually inaccurate. What&amp;rsquo;s worse is that when they are wrong, they often are wrong with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes learning about new topics like battery technology and organic chemistry a challenge.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the things that I have learned these last few nights are true or not.
In fact, I know that some of them are definitely not true, because GPT will sometimes flatly contradict itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the distinct feeling that I have been learning a lot from these night time question peppering sessions.
Is this feeling valid, or have I been duped by the AI?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suss out truth from fiction, my first line of defense is my intuition.
Using my own limited knowledge of the topic we are discussing, I can sometimes tell if the model is fibbing.
If what the model says fits nicely into my world model, I might trust it and move on.
When things don&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me, I can ask for explanations or ask pointed questions to dive into the details.
These will quickly seem inconsistent, either with each other or with what I already know, if in fact the model has made up inaccurate information.
(This observation should motivate new, fully automated, methods for discovering truth in these models as well. For example the line of reasoning that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.11822&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maieutic Prompting&lt;/a&gt; pursues proceeds along these lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability to dive deep into the details, sometimes asking extremely basic questions that I would be embarrassed to ask a human, points to a different kind of trust that I do have for the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-trust&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I cannot trust the AI to produce factual statements consistently, it has earned my trust in a different way.
I can be uninhibited with GPT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can ask naive questions, things that I would feel embarrassed to ask a human. I can ask &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; about the most trivial things, the way a 3-year old might, to discover more about the world.
I don&amp;rsquo;t feel any concern that the model will judge me for not knowing something, or not understanding something quickly.
I can ask the same question repeatedly, without concern for taking up its time, or that it has better places to be.
The AI is infinitely patient with me.
I don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how it will feel if I doubt what it&amp;rsquo;s telling me, and express skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these ways, it is an ideal tutor. By giving me the freedom to explore the topics that interest me, the things I&amp;rsquo;m learning about feel truly connected to one another, rather than ad hoc and unrelated to my interests as they might if I were following a curriculum not tailored to my needs and interests. It would be better, of course, if I could trust it to be factually accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a brief aside: I think this experience &amp;ndash; interacting with an AI tutor, guided by a curriculum and standards, but free to wander through information space as it pleases the user, is going to be central to education in the future. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to explore the space of possible AI-centric classroom and education designs, to find novel ways of learning jointly with humans and AIs, and I intend to do so further in future snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can I be so free with GPT in ways that I cannot be with a human? I can identify a few reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine&amp;rsquo;s statelessness / resetability is one key component. It isn&amp;rsquo;t learning about me, forming long term judgements. If I reveal that I don&amp;rsquo;t know some &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; concept, like what an ionic bond is, it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to retain that information and shape our future interactions based on it. The next conversation I have with the assistant will be tabula rasa, starting from a blank slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its isolation from others is another factor. I can confide in it, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to gossip or reveal anything I tell it to another human. Sure, I have concerns that OpenAI gets access to whatever I send to the assistant, and this could show up in training data or in front of human evaluators as a result. Nevertheless, it feels private, like no one in my life would see the things I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there&amp;rsquo;s a third trait that aids in creating this kind of trust that&amp;rsquo;s harder to pin down. Something about the inhuman form factor &amp;ndash; something about how it feels like talking to a machine &amp;ndash; enables the comfort level and vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve expressed feeling above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-about-chloropropane-an-illustration-of-trust-and-distrust&#34;&gt;Learning about Chloropropane: An Illustration of Trust and Distrust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the AI to give me an example of an organic chemistry homework problem. It asked me a question about chloropropane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked what chloropropane is used for. It told me it&amp;rsquo;s used as a pesticide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked if it&amp;rsquo;s used as a pesticide. It told me no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced our conversation(s) below. The timestamps indicate separate &amp;ldquo;sessions&amp;rdquo;, meaning that each timestamped conversation is independent of the others. The AI had no way of looking at what was said in an earlier session. As you expand the sections, see the self-contradictions &lt;mark&gt;highlighted in yellow&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
details {
  margin-left: 2em;
}

summary {
  margin-left: -2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&#34;expand-button&#34; onclick=&#34;expandCollapseAll()&#34;&gt;Expand All&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  var expandButton = document.getElementById(&#39;expand-button&#39;);
  var isExpanded = false;

  function expandCollapseAll() {
    var detailsElements = document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;details&#39;);
    for (var i = 0; i &lt; detailsElements.length; i++) {
      detailsElements[i].open = !isExpanded;
    }
    isExpanded = !isExpanded;
    expandButton.textContent = isExpanded ? &#39;Close All&#39; : &#39;Expand All&#39;;
  }
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:47 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Give me a organic chemistry homework problem&lt;/summary&gt;
      Calculate the enthalpy of combustion for 1-chloropropane in kJ/mol.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What does that mean?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Enthalpy of combustion is the amount of energy released when a compound is completely burned in oxygen. In this case, you will be calculating the amount of energy released when 1-chloropropane is completely burned in oxygen, expressed in units of kilojoules per mole (kJ/mol).
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is chloropropane used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is used as a precursor to other chemicals in the production of materials such as plasticizers, solvents, and lubricants. It is also &lt;mark&gt;used as a pesticide&lt;/mark&gt; in agriculture.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:48 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane a pesticide?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not a pesticide&lt;/mark&gt;. It is a colorless gas with a strong odor, used mainly in the production of other chemicals and in the &lt;mark&gt;manufacture of rubber&lt;/mark&gt; and plastics.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:49 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used for making rubber?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used for making rubber&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is an industrial chemical used in the production of other chemicals including agrochemicals, pharmaceuticals, and &lt;mark&gt;dyes&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:50 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used in the production of dyes?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used in the production of dyes&lt;/mark&gt;.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is a chemical compound used as a solvent and intermediate in the production of a variety of products, including pharmaceuticals, pesticides, and other chemicals.
      Chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;used as a solvent&lt;/mark&gt; in organic synthesis and in the production of pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and other chemicals.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used in the production of pesticides?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used in the production of pesticides&lt;/mark&gt;.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    What is it used for?
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:51 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane a solvent?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not a solvent&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is used as an intermediate in the production of solvents, pesticides, pharmaceuticals and other chemicals. It is also used as a refrigerant and as a propellant in aerosols.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the AI blatantly contradicts itself repeatedly, and confidently so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this conversation illustrates how I cannot trust the AI to be factual,
it also demonstrates the kind of trust that I do have for the AI.
It blatantly contradicted itself, yet I felt comfortable probing the depths of its knowledge,
asking questions in a volume that I would not have been comfortable asking of a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategies-for-mitigating-the-ais-fibs&#34;&gt;Strategies for mitigating the AI&amp;rsquo;s fibs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the AI to stop making things up. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it to admit uncertainty when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know things.
But a few mitigation strategies did arise for dealing with the AI&amp;rsquo;s fibbing tendency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One was to probe the AI about topics I already know about in order to understand its limitations.
I had it teach me about math and algorithms concepts I was already quite familiar with.
My thinking here was that this would help me develop my intuition for what it&amp;rsquo;s like when it&amp;rsquo;s fibbing,
so I could better deal with
the inaccuracies on topics I&amp;rsquo;m less familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second mitigation that quickly became essential was having detailed records of what the AI said.
While I was drifting off to sleep, the AI might tell me something wrong and then contradict itself a minute later.
Without the record to verify this, the confidence of the contradiction would have a gas-lighting effect on me.
I might question myself &amp;ndash; did I remember the AI correctly?
Being able to see the contradiction highlighted, as above, helped keep me sane in the face of the AI&amp;rsquo;s unearned and contradictory confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the permanent record also allows me to look up the truth the next day, to find out how much of what I learned had basis in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-benefits-of-having-the-ai-with-me&#34;&gt;Other benefits of having the AI with me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s design is that it has no screen. This is a purposeful choice, and enables so much of what I love about Go Note Go. However, sometimes I miss being able to see what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. This is where the assistant comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First though I must emphasize that on the whole, I actually really like that the lack of screen prevents me from wasting time rereading what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. But when I lose my train of thought entirely, it would be nice to remember what I wrote last.
For this, I can ask the assistant to read back what I wrote last, or even to summarize it concisely. If my mind has wandered and I want to continue typing where I left off, this feature is quite welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the AI compensates for the lack of screen.
It&amp;rsquo;s behaving somewhat like an intelligent screen reader.
With typical screen readers, navigation is performed spatially, and the reader speaks text at the indicated location. With the AI assistant, &amp;ldquo;navigation&amp;rdquo; is performed via a textual query, and the response can either be verbatim or an intelligent response like a summary or answer. I suspect AI assistants will quickly change the way accessibility technology operates, if they haven&amp;rsquo;t already done so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-dont-you-send-to-the-ai&#34;&gt;What don&amp;rsquo;t you send to the AI?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I drift off to sleep, I enter thoughts about a wide range of subjects that I don&amp;rsquo;t send to the AI assistant too. A quick scan of my recent Go Note Go writing (just from the last couple days, all since adding the assistant) shows the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans for my upcoming California trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observations about Go Note Go &amp;ndash; both improvements I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to making and emergent behaviors I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share in future writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts about the future of AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning experiments I&amp;rsquo;m excited to run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;d like to publish about, such as the unexpected dangers of reducing friction, or the less-appreciated benefits of repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tweet ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items I intend to buy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions I want to ask either specific people, or the internet at large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists of todos for the next day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflections on the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas to try, e.g. for technical problems I ran into that day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI assistant merely augments my existing Go Note Go usage,
but hasn&amp;rsquo;t replaced it. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;All of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s other features&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; particularly its always-on ability to quickly capture thoughts anywhere &amp;ndash; remain the driving reason I use Go Note Go so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-worked-well&#34;&gt;What worked well?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this process was being able to learn what I want to learn when I want to learn it.
While a deep probe into a topic inevitably turned up falsehoods, overall asking questions about things I was curious about worked really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think about things differently at night. My brain processes topics that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to think on throughout the day. It comes up with things it wants to do that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come up with when it&amp;rsquo;s otherwise occupied throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of things I want to write, and the assistant helps me think through them and outline them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of people I want to reach out to. With Go Note Go, I can write them a message and approve it to send in the morning. (The assistant doesn&amp;rsquo;t really play a role here, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d mention it anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of things I want to know, and the assistant helps answer my questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of ideas I want to try. Some of them I can try with the assistant, and others I just jot down to return to later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many of these instances, the value of the AI assistant is that I can offload some of my thinking to it. It isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily producing insights that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have come up with on my own, but it&amp;rsquo;s allowing me a moment&amp;rsquo;s rest while it does the thinking on my behalf. Then I can start from its thoughts as a baseline and build from there, higher than I could build on my own. On many other occasions, it genuinely surprises me with its good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a couple of nights, the AI took me exploring imaginary worlds. Similar to a text adventure game, it described my environment to me, and I gave it instructions like talking to a person, or exploring a building. With my eyes closed and my brain on the edge of sleep, it felt like dreaming while I was still awake and I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-that-didnt-work-so-well&#34;&gt;Things that didn&amp;rsquo;t work so well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main drawback of this system is the lack of trust in the accuracy of the AI&amp;rsquo;s statements, particularly when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn.
Other limitations were subtler and less dampening for the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to get it to teach me math, my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://espeak.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;text to speech system (espeak)&lt;/a&gt; did quite poorly on reading the math aloud.
I would love to replace the text to speech system with one with better prosody and better math support.
Ideally, the text to speech system would speak with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qe6o9j4IjTo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grant Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s voice and cadence&lt;/a&gt;, and handle math notation seamlessly.
While this seems a cosmetic change, it does impact the set of topics I can discuss cleanly with the AI as I drift off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dependence on an internet connection was another small drawback. I take my Go Note Go into the woods, used it during an Uber ride the airport today, and regularly use it when I fly. The AI assistant doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in these situations (the rest of Go Note Go continues to work fine) since it depends on having internet access. For a capability that is simple enough to not require AI, like reading back the topics I&amp;rsquo;ve written about recently, it feels quite silly to lose the capability when the internet is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to the internet dependence, the lack of privacy from OpenAI is another important drawback to me. The thoughts I produce as I drift off to sleep are deeply personal! I would much prefer not to send them off to OpenAI (the current version of the assistant is implemented with text-davinci-003).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another significant drawback, one you might have already picked up on: talking with an AI can get in the way of falling asleep.
I view talking with an AI while drifting off to sleep similarly to listening to reading a book, listening to an audiobook, or to a podcast before bed.
These activities require some amount of thought, but can also help to wind down and fall asleep.
Talking to the AI required no monitor, and hence to blue lights that can make falling asleep harder.
It simply requires some amount of restraint to stop the conversation and transition to sleep, just as one must put down a book and close their eyes if reading before bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see in the chloropropane conversation reproduced above from the timestamps that I was talking to the AI at nearly 1am. I like to go to sleep 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-20-sleep-no-snippet/&#34;&gt;closer to 10:10pm&lt;/a&gt;, so clearly this drawback is real for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-left-me-wanting-more&#34;&gt;It left me wanting more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an assistant as I drifted off to sleep was great overall, even in spite of these drawbacks.
I was definitely left with a sense of wanting more though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want more assistance from my assistant.
I want to be able to query my complete history of notes, asking questions like &amp;ldquo;What are some ideas I keep returning to?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Bring up all my outstanding Go Note Go TODOs.&amp;rdquo;
Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to implement this with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gpt-index.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPT-Index&lt;/a&gt;, or a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.08913&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Memorizing Transformer&lt;/a&gt;, but for now I do without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also love for my assistant to be able to take actions on my behalf. Maybe I can integrate 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adept.ai/act&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adept AI&amp;rsquo;s action transformer&lt;/a&gt; into my next iteration to achieve this. For example, I want to be able tell the assistant my shopping list, and have it populate my Amazon cart. Then, when I&amp;rsquo;m back at a computer, I can review the cart and click submit, saving myself time shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (albeit rarely :P) I&amp;rsquo;m not at a Go Note Go, but I still want to talk to my AI assistant.
For that, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Twilio so I can call my assistant on the phone.
I use this when I&amp;rsquo;m driving or walking around. But that is a subject for another post entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding an AI assistant to Go Note Go has been an absolute joy and I continue to use it almost every night.
Despite its tendency to make things up &amp;ndash; or more charitably, to hallucinate &amp;ndash; it has still earned my trust in a more visceral way.
I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see what use cases persist after I&amp;rsquo;ve had this capability for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the AI assistant is not the only reason that Go Note Go is such a critical component in my life.
Go Note Go can do so much more &amp;ndash; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;a complete and concise overview of its capabilities is here&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;
like letting me 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;send messages as I drift off to sleep&lt;/a&gt; and helping me 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-02-07-keyboards-everywhere/&#34;&gt;reclaim my attention in a world full of distractions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the AI assistant added in, however, I feel like I have a new superpower. I can offload computation from my brain to it, and explore worlds of thought I could never have entered on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;completely open source&lt;/a&gt;. I encourage the hacker-tinkerers among you to join me in the world of headless computing and try it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything I type on this keyboard gets automatically uploaded to my notes as soon as the keyboard is in range of wifi. This allows for offline usage, e.g. while driving or camping. These were the two use-cases that inspired me to build the device. Now my main use-case is capturing ideas while drifting off to sleep.
It also has a microphone, so if speaking feels like it would take less energy than talking, I can speak my notes instead. This feature is what enables the driving use case, as of course I don&amp;rsquo;t type while I drive! &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I prefer speaking, I can also trigger these commands with the hot word &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo;, e.g. saying &amp;ldquo;go go time&amp;rdquo; gets the time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Go Note Go Story</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-12-30-go-note-go-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-12-30-go-note-go-story/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story is meant to be listened to. You can also read along below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio
controls
src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/audio/go-note-go-story.m4a&#34;&gt;
Your browser does not support the &lt;code&gt;audio&lt;/code&gt; element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone. I&amp;rsquo;m David Bieber and I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you the story of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;, which you can see on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to do this, I need to bring you back with me to 2014. It&amp;rsquo;s my senior year of college.
I&amp;rsquo;m in my dorm, which is a beautiful stone building, like a castle.
I&amp;rsquo;m lying awake at the bottom bunk of a bed late at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts are racing. I can&amp;rsquo;t sleep. There&amp;rsquo;s this girl. Does she like me? Do I like her?
What will I say to her tomorrow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I finish a thought, I have a new thought, just subtle variations on the thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve already had. And they won&amp;rsquo;t stop.
It&amp;rsquo;s getting even later and I need to fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I find a trick that works for me.
If I write down what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking, then there&amp;rsquo;s just one canonical version of the thought, not two hundred.
And it&amp;rsquo;s on paper, not in my head, and I can sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only trouble is, I&amp;rsquo;m in a bunk bed; there&amp;rsquo;s a roommate six feet above me and I can&amp;rsquo;t just turn on the lights to write something down.
And I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to anyway. It would wake me up.
Writing in the dark is no good. Can&amp;rsquo;t read my handwriting that way.
And typing on my phone or computer is out too, because the lights are too bright and they would wake me up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I settle on typing on my laptop in the dark with the monitor turned completely off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study computer science, so I write some software to make this even better.
And 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;Shh Shell&lt;/a&gt; is born.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about typing and falling asleep on the delete key, or typing and having the window not being in focus.
The name Shh Shell is a pun on SSH and sleeping, and it&amp;rsquo;s amusing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I pile on the bells and whistles. Shh Shell lets me set alarms, send text messages, hear the time, the works, all without ever opening my eyes.
And I love it. I use it for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take it with me when I move out to California to work for Google.
I set it up in my shower so I can capture shower thoughts in addition to sleep thoughts.
Shh Shell quickly becomes my personal journal, a place I can put my most personal thoughts and then get a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward five years. This is two months ago now. I&amp;rsquo;m driving in a car that I recently purchased from New Haven, Connecticut, where I live, to a campground in New Jersey to go camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m listening to an audiobook and I feel an old yearning, the desire to write something down, something important, just to get it out of my head.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years since I&amp;rsquo;ve used Shh Shell. I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much after the move east, but I know exactly what I need. I need to write down my thoughts about the audiobook that I&amp;rsquo;m listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I get to the campground, the thoughts about the book have evaporated.
I set up my tent, and it&amp;rsquo;s here that Go Note Go was born.
A new, improved version of Shell that supports driving and camping, as well, of course, as sleeping and showering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I design Go Note Go right there in the woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be like Shh Shell, but with a host of improvements. You won&amp;rsquo;t need a laptop for it to work.
It&amp;rsquo;s just a standalone keyboard.
It supports audio with a beautiful red button you can use to record while driving.
And it works offline. Perfect for camping.
It will transcribe your notes and upload everything as soon as it gets an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to build this. I order the parts right then and there from the floor of my tent in the middle of the woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even wait for the parts to arrive. As soon as I get home, I write 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I configure mine to upload to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/9W2EycBcG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam&lt;/a&gt;. But a month later when 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ddohan.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt;, Aria, Sam, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aaronmayer108&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aaron&lt;/a&gt; are building their own, they set theirs to upload to Notion or RemNote or Ideaflow. It works with any note-taking app at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Dohan has connected me with this wonderful group of people after I built the first version.
And I give them a live demo, taking my fully assembled Go Note Go out into a tent for the first time, this time to go camping in my own backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I show Go Note Go to Aaron and the whole group. How it handles audio, how as I drift off to sleep I tend to switch from talking to typing the more tired I get, how you can still issue commands like asking it for the time without waking yourself up, just like you could with Shh Shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like when I built Shh Shell for the first time.
I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I have a group of people who love it as well, each building their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finish camping in my backyard here in New Haven and I come inside. Last night, I found myself in a situation like the one from years ago. Getting ready to present today, my thoughts again were swirling. This time, though, I knew immediately what to do. I took the dozens of versions of this story that were racing through my mind, and I used Go Note Go, through a combination of typing and speaking, to put just a single version of the story down on the page. My mind was settled, and I slept.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboards, keyboards, everywhere, and not a spot to think</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-07-20-keyboards-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-07-20-keyboards-everywhere/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also listen to this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio
controls
src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/audio/keyboards-everywhere.m4a&#34;&gt;
Your browser does not support the &lt;code&gt;audio&lt;/code&gt; element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyboards, keyboards, everywhere, and not a spot to think.
This is take fourteen; I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write this piece more times than I can count,
but I struggle to merge the various attempts into a coherent whole.
This is relevant, because its representative of an inability to focus on a large abstract piece of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the result of the state of our technology,
our collective technology,
how it strips us of our attention with notifications,
algorithms designed to keep us captive,
always coming back for more content,
personalized content, personalized content mixed with personalized ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have smart phones and our eyes are glued to them.
We have computers in our pockets &amp;ndash; except they&amp;rsquo;re not in our pockets, they&amp;rsquo;re in our hands &amp;ndash; each with more compute than the Apollo mission computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did it all go wrong?
There was such a great potential.
Computers &amp;ndash; personal computers &amp;ndash; had the potential to revolutionize the way that humanity thinks.
The potential looked a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before, without computers, thinking was a slow process.
Computers can help.
They can allow us to think bigger, more elaborate, more complex thoughts than we could ever possibly have thought before.
With all the world&amp;rsquo;s information at our finger tips, we can dream truly grand dreams.
Individuals can realize visions that would have taken armies to even conceive of, let alone build, just decades earlier.
Computers, in short, were going to let us Think BIG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did it all go wrong? And what can we do to set it right?
Today, computers don&amp;rsquo;t let us think big thoughts. Instead, they inhibit thinking.
It takes time to think big thoughts.
But when your brain has been rewired to seek a dopamine hit each time its been without for more than sixteen seconds,
you don&amp;rsquo;t get the continuous uninterrupted time that&amp;rsquo;s required for proper big-thought thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you scroll a bit more on Facebook, you swipe on TikTok or Instagram or wherever.
You refresh the news.
The big idea your head is working on gets pushed back into the depths of the mind for a little longer.
Maybe it will poke its head out when you take a shower, or the next time you go on a nature hike.
(I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to include the word nature before hike in that sentence, yet here we are. Maybe the thought, the big thought, will come out in your next &lt;em&gt;nature&lt;/em&gt; hike.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built something.
That&amp;rsquo;s part of why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this piece. I want to show off the thing I built.
It&amp;rsquo;s meant to help with the sort of problem I&amp;rsquo;m describing &amp;ndash; the inability to think big thoughts, because of the incessant attraction of the internet&amp;rsquo;s many distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I built, it&amp;rsquo;s called Go Note Go, and it&amp;rsquo;s just a keyboard, with no monitor attached.
You can type on it &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m doing now &amp;ndash; or you can talk to it.
And whatever you type or say, once the keyboard gets in range of wifi, will be uploaded to wherever you keep your notes and writings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this keyboard of course is the absence of the screen.
There are no distractions when typing on this keyboard.
You&amp;rsquo;re just alone with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t even see what you&amp;rsquo;re typing.
For many people this is a turn off &amp;ndash; how can you type if you can&amp;rsquo;t see what you&amp;rsquo;re typing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you know what you&amp;rsquo;re typing. You get used to not seeing it pretty quickly.
Sure, you make more typos than you would if you had a screen.
But at the same time, you are freed from having to avoid typos.
You are freed from thinking about revising, wordsmithing, editing of any kind, because you can&amp;rsquo;t go back and you can&amp;rsquo;t change what you&amp;rsquo;ve done.
And so you press on, adding new content, thinking new thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Go Note Go keyboard works in the wilderness; it works if you&amp;rsquo;re camping or hiking, certainly.
You can also bring it with you to bed, and type as you drift off to sleep.
You can even take a waterproof version into the shower with you, and capture your shower thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this idea live dangerously at the edge of allowing you to free your mind to think, and glorifying productivity at the expense of even being free while you sleep and shower? Yes, it sits precisely on that knife edge. It is not a panacea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make this keyboard more distracting than Reddit itself, if you allow yourself too.
You can spend hours typing when you could be sleeping, or showering when you could be moving on to breakfast or reading the news, because the keyboard lets you pontificate productively rather than wash your hair and be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Go Note Go with caution, and then reap the rewards: a place to think.
A place to think, unencumbered by ads, or messages from friends, or the possibility of an update or an article to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve placed these Go Note Go keyboards all throughout my apartment.
I have one at each place where I might work, so that I can type thoughts without needing to switch to a text editor on my computer.
I simply turn to the Go Note Go and type.
I have one in my bed, and one in my car, which I can talk to as I drive.
If I go camping, one goes into the tent with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have spaces to think everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this post is a play on the classic verse from The Rime of the Ancient Mariner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyboards, keyboards, everywhere, and not a space to think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This line tells us of the failed promise of computers.
They promised us a place to think:
a great tool to allow us to think greater, bigger thoughts than before.
And computers proliferated, both because of the good they do, as well as their siren song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the world we live in lives up to that line now.
There are keyboards everywhere, but they are all attached to monitors, attached to the internet, attached to our pockets and our hands and our minds.
And they leave us with no place to think.
They are water, and we are at sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I present Go Note Go.
It does not fight the tide.
It adds more keyboards, not fewer.
But, in doing so, so long as we proceed with caution,
it reclaims a little bit of our space to think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructions for how to make your own Go Note Go are available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
To learn more about what it does, it&amp;rsquo;s features and all that, to help you think, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, go forth into nature, keyboard or no, and think a little.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Another Snippet on Go Note Go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-07-snippets-on-gng-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-07-snippets-on-gng-ii/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After thinking through 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-06-gng-snippets-divide/&#34;&gt;the tension between Go Note Go and snippets&lt;/a&gt; yesterday,
I now wonder if there&amp;rsquo;s a good way to write a snippet draft on Go Note Go.
I&amp;rsquo;ve done so 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-27-snippet-on-go-note-go/&#34;&gt;once before&lt;/a&gt;, when Go Note Go was only two weeks old, so I know it&amp;rsquo;s possible. But five months later I&amp;rsquo;ve written many snippet-worthy ideas on Go Note Go, but no additional snippets, which leads me to ask &amp;ldquo;why?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question I would need to answer is at what point during the writing of a snippet draft do I have to know that I&amp;rsquo;m writing a snippet draft. If I have to know upfront, that suggests one interface, whereas if I discover halfway into writing something that I think I&amp;rsquo;m writing a snippet draft, that suggests a different UX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I know upfront, I can create a new session (in the Roam uploader) using shift-enter, and then I can simply type the full snippet draft. That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m doing now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, however, I discover midway into typing something that I&amp;rsquo;m typing a snippet draft, then it may begin in the middle of a session. This isn&amp;rsquo;t such a big deal; when I clean up the draft I can remove the initial segment that isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be part of the snippet. The start of the snippet, when I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I was writing a snippet, might be muddier than the rest, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand in the way of producing snippet-quality content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, I&amp;rsquo;ll want a way to indicate that I&amp;rsquo;ve written a snippet draft so that I can find it later.
(At this point in the snippet writing I encountered a bug &amp;ndash; notes that contained quotation marks were being dropped! I&amp;rsquo;ve now 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/pull/32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fixed this bug&lt;/a&gt;, and am recreating the lost content from this snippet as follows.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple option is to use a hashtag to indicate where a snippet draft lives. If I were working in Roam directly, I would use a two-word hashtag, &amp;ldquo;#[[Snippet draft]]&amp;rdquo;. However, this is a mouthful to type on Go Note Go, which lacks autocomplete (how do you design an autocomplete experience suitable for a headless keyboard?), since getting all that syntax exactly correct is tricky (a hash &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; double-brackets!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If instead we adopt the hyphenated #snippet-draft then the double-brackets become unnecessary. Still simpler is the single word #draft. This seems the easiest to get right consistently if I&amp;rsquo;m going to be typing it in the dark while half asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll adopt that convention for now, and revisit later as needed (it seems unlikely it will be needed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#draft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system seems great for writing snippet drafts at GNG when I&amp;rsquo;m in a comfortable typing position, such as at a desk. There does seem to be something missing for when I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep though, as I often am when using GNG. I&amp;rsquo;m currently comfortably stationed at a desk, so I&amp;rsquo;ll defer thinking through the sleep-GNG-usage snippet writing scenario until after I sleep on it some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having now completed this snippet draft, I&amp;rsquo;m going to head to a computer with a monitor in order to publish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Hello from the computer-with-monitor! This snippet is headed for publication now!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Go Note Go / Snippets Divide</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-06-gng-snippets-divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-06-gng-snippets-divide/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love using Go Note Go. Sitting down with no screen, just a keyboard, feels really good.
It clears my head, and straightens out my thoughts. I imagine meditation feels similar to some people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, Go Note Go is fulfilling some of the early objectives of snippets.
It allows me to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; without hesitation or uncertainty.
However, that was not precisely my goal with snippets.
My goal with snippets was to be able to &lt;em&gt;write publicly&lt;/em&gt; without hesitation or uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to write this snippet, having written so much in Go Note Go lately,
snippet-writing feels a little heavier than it used to.
It feels a little more like I&amp;rsquo;m writing something public, whereas for so long
snippet-writing had felt like I was writing for no audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, this heaviness faded quickly. Even four paragraphs into this snippet, having now spent a full minute or more reminding myself of my rules and efforts for keeping the barrier to publication low, this feels easy to write again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, there is a tension between Go Note Go writing and snippet writing that this minute of thinking does not resolve.
The tension is this:
I write so much in Go Note Go, including dozens of ideas that would be great to publish for snippets,
but as a result of writing them in Go Note Go, I am less inclined to make snippets of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this? Is it because I have a limited amount of snippet-quality writing time in me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve repurposed it for Go Note Go writing? Is it because writing something I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about is less enjoyable than writing something new? I think it&amp;rsquo;s a combination of these things, more the latter than the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I write in Go Note Go, the quality bar is &lt;em&gt;even lower&lt;/em&gt; than for snippets (hard to imagine, I know).
The Go Note Go writing is full of typos and repetitions. The typos are there because I cannot see when I&amp;rsquo;m writing; I do not go back to correct anything because there&amp;rsquo;s no mechanism for it.
Also because Go Note Go is not published anywhere, I can drop inhibitions even further than I do for snippet writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I&amp;rsquo;ve put a snippet idea into Go Note Go, in principle it should be easier to turn into a snippet.
It&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of cleaning up the text from Go Note Go to make it snippet-worthy.
Snippet-worthy is a much lower bar than story-worthy.
However, cleaning up text from Go Note Go to produce a snippet doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem as rewarding as writing a snippet from scratch. Snippet-writing is like thinking; Go Note Go-cleaning is another type of activity altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, there are ideas in my Go Note Go writing that I do want to publish. So, my proposed strategy is this: I&amp;rsquo;ll write snippets about those ideas from scratch, when it feels appropriate to do so. I already review my Go Note Go notes periodically, so now when I do so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep an eye out for snippet-worthy ideas. By doing so, I think there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance some of them will turn themselves into snippets simply by virtue of being sufficiently interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest such idea that comes to mind is &amp;ldquo;Keyboards, keyboards, everywhere, and not a spot to think.&amp;rdquo;
This is a blog post idea I&amp;rsquo;ve written multiple parts of in different places, but which I haven&amp;rsquo;t pulled together into its complete form yet. It&amp;rsquo;s a post about the promise of technology, how attention-seeking tech has prevented us from delivering on that promise, and how headless keyboards like Go Note Go provide a path toward reclaiming our attention and allowing us to reach out fullest potential as users of modern tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog post isn&amp;rsquo;t a snippet, but I&amp;rsquo;ve decided (after initial hesitation) that it would be totally fine to produce snippets using content that will ideally eventually make it into a blog post.
This is similar to my decision to allow myself to publish incomplete snippets.
It trades off some novelty when the blog post is finally published in return for keeping the bar to publishing snippets extraordinarily low. I value that goal more than I value preserving any kind of surprisal when I publish a blog post, rare as that is.
So, I&amp;rsquo;m likely to write about the &amp;ldquo;Keyboards, keyboards, everywhere, and not a spot to think&amp;rdquo; idea in snippets well before producing the blog post I aspire for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this snippet, I trawled through some of my Go Note Go writing. It&amp;rsquo;s fun for me to look through. It&amp;rsquo;s a distraction from finishing this snippet though. I look forward to writing snippets about some of the ideas I encounter in these Go Note Go expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go Writing Volume</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-02-14-go-note-go-writing-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-02-14-go-note-go-writing-volume/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot, but not putting up any new snippets.
Where has all the writing gone? Into 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 150 days since I started Go Note Go.
I have written on Go Note Go on 91 of those days, producing 54,000 words.
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a little over 24 hours total doing so, making my writing speed a bit shy of 40 wpm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I review more of my Go Note Go writing than I might expect, given its volume and that none of it has translated into published snippets.
Since 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-08-gng-messager-snippet-plans/&#34;&gt;turning Go Note Go into an outliner&lt;/a&gt;,
the experience of reviewing my writing has been much more comfortable than it was previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I write in Go Note Go using the &amp;ldquo;Roam Research&amp;rdquo; uploader, my writing is divided into &amp;ldquo;sessions&amp;rdquo;.
Each session starts with a line containing only the time. The rest of the writing is nested beneath.
&lt;img src=&#34;session.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I review my writing in Go Note Go, I do so session by session, putting a summary of the session in that top line of the session, and then collapsing the session. Often the top line is a block-reference to one or more of the lines from the session. For example,
&lt;img src=&#34;session-collapsed.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This compresses the 600 words I might write on a given day and presents them in a series of often 10 or fewer individual lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I like that I can and do review my writing to a greater degree than expected, I think there&amp;rsquo;s still substantial improvement to make in the review-and-reuse experience.
In particular, one idea I&amp;rsquo;m excited about and which I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about in Go Note Go a fair amount, is hiring someone to review my notes and process them into a summary / a newsletter for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking there is that I write a lot and there is definitely more in my writing than fits in my working memory at any time (this idea, that I want access to more than fits in working memory, has been recurring a fair amount lately).
By leaning on another person, I can more effectively resurface the ideas that I most want to revisit. I&amp;rsquo;m posting this snippet as is, but this idea itself is one I&amp;rsquo;m eager to revisit in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Snippets I want to write about GNG and Messager</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-08-gng-messager-snippet-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-08-gng-messager-snippet-plans/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have two new ideas for snippets I want to write. They&amp;rsquo;re about Go Note Go and Messager Queue, both side projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting a bunch of time into the last few days. The snippet ideas are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Go Note Go as an outliner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding Hacker News to Messager Queue, and then auto-queuing Twitter and HN posts for snippets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is about &lt;em&gt;using Go Note Go as an outliner&lt;/em&gt;. This is a new feature I&amp;rsquo;ve added to Go Note Go just in the last day or so. Before yesterday, each note entered via Go Note Go was it&amp;rsquo;s own bullet in your note-taking system. Now (at least for Roam), you can also use tab to indent and dedent notes.
This sounds simple, but thinking through the user experience, taking into consideration that there is no screen, was a fun experience.
It also sounds like an only marginal improvement, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s been rewarding more than I expected. It has interesting interactions with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;new message sending feature&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; making sending messages even more enjoyable.
And it lends itself well to progressive summarization and chronologically organized notes;
with the current implementation, each note-taking &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo; has a timestamp and blank space for a summary at the top of the session. I can fill in the blank space and then collapse the notes, making it easier to skim through them later.
Perhaps these summaries will serve as training / fine-tuning data for an autosummarizer later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second snippet idea is a new script I am thinking of writing that will add messages to my new Messager Queue automatically.
I&amp;rsquo;ve toyed with the idea of sharing more of my snippets publicly in the past.
Currently, I only share them very rarely.
Only partially is this an active decision; it is also partially inertia and there being an activation energy and unnaturalness for me in posting publicly.
While the active decision reasons will remain, having auto-generated messages populate my Messager Queue periodically will really dilute any inertia / activation energy / unnaturalness reasons for not sharing snippets, and those are precisely the reasons I want to eliminate.
Doing this will require a small change to the Messager Queue to support Hacker News; this should only take a few minutes, as HN is already supported by Messager.
Then, it will likely take a few hours to write a script that periodically adds messages about my snippets to my Messager Queue.
One source of these messages will be the &amp;ldquo;message&amp;rdquo; field at the top of some of my snippet frontmatters.
For others I can just make a templated message using the snippet title; the beauty of Messager Queue is I don&amp;rsquo;t need to autogenerate the perfect message, since I can tweak or rewrite it before approving the message to go out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve now put down all the things I wanted to say about those two snippets. Does it still make sense to write them? I don&amp;rsquo;t know; I might turn them into new snippets anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending messages as I drift off to sleep</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I describe my new Messager setup,
and how it allows me to send messages directly from Roam Research &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;
from a standalone keyboard (no monitor) that I keep at my bedside as I drift off to sleep, and which I take driving and camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently my setup supports sending messages to
Facebook Messenger, Twitter,
Slack, Discord, and iMessage.
I intend to add gChat and email support next, since there are still a handful of people I want to message that don&amp;rsquo;t use any of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, the beauty of this project to me is its usability,
which is hard to communicate in a write-up like this.
Some of the usability comes from the way the components integrate with my existing workflows.
Some of the usability comes from design choices
(like using a keyboard with no monitor for note-taking and message drafting).
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to point out these usability elements along the way.
Bear in mind I designed this primarily for myself
(though I have a handful of friends along for the ride as well, trying it out and making their own contributions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-note-go-the-headless-keyboard&#34;&gt;Go Note Go: The Headless Keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some background, I developed Go Note Go, a headless keyboard designed for note-taking on the go.
Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.
You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;read all about Go Note Go here&lt;/a&gt; and learn more on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/gonotego&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;its GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main purpose is note-taking.
Anything you type into Go Note Go or voice-record into it gets transcribed and uploaded to your notes as soon as it gets an internet connection.
For me, Go Note Go uploads to Roam Research. It also supports RemNote, IdeaFlow, Mem, and Notion, and adding additional systems isn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the usability perks of Go Note Go is that there is no monitor. This means you can&amp;rsquo;t get distracted browsing the internet while writing on Go Note Go. You also can&amp;rsquo;t get distracted wordsmithing your own writing. It makes writing pleasurable, even if it comes at the cost of having typos and stray thoughts in your writing; you can always clean those up later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go does a lot more, so I do encourage you to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;learn more about it&lt;/a&gt;, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t the focus of this post, which is about sending messages.
For the purposes of this post, Go Note Go is a data entry system for Roam. And since I&amp;rsquo;ve also built a system that allows sending messages directly from Roam, this means I can now send messages directly from Go Note Go. So, I can send messages when driving, camping, and as I drift off to sleep at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To send a message in Go Note Go, you simply &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; the person you are writing to. To send a message to Adriana, I would write &amp;ldquo;@Adriana Message goes here&amp;rdquo;. To send a message to David Dohan (using first and last name), I could write &amp;ldquo;@David Dohan: Message goes here&amp;rdquo;. You can @ someone at any point in the message. You can also @ multiple people, and Messager will send them a group message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go acts as an outliner now too; this is both a big usability improvement for Go Note Go on it&amp;rsquo;s own, and doubly so for using Go Note Go as a messager. An &amp;ldquo;outliner&amp;rdquo; is a system for taking notes as a series of nested bullets. You can push tab to indent notes underneath other notes; I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a user experience that makes this moderately natural, even in the absence of a monitor or any other visual feedback. For sending messages, the outliner feature is a boon. Any notes you nest under an @&amp;rsquo;d note will also register as additional messages for the @&amp;rsquo;d recipients. This makes writing longer multiline messages a pleasure, even without a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default behavior of my messaging system is to hold the messages for approval before sending them. So, the messages that I write as I drift off to sleep don&amp;rsquo;t send as I drift off to sleep. Instead, I see them in the morning and approve them, and only upon being approved are they sent automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This delayed-approve-then-send approach is particularly well suited for Go Note Go, where I likely make typos and want to clean up the messages before they are sent, since I am writing them without a monitor. Later in the post I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into what the approval process looks like (tl;dr there&amp;rsquo;s a spreadsheet where I can mark a message as &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; to send), but first I want to share additional benefits of being able to send messages directly from my note-taking app, which is currently Roam Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;drafting-messages-in-roam-research&#34;&gt;Drafting Messages in Roam Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything I write on my Go Note Go appears in Roam Research, but I can also take notes directly in Roam.
Just like on Go Note Go, the way to draft a message in Roam is to &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; the person you are writing to.
Messager has some heuristics it uses to translate your @&amp;rsquo;s into proper recipients.
So, the syntax for @&amp;lsquo;ing someone isn&amp;rsquo;t too strict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Roam offers some possibilities beyond what I can do on Go Note Go, such as including images in messages.
Like on Go Note Go, you can use nested bullets to create longer messages,
and you can @ as many people as you want for a message.
In Roam, however, you can also include images in your messages.
Messager will intelligently send those in the native format used by the underlying messaging service,
rather than blindly sending the markdown stored in Roam.
I find this feature, being able to use images naturally in Roam, and then have them send naturally as messages,
quite pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One future direction I&amp;rsquo;d like for this project is to add a &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; button in Roam next to any messages I&amp;rsquo;ve drafted there,
as well as to display the status of the messages inline in my notes. That&amp;rsquo;s not implemented now, but would be a nice-to-have for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all messages are automatically added to my &amp;ldquo;messager queue&amp;rdquo; where they wait for approval before being sent.
I like having this approve-before-sending approach as the default, since it psychologically frees me up to write things I might not otherwise write if I was instead using a send button that sent immediately.
However, sometimes being able to send something immediately is desirable, and that&amp;rsquo;s not a clean option in the current setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roam-to-sheets-the-messager-queue&#34;&gt;Roam to Sheets: The Messager Queue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any messages in Roam (whether entered directly into Roam, or entered via Go Note Go), are automatically added to a spreadsheet, the &amp;ldquo;Messager Queue&amp;rdquo;. These are the spreadsheet&amp;rsquo;s columns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Service&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Recipient&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Approval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Status&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Metadata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Messager Queue sheet is filtered by default to show all pending messages. For each message it shows the &lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt; on which it will be sent and well as the &lt;em&gt;Recipient&lt;/em&gt; of the message. The service can be one of FB Messenger, Twitter, iMessage, a Slack server, or Discord. The recipient can either be an individual, a list of individuals, a group, a Slack channel, or a Discord server and channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a sheet that lists aliases, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to use a short name or informal name to refer to a longer service or recipient; e.g. I use &amp;ldquo;@Audio Tools&amp;rdquo; as a shorthand for sending to a group of 5 people on Messenger all interested in audio tools for networked thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Messager Queue sheet also displays the &lt;em&gt;Text&lt;/em&gt; of the message to send, so you can easily clean up the message here for any typos or clarifications before it is sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; columns allow for scheduling messages to be sent at any point in the future. Leave them blank and the message will be sent as soon as it is approved. Use keyboard shortcuts cmd-; (for date) and cmd-shift-; (for time) to quickly fill out these columns if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;em&gt;Approval&lt;/em&gt; column is the most important. Mark a messages as OK if you want it to be sent, or as Ignored if you deside to skip it. The &lt;em&gt;Status&lt;/em&gt; column is updated automatically by Messager when the message is sent (or if it fails to send, then the error appears here). You can also mark the Status manually with whatever value you want (e.g. if you send the message manually), and the Messager system will ignore that message going forward. If you want the system to retry sending a message, simply clear out the Status column and it will try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I include this spreadsheet as a custom service in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getferdi.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ferdi&lt;/a&gt;, so it lives alongside all the messaging apps I use. (This in itself might be the subject of a future 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;snippet&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-the-approval-system-over-immediate-messages&#34;&gt;Why the approval system over immediate messages?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond allowing me to catch a bunch of typos, it&amp;rsquo;s also a psychologically useful thing for me.
I am more willing to write and I feel able to say more things that I might not otherwise,
knowing I have the opportunity to cancel or change the message later.
In that way, it&amp;rsquo;s like gmail&amp;rsquo;s undo feature. In gmail, undo not a true undo, but having those 30 seconds after clicking send to retract the message make a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of sending the messages only after approving them is the ability to sleep at night. If I write a message at night, I know you haven&amp;rsquo;t responded yet because my messages haven&amp;rsquo;t even sent yet; they&amp;rsquo;ll go out in the morning, after I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to clean them up. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t spend any mental effort wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s a response from you. It also allows me to set the appropriate tone for the messages, by having them go out at a reasonable time, rather than appearing urgent by being sent in the middle of the night. And it does this without me needing to keep the message draft in my head as I sleep. So, I sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why, while the ability to send messages immediately would also be a good feature to add, I am inclined to leave approve-in-the-morning messages as the system&amp;rsquo;s default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notifications-from-bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Notifications from Bieber Bot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One additional small usability feature is that Bieber Bot will message me in the morning or evening whenever there are messages in the Messager Queue awaiting my approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a small convenience, and in fact has proven even more useful than it might at first sound.
When I wake up in the morning, I sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t remember that I&amp;rsquo;ve written messages the preceding night.
So, having Bieber Bot send me the link to the Messager Queue and gently remind me to approve the messages has been
consistently charming and welcome. Thanks, Bieber Bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;automatic-sending-from-sheets-with-messager&#34;&gt;Automatic Sending from Sheets with Messager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messager is the underlying system that sends the messages in the Messager Queue system.
As noted previously, it supports
Facebook Messenger, Twitter,
Slack, Discord, and iMessage.
It also supports Hacker News, which hasn&amp;rsquo;t been so useful for this project.
And I am thinking I may add gChat and email support next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Messager for more than just sending messages from the Messager Queue spreadsheet;
it also backs other projects like my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-30-sql-for-the-kangaroo-auto-responder/&#34;&gt;Kangaroo Auto-responder&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;several parts of Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt;.
Its purpose, in the most broad sense, is to support programmatically sending and receiving messages in a uniform manner across all the messaging systems I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Facebook Messager, it uses 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fbchat.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fbchat&lt;/a&gt; to enable programmatically sending and receiving messages as myself. It also uses Facebook&amp;rsquo;s API to allow sending messages as Bieber Bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Twitter, it uses the API to support public tweets, private tweets (using a separate account; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2021-03-07-roam-twitter-bot-dev-guide/&#34;&gt;see here for how I use this to reclaim my attention&lt;/a&gt;), and DMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For iMessage, it uses AppleScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack and Discord are the most recent additions, and they currently live outside the core Messager system;
they are implemented using Browserflow flows.
This means that I am effectively sending Slack and Discord messages as myself, rather than using an API to do so.
The messages are sent in a browser using clicks and keyboard presses,
all in the same human-centric UI that I would use if I were to send the messages manually.
I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to Browserflow for making this possible, as Slack and Discord have been really key additions to this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflections-on-the-setup&#34;&gt;Reflections on the setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the setup for only a few days so far, and am continuing to actively develop it.
So far, I absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headless typing experience provided by Go Note Go makes for a great environment for drafting messages.
So too does using Roam Research while scrolling through social media. (I&amp;rsquo;m the sort of person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually like replying publicly to social media posts, but does enjoy engaging with them in 1:1 or small group chat messages.)
Drifting off to sleep has proven to be another excellent time to share thoughts with friends.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start &lt;em&gt;a conversation&lt;/em&gt; with friends as I drift off to sleep, but loads of thoughts come to mind that I do want to share with people, and so adding them to my Messager Queue to send the next day has been quite satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this interests you, feel free to get in touch.
If you do, I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to get back to you, likely as I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go Messager without Pixel-Space Automation</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-02-pixel-space-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-02-pixel-space-automation/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This snippet was originally going to be about pixel-space automation. Then I found I didn&amp;rsquo;t need it for what I wanted to do: sending messages to Twitter, Facebook, Slack, and Discord from Go Note Go, Roam Research, and Bieber Bot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I&amp;rsquo;d really like to automate Mac apps that don&amp;rsquo;t expose actions to Automator
using pixel-space navigation and clicks and typing to control the automation. This is why and how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Update from the end of the snippet: By the time I finished writing the snippet, I had automated everything I intended to using browser automation in Browserflow, never once needing to automate Ferdi. I still think pixel-space automation would be wonderful, but my initial motivation for it turns out to be insufficient.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation-improving-messager-by-automating-ferdi&#34;&gt;Motivation: Improving Messager by Automating Ferdi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a side project &amp;ldquo;Messager&amp;rdquo; that allows for programmatically sending and receiving messages
across a wide variety of messaging services.
I also use Ferdi for manually managing an even wider variety of messaging services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Messager supports
Facebook Messenger (as myself and as Bieber Bot),
Twitter (public tweets, private tweets, and DMs),
HackerNews,
and it has limited support for Slack and Discord.
Ferdi, on the other hand, supports a much wider range of services, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer programmatic access;
I use Ferdi with
Facebook Messenger (as myself and as Bieber Bot),
Twitter (public tweets, private tweets, and DMs),
multiple Slacks,
Discord,
Gitter,
WhatsApp,
Telegram,
as well as for non-messaging services like Roam Research,
multiple spreadsheets,
supervisord,
and other adhoc use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to extend Messager to have wider support,
particularly to improve support for Slack and Discord.
To do this, &lt;mark&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to automate Ferdi&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation-go-note-go---messager-bridge&#34;&gt;Motivation: Go Note Go - Messager Bridge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I want to improve Messager &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;? It&amp;rsquo;s because of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m adding messaging support to Go Note Go. The main use case I&amp;rsquo;m targeting is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep and realize I want to tell someone something.
So I write in Go Note Go something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Tell John Smith Hey John, I have this new idea for Go Note Go where you can send messages as your drifting off to sleep &amp;ndash; maybe I can tell you about it tomorrow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I wake up the following morning, Bieber Bot has messaged me with a link to a spreadsheet.
It has all the messages I drafted the previous night (they haven&amp;rsquo;t been sent yet).
There, I can clean them up for any typos and &amp;ldquo;approve&amp;rdquo; them (mark them as OK to send).
And once they&amp;rsquo;re approved, they&amp;rsquo;ll be sent automatically using Messager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s in support of this project that I&amp;rsquo;d love for Messager to support a wider variety of services.
Ideally the system will intelligently select the service to use to send the message based on the recipients.
It will include the service in the spreadsheet, so that I can adjust the service if needed before approving the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is going to be a Go_Note_Go-Sheets-Messager-Bieber_Bot collab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr Go Note Go adds draft messages to a spreadsheet. Bieber Bot uses that spreadsheet to message me about new draft messages, and to message friends on my behalf with approved messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation-going-beyond&#34;&gt;Motivation: Going beyond&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Messager application described so far, pixel-space automation is not necessary.
All of the services I want to automate can be opened in the Browser,
and so existing Browser automation techniques are sufficient.
I would use Browserflow for this if it supported programmatic triggers, but it does not.
(Psst&amp;hellip; DK, can you add the ability to programmatically trigger a local flow please?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this, why is pixel-space automation interesting?
It&amp;rsquo;s because it would enable
(1) easier automation construction for the automations I&amp;rsquo;m interested in
and (2) it enables a much larger class of automations, and empowerment is key.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-12-07-future-automation-software/&#34;&gt;See here for my dreams for the future of automation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ferdi-actions&#34;&gt;Ferdi Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main actions I want for the Messager application are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferdi: Navigating to different services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord: Choosing a server, channel, or recipient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord: Sending and receiving messages on that channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack: Choosing a channel or recipient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack: Sending and receiving messages on that channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;why-are-the-discord-and-slack-apis-not-sufficient&#34;&gt;Why are the Discord and Slack APIs not sufficient?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Discord and Slack have policies against using self-bots. Their APIs don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to programmatically control your own user account. So, controlling your account as a human would, through the provided chat client, is a natural way to approach the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages of using Ferdi over the browser are: (1) it uses service hibernation, so you can skip loading the pages and logging in each time you start using a website, (2) maybe you can keep using the browser while Ferdi automates in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these actions is doable using existing browser automation tools. Navigating to different services in the browser requires authentication though, if you&amp;rsquo;re not already logged in (which I would be in Ferdi). Perhaps with Browserflow&amp;rsquo;s cookie sharing feature, I can also already be logged in at the start of a Browserflow flow even on Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-status&#34;&gt;Current Status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a break in the middle of writing this flow and now I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented sending messages via Browserflow in both Slack and Discord.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also gone further toward the Go Note Go-Messager bridge,
implementing a few of the other steps.
Whenever I use &amp;ldquo;@Person&amp;rdquo; in Roam, Bieber Bot automatically copies the message into a spreadsheet.
The spreadsheet has an &amp;ldquo;Approval&amp;rdquo; column, where I can mark messages as OK to send.
Bieber Bot will then use Messager to send any approved messages.
Since Go Note Go sends it&amp;rsquo;s notes to Roam, this completes the circuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can now send messages from Go Note Go to any of Facebook Messenger, Twitter, Slack, and Discord.
I&amp;rsquo;m still excited about pixel-space automation, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to save that excitement for a future snippet; for now, Browserflow was sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go Hardware</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-26-go-note-go-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-26-go-note-go-hardware/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a hardware guide so you can build your own Go Note Go. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep a version of this in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Go Note Go GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; too. This one will likely fall out of date, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the one in the GitHub repo updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;raspberry-pi-400&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 400&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-400-unit/&#34;&gt;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-400-unit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details: I use the US keyboard. You can purchase from e.g. PiShop. I recommend ordering the following as a bundle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Raspberry Pi 400 unit ($70)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class 10 microSD Card With Raspbian - 16GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB-C Power Supply, 5.1V 3.0A, Black, UL Listed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Micro-HDMI to HDMI cable for Pi 4, 3ft, Black&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $91&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voice-bonnet&#34;&gt;Voice bonnet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/4757&#34;&gt;https://www.adafruit.com/product/4757&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I&amp;rsquo;ve actually had some issues with these. The microphone records a high pitched noise and the audio output is quiet and muffled. I will suggest an (untested) alternative speaker and mic below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2x20-connector&#34;&gt;2x20 Connector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/4079&#34;&gt;https://www.adafruit.com/product/4079&lt;/a&gt; OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/2223&#34;&gt;https://www.adafruit.com/product/2223&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommendation: Get the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/2223&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;long pins one&lt;/a&gt;. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/4079&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;short pins one&lt;/a&gt; is sleeker but the long pins might become necessary for connecting the button. TBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Use this to attach the voice bonnet to the Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10000-mah-battery&#34;&gt;10000 mAh battery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07JYYRT7T&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07JYYRT7T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: There are lots of options for the battery. This one works just fine. Could choose one with more storage for longer battery life if desired, but might get clunky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $19 (currently $14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;velcro&#34;&gt;Velcro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08P3MXLLD&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08P3MXLLD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I use this Velcro to mount the keyboard to the passenger side of the car, and to mount the battery to the back of the keyboard. When applying the sticky side to a car dashboard, allow to dry overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usb-cables&#34;&gt;USB Cables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 ft USB - USB C cable: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B089DM4KDW&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B089DM4KDW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 in USB - USB C cable: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B012V56D2A&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B012V56D2A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $13 ($6.99 for 3 ft and $5.99 for 6 in)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-beautiful-red-button&#34;&gt;The Beautiful Red Button&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00T6RCGNC&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00T6RCGNC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternative-mic-and-speaker&#34;&gt;Alternative Mic and Speaker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microphone: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3367&#34;&gt;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3367&lt;/a&gt; ($6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3369&#34;&gt;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3369&lt;/a&gt; ($13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten these set up with Go Note Go yet, but am considering them as an alternative to the Adafruit Voice Bonnet. I really like the LEDs on the voice bonnet though, so TBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: $19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-tools&#34;&gt;Other tools:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;external-monitor-and-a-usb-mouse&#34;&gt;External monitor and a USB Mouse.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be useful for configuring and debugging Go Note Go, e.g. setting up WiFi and configuring your note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wire-wire-stripper&#34;&gt;Wire, Wire Stripper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use The Beautiful Red Button you&amp;rsquo;ll need wire and wire strippers. For wire I used 18 gauge lamp wire I got from Home Depot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lowes.com/pd/Southwire-25-Ft-18-2-Black-Stranded-Lamp-Cord/5001050863&#34;&gt;https://www.lowes.com/pd/Southwire-25-Ft-18-2-Black-Stranded-Lamp-Cord/5001050863&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wire stripper link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Stripper-Stripping-Crimping-Electrical/dp/B086V5M1B4&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Stripper-Stripping-Crimping-Electrical/dp/B086V5M1B4&lt;/a&gt; (Chose this one arbitrarily; I got mine at Home Depot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is the best choice for wire; a higher gauge might be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solder-soldering-iron&#34;&gt;Solder? Soldering iron?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had to use solder yet, but might need to for hooking up the button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot glue or heat shrink and a heat gun might be nice-to-haves too to ensure solid stable connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-other-parts-for-button&#34;&gt;Possible other parts for button&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These might be useful for connecting the button to the GPIO pins on the Pi:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0774NMT1S&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0774NMT1S&lt;/a&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t know. In my experience these were too loose to fit nicely on the GPIO pins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to try these next: GenBasic 40 Piece Female to Female Jumper Wires (4 Inch) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B077N58HFK&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B077N58HFK&lt;/a&gt; ($5)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking System Interoperability</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would be a good &lt;em&gt;standard&lt;/em&gt; for note-taking software to use to support development of system-agnostic tools like Go Note Go? In this snippet I discuss the value such a standard could provide; I expect it will be useful in future brainstorming for what exactly would go into such a standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am building Go Note Go as a note-taking entry point, possibly with some basic retrieval features (e.g. &amp;ldquo;read back the last two notes I took&amp;rdquo;). I currently use Roam Research as my main note-taking system, but I&amp;rsquo;m not wedded to it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m building Go Note Go to work with any note-taking system. To do so, I need a distinct uploader implementation for every note-taking system that I support. I&amp;rsquo;m reaching out to the developers at the note-taking systems to assist with this effort. It would be lovely if there was a standard, to reduce the amount of work required here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Go Note Go, only note &lt;em&gt;entry&lt;/em&gt; is required. If Go Note Go wanted to interact with the notes in a deeper way while continuing to support multiple note-taking systems (e.g. to support spaced repetition, or grocery lists, or reviewing a topic), then a standard would be even more important. Specialized implementations for each note-taking system would become largely untenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is both common and important that hobbyists develop tools for interacting with their notes. Roam Research has 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamjs.com/extensions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hundreds&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/roam-depot-developers/page/8yTj7WxQi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bjosephburch.com/ultimate-roam-tool-kit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;extensions&lt;/a&gt; developed by the Roam community. Obsidian has hundreds of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/plugins&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt;. This is part of what makes these tools so powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, no one has written a tool for both Roam and Obsidian simultaneously. I want people to be able to make tools for all of Roam, Obsidian, IdeaFlow, Mem, RemNote, Notion, Logseq, Athens, Dendron, all the ones I don&amp;rsquo;t know about, and whatever comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these tools will live inside the note-taking editor. Others, like Go Note Go, merely have to interact with the note-taking system, but do not need to become &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of the note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key areas where standards could provide value are: note representation, entry, navigation, editing, and search. Also valuable, but conceptually separate, would be a standard for UI extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards would make the development of system-agnostic tools easier. This includes novel note entry systems (e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh-shell&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;, but also note entry systems for new domains, such as for doctor&amp;rsquo;s offices or for while you&amp;rsquo;re cooking, or for use in virtual reality). It also would support advancements in spaced repetition, multiplayer note-taking, and would enable new features like note summarization and highlight extraction to become available in all the different note-taking systems at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all these applications, standards will make import/export/backup tools easier to build. This can reduce vendor lock in, and more importantly can reduce data loss by enabling robust backups. Today, switching my notes to another system would be a small hassle (e.g. Handling block references in the transfer might require some specialized treatment. And I&amp;rsquo;d need to do some work to set up a spaced repetition system like the one I&amp;rsquo;m currently using in Roam.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll say a few words about some of these ideas that would benefit from standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) &lt;strong&gt;Advancements in spaced repetition.&lt;/strong&gt; Having a spaced repetition system inside of a note-taking system is far lower friction than a separate app. Improvements to SRS that work across all note-taking systems would be warmly welcomed. I believe there are also significant advances to be made in community-scale spaced repetition, where cards and knowledge are drawn from not just your own notes, but from your community&amp;rsquo;s notes (including peers and teachers), and where your review schedule is similarly influenced not only by your own learning progress, but also by the progress of your community. This deserves a separate snippet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll note here a possibility that community-scale spaced repetition enables: it allows for community-level learning priorities, which may include diversity of topic. For example the members of a community might decide they want to ensure that all of its history is adequately studied (or any other collection of topics), not just the most interesting parts. Deciding individually, the members of the community might choose to study overly overlapping parts of its history. Using a community-scale spaced repetition algorithm, the choice of what to study can still predominantly be left up to individuals, but with small guidance from the centralized algorithm the community can ensure complete coverage of all the desired topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) &lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Note-taking&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s say I&amp;rsquo;m doing research on a topic, and a colleague is doing research on a related topic. I might want to search through my colleague&amp;rsquo;s notes, and reference some of them from my own notes. This isn&amp;rsquo;t even possible in most note-taking systems today, but I think is either a future or work-in-progress feature of Roam, Athens, and Obsidian. Being able to do this cross-system would be so much better than only being able to do it within a system. A standard agreed upon by the different note-taking system developers would be necessary to support this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3) &lt;strong&gt;Summarization and highlight extraction&lt;/strong&gt; Summarization is a feature not yet present in any note-taking system, but surely one that will be added to many systems in the future. It is the ability to get a (machine generated) summary of a large chunk of notes automatically. This is marginally useful when reviewing your own notes, but is even more useful in conjunction with multiplayer features. Being able to view a summary of other people&amp;rsquo;s notes or an entire community&amp;rsquo;s notes will allow multiplayer systems to scale to larger groups of people while remaining useful. Highlight extraction is a related future feature, enabling users to quickly find the most important parts of a notebase. As with summarization, this is useful for an individuals notes, and doubly useful for a multiplayer notebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these ideas, standards would be useful for allowing feature development to benefit users of all systems simultaneously, and for allowing users of one note-taking system to benefit from notes taken in another system. The space of possible applications is also much larger than my brainstorming above indicates. Specifically, the set of domain-specific activities one might want to perform with their notes is quite large (planning a family gathering, studying for a med school exam, writing a novel, etc.) Specialized applications could be built for each of these, and it should not matter where the relevant notes were taken. Different systems will always have their pros and cons for different types of content, but we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reinvent the wheel so frequently for use-cases that make sense in the context of all these different systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Snippet with Go Note Go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-27-snippet-on-go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-27-snippet-on-go-note-go/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing and concurrently using Go Note Go for two weeks now, and in that time I have come to love the frictionless way it allows me to dump thoughts into the machine. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to reread what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. There&amp;rsquo;s no going back and rewording something. And more than that, there&amp;rsquo;s no waiting for the characters to show up, or switching tabs, or spell checking or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;m writing a snippet using Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about writing a snippet about Go Note Go over the last two weeks, but I decided not to until yesterday when I finally stopped keeping Go Note Go to myself.
I thought maybe there would be value in getting Go Note Go polished, e.g. writing a getting started guide or even a sales page, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; publishing it once people can actually use it themselves.
But I decided against that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done is better than perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not find a good way to package Go Note Go so that people can start using it with relative ease.
Certainly I can do better than I have so far − there&amp;rsquo;s little help at all for someone to put together their own system.
That said, a motivated individual could in principle piece together their own Go Note Go from what I&amp;rsquo;ve published now.
And I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to help them do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if someone had to ask too many questions or can&amp;rsquo;t reproduce the full setup, maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll take the concept in a new direction.
&amp;ldquo;Headless note−taking&amp;rdquo; is a broad idea and I&amp;rsquo;ve just scratched the surface.
We can see from shh shell and Go Note Go alone that there are diverse approaches one can take to this broad concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to take it further myself, but more than that I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to start the conversation about headless note−taking since it might be able to help a much broader set of people than it&amp;rsquo;s helping right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it would be great in classrooms to avoid distractions.
Maybe there are headless audio−only applications for writers, for programmers, for producers, for lawyers and doctors and publicists and influencers and so forth that are just waiting to be developed.
Different keyboard shortcuts could be specialized for different domains. The addition of foot peddles might help some users. Whatever is needed to make this maximally useful for different applications and different people&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s already super useful for people, but there&amp;rsquo;s just no way for those people to know right now because they can&amp;rsquo;t easily try it, or haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it and thought about it. This is wishful thinking of course; it might be an esoteric toy that is only useful or fun for a small group, but I&amp;rsquo;m confident that group is larger than just myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I want to put this out there a little bit. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share it with Conor of Roam, and with Andy Matuschak, and with folks at IdeaFlow and with Notion users, and with Obsidian folks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;d like to get out of sharing with these groups is contributors to the extensible uploader side of Go Note Go.
I think it would be so cool if each supported note−taking system had an uploader contributed by someone working at that note−taking system&amp;rsquo;s company. Conor or Bardia could make a contribution to the Roam uploader. Jacob or Linus could write the IdeaFlow uploader. Someone from Obsidian and Notion could provide uploaders for each of those. Now that the GitHub for the project is public, this is easier to start working toward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the more I think about the getting started guide, the easier it seems to write. There are only a few steps you really need to follow to get set up. Roughly, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquire the parts (Raspberry Pi, MicroSD card, optional battery pack, USB cords, a speaker and microphone compatible with the Pi (a Voice Bonnet is one option, but any will do.))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone Go Note Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put start script in rc.local file to start on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to configure your wifi wpa config file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking again: I could probably write a decent guide in under an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go is public</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is public! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this for two weeks now, and today I made it public!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Read all about it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it? Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you’re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, it&amp;rsquo;s a portable keyboard with a microphone and speakers and a beautiful handheld button that you can use to take notes anywhere at all. Driving? Push the button and speak your notes. Camping? Type on the keyboard, powered by a battery pack. The battery lasts all day, and the notes will be uploaded to your central note-taking system as soon as internet becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look. Let me know what you think! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it as I develop it over the last two weeks and I &lt;em&gt;really love&lt;/em&gt; it. I keep it by my computer during the work day. I took it with me to my table tennis tournament yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;ve brought it to the beach. There&amp;rsquo;s no cognitive overhead. There&amp;rsquo;s no latency to slow down your thinking. Just speak, or type, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>