<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>go-note-go | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/go-note-go/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/go-note-go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>go-note-go</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>go-note-go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/go-note-go/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking System Interoperability</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would be a good &lt;em&gt;standard&lt;/em&gt; for note-taking software to use to support development of system-agnostic tools like Go Note Go? In this snippet I discuss the value such a standard could provide; I expect it will be useful in future brainstorming for what exactly would go into such a standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am building Go Note Go as a note-taking entry point, possibly with some basic retrieval features (e.g. &amp;ldquo;read back the last two notes I took&amp;rdquo;). I currently use Roam Research as my main note-taking system, but I&amp;rsquo;m not wedded to it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m building Go Note Go to work with any note-taking system. To do so, I need a distinct uploader implementation for every note-taking system that I support. I&amp;rsquo;m reaching out to the developers at the note-taking systems to assist with this effort. It would be lovely if there was a standard, to reduce the amount of work required here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Go Note Go, only note &lt;em&gt;entry&lt;/em&gt; is required. If Go Note Go wanted to interact with the notes in a deeper way while continuing to support multiple note-taking systems (e.g. to support spaced repetition, or grocery lists, or reviewing a topic), then a standard would be even more important. Specialized implementations for each note-taking system would become largely untenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is both common and important that hobbyists develop tools for interacting with their notes. Roam Research has 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamjs.com/extensions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hundreds&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/roam-depot-developers/page/8yTj7WxQi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bjosephburch.com/ultimate-roam-tool-kit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;extensions&lt;/a&gt; developed by the Roam community. Obsidian has hundreds of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/plugins&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt;. This is part of what makes these tools so powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, no one has written a tool for both Roam and Obsidian simultaneously. I want people to be able to make tools for all of Roam, Obsidian, IdeaFlow, Mem, RemNote, Notion, Logseq, Athens, Dendron, all the ones I don&amp;rsquo;t know about, and whatever comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these tools will live inside the note-taking editor. Others, like Go Note Go, merely have to interact with the note-taking system, but do not need to become &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of the note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key areas where standards could provide value are: note representation, entry, navigation, editing, and search. Also valuable, but conceptually separate, would be a standard for UI extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards would make the development of system-agnostic tools easier. This includes novel note entry systems (e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh-shell&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;, but also note entry systems for new domains, such as for doctor&amp;rsquo;s offices or for while you&amp;rsquo;re cooking, or for use in virtual reality). It also would support advancements in spaced repetition, multiplayer note-taking, and would enable new features like note summarization and highlight extraction to become available in all the different note-taking systems at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all these applications, standards will make import/export/backup tools easier to build. This can reduce vendor lock in, and more importantly can reduce data loss by enabling robust backups. Today, switching my notes to another system would be a small hassle (e.g. Handling block references in the transfer might require some specialized treatment. And I&amp;rsquo;d need to do some work to set up a spaced repetition system like the one I&amp;rsquo;m currently using in Roam.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll say a few words about some of these ideas that would benefit from standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) &lt;strong&gt;Advancements in spaced repetition.&lt;/strong&gt; Having a spaced repetition system inside of a note-taking system is far lower friction than a separate app. Improvements to SRS that work across all note-taking systems would be warmly welcomed. I believe there are also significant advances to be made in community-scale spaced repetition, where cards and knowledge are drawn from not just your own notes, but from your community&amp;rsquo;s notes (including peers and teachers), and where your review schedule is similarly influenced not only by your own learning progress, but also by the progress of your community. This deserves a separate snippet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll note here a possibility that community-scale spaced repetition enables: it allows for community-level learning priorities, which may include diversity of topic. For example the members of a community might decide they want to ensure that all of its history is adequately studied (or any other collection of topics), not just the most interesting parts. Deciding individually, the members of the community might choose to study overly overlapping parts of its history. Using a community-scale spaced repetition algorithm, the choice of what to study can still predominantly be left up to individuals, but with small guidance from the centralized algorithm the community can ensure complete coverage of all the desired topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) &lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Note-taking&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s say I&amp;rsquo;m doing research on a topic, and a colleague is doing research on a related topic. I might want to search through my colleague&amp;rsquo;s notes, and reference some of them from my own notes. This isn&amp;rsquo;t even possible in most note-taking systems today, but I think is either a future or work-in-progress feature of Roam, Athens, and Obsidian. Being able to do this cross-system would be so much better than only being able to do it within a system. A standard agreed upon by the different note-taking system developers would be necessary to support this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3) &lt;strong&gt;Summarization and highlight extraction&lt;/strong&gt; Summarization is a feature not yet present in any note-taking system, but surely one that will be added to many systems in the future. It is the ability to get a (machine generated) summary of a large chunk of notes automatically. This is marginally useful when reviewing your own notes, but is even more useful in conjunction with multiplayer features. Being able to view a summary of other people&amp;rsquo;s notes or an entire community&amp;rsquo;s notes will allow multiplayer systems to scale to larger groups of people while remaining useful. Highlight extraction is a related future feature, enabling users to quickly find the most important parts of a notebase. As with summarization, this is useful for an individuals notes, and doubly useful for a multiplayer notebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these ideas, standards would be useful for allowing feature development to benefit users of all systems simultaneously, and for allowing users of one note-taking system to benefit from notes taken in another system. The space of possible applications is also much larger than my brainstorming above indicates. Specifically, the set of domain-specific activities one might want to perform with their notes is quite large (planning a family gathering, studying for a med school exam, writing a novel, etc.) Specialized applications could be built for each of these, and it should not matter where the relevant notes were taken. Different systems will always have their pros and cons for different types of content, but we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reinvent the wheel so frequently for use-cases that make sense in the context of all these different systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Snippet with Go Note Go</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-27-snippet-on-go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-27-snippet-on-go-note-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing and concurrently using Go Note Go for two weeks now, and in that time I have come to love the frictionless way it allows me to dump thoughts into the machine. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to reread what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. There&amp;rsquo;s no going back and rewording something. And more than that, there&amp;rsquo;s no waiting for the characters to show up, or switching tabs, or spell checking or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;m writing a snippet using Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about writing a snippet about Go Note Go over the last two weeks, but I decided not to until yesterday when I finally stopped keeping Go Note Go to myself.
I thought maybe there would be value in getting Go Note Go polished, e.g. writing a getting started guide or even a sales page, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; publishing it once people can actually use it themselves.
But I decided against that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done is better than perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not find a good way to package Go Note Go so that people can start using it with relative ease.
Certainly I can do better than I have so far − there&amp;rsquo;s little help at all for someone to put together their own system.
That said, a motivated individual could in principle piece together their own Go Note Go from what I&amp;rsquo;ve published now.
And I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to help them do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if someone had to ask too many questions or can&amp;rsquo;t reproduce the full setup, maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll take the concept in a new direction.
&amp;ldquo;Headless note−taking&amp;rdquo; is a broad idea and I&amp;rsquo;ve just scratched the surface.
We can see from shh shell and Go Note Go alone that there are diverse approaches one can take to this broad concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to take it further myself, but more than that I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to start the conversation about headless note−taking since it might be able to help a much broader set of people than it&amp;rsquo;s helping right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it would be great in classrooms to avoid distractions.
Maybe there are headless audio−only applications for writers, for programmers, for producers, for lawyers and doctors and publicists and influencers and so forth that are just waiting to be developed.
Different keyboard shortcuts could be specialized for different domains. The addition of foot peddles might help some users. Whatever is needed to make this maximally useful for different applications and different people&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s already super useful for people, but there&amp;rsquo;s just no way for those people to know right now because they can&amp;rsquo;t easily try it, or haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it and thought about it. This is wishful thinking of course; it might be an esoteric toy that is only useful or fun for a small group, but I&amp;rsquo;m confident that group is larger than just myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I want to put this out there a little bit. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share it with Conor of Roam, and with Andy Matuschak, and with folks at IdeaFlow and with Notion users, and with Obsidian folks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;d like to get out of sharing with these groups is contributors to the extensible uploader side of Go Note Go.
I think it would be so cool if each supported note−taking system had an uploader contributed by someone working at that note−taking system&amp;rsquo;s company. Conor or Bardia could make a contribution to the Roam uploader. Jacob or Linus could write the IdeaFlow uploader. Someone from Obsidian and Notion could provide uploaders for each of those. Now that the GitHub for the project is public, this is easier to start working toward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the more I think about the getting started guide, the easier it seems to write. There are only a few steps you really need to follow to get set up. Roughly, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquire the parts (Raspberry Pi, MicroSD card, optional battery pack, USB cords, a speaker and microphone compatible with the Pi (a Voice Bonnet is one option, but any will do.))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone Go Note Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put start script in rc.local file to start on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to configure your wifi wpa config file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking again: I could probably write a decent guide in under an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go is public</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is public! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this for two weeks now, and today I made it public!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Read all about it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it? Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you’re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, it&amp;rsquo;s a portable keyboard with a microphone and speakers and a beautiful handheld button that you can use to take notes anywhere at all. Driving? Push the button and speak your notes. Camping? Type on the keyboard, powered by a battery pack. The battery lasts all day, and the notes will be uploaded to your central note-taking system as soon as internet becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look. Let me know what you think! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it as I develop it over the last two weeks and I &lt;em&gt;really love&lt;/em&gt; it. I keep it by my computer during the work day. I took it with me to my table tennis tournament yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;ve brought it to the beach. There&amp;rsquo;s no cognitive overhead. There&amp;rsquo;s no latency to slow down your thinking. Just speak, or type, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
