<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puzzle | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/puzzle/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/puzzle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Puzzle</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://davidbieber.com/img/portrait.jpg</url>
      <title>Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/puzzle/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Castle Heterodyne</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We built an Escape Room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious props to Bianca Homberg and her amazing talented group of friends for making this happen.
I was just a small piece of this epic endeavor. Bianca was the organizer and driving force for a really impressive piece of puzzle craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise for the escape room is based on the webcomic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Girl Genius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escape-castle-heterodyne&#34;&gt;Escape Castle Heterodyne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a castle, &lt;a href=&#34;http://girlgenius.wikia.com/wiki/Castle_Heterodyne&#34;&gt;Castle Heterodyne&lt;/a&gt;, which is a living, breathing, &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt; entity. In our escape room, the Castle is voiced by Mark Velednitsky. The castle&amp;rsquo;s personality is damaged, and you and your team (4 people total) have been sent into the castle to see if you can repair it. The castle, in it&amp;rsquo;s damaged state, doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand that you&amp;rsquo;re here to help. Quite the opposite in fact; it considers you hostile! At your entrance, Castle Heterodyne slams its doors shut behind you. It cuts power to the lights and activates its 30 minute self-destruct countdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you repair the castle, thereby bringing it back to its senses? Can you escape your impending doom? You must solve puzzles and make your way through four decorative challenge-filled rooms if you wish to live to see another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-engine-room&#34;&gt;The Engine Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for just the first room of the escape room (as well as, I later learned, anything requiring height). This first room was the Engine Room. When you enter the Engine Room, der Castle promptly kills the lights and initiates the castle&amp;rsquo;s self-destruct sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your challenge: get the lights up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do this by first locating a blacklight flashlight on the table in the room. You use this blacklight flashlight to read clues written in invisible ink on colored paper hidden around the room. These clues in turn allow you to figure out which of the nearly 50 switches you need to flip in order to turn all the lights on without overheating any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the puzzle looks like partial solved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;engine-room-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Engine Room: Lights Out Puzzle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the physical puzzle is no longer operational, you can have a go at the software-only version of the puzzle: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/engine-room-demo&#34;&gt;Click here to try the puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-closet&#34;&gt;Storage Closet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you successfully turn the lights back on in the Engine Room, the castle realizes your utility, and presents you with the key to the next room: the Storage Closet. It&amp;rsquo;s too late to turn off the self-destruct sequence though, and so your only way out is forward, through the Storage Closet and the rest of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Storage Closet is in my opinion the coolest room in the Castle. I will refrain from spoiling it here (for now), and simply tell you that I was very impressed with the work that went into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escaping-the-castle&#34;&gt;Escaping the Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making your way through the Storage Closet, you must next navigate the Secret Lab, the Pink Torture Chamber (no puzzles here), and lastly the Crypt. Only after solving the puzzles in each of these rooms with the help can you escape der Castle and avoid a ghastly death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The source code for the Engine Room puzzle (both the physical version and the software-only version) is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bhomberg/heterodyne/blob/master/engine-room/&#34;&gt;GitHub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life at KA: A Khanversation with David Bieber</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-14-khanversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2013-08-14-khanversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://life.khanacademy.org/post/58251244282/im-a-belieber-a-khanversation-with-sw-dev-intern&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted at life.khanacademy.org&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll dive straight into the questions for our latest Khan Academy Khanversation, this time featuring rising Princeton senior David Bieber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David, let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the question everyone is dying to hear you answer. Are you related to Justin Bieber?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny you should ask that. People tell me all the time &amp;ldquo;sorry about your last name&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I hope you&amp;rsquo;re not related to &lt;em&gt;that singer&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;can you get me free tickets to the Bieber concert?&amp;rdquo; And because of that, I&amp;rsquo;ve started feeling a real connection to the guy. I root for his success. I feel down when people trash his music. I think we could become genuinely good friends if we weren&amp;rsquo;t both vying for the top spot on Google for the search term &amp;ldquo;Bieber.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no, I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to his music (much).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;david-bieber-no-beber.png&#34; alt=&#34;No Bieber!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Bieber, how did you come to work at Khan Academy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like life story time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some pretty incredible teachers growing up. Lots of them. And not just the grown-up kind &amp;ndash; the peer kind too. Throughout middle and high school I was involved in this fantastic math community, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://albanyareamathcircle.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Albany Area Math Circle&lt;/a&gt;. We practiced loads of competition math, and most of what I learned, I learned from other students. Some a few years older than me, some a few years younger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I got involved in coaching MathCounts, and I quickly realized that I love teaching. I ran a math camp for middle school students one summer and I had a blast doing it. Whatever I was going to do with my life, it was going to involve teaching in some capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple years, and I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a dining hall in some castle in Princeton. I&amp;rsquo;m talking with some friends about startup ideas &amp;ndash; I have a lot of friends interested in entrepreneurship &amp;ndash; and I have a brilliant idea for a company. (I love getting lost in the excitement of a good idea.) &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll take classes, and we&amp;rsquo;ll put them online. Just Princeton classes to start &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;ll be like MIT&amp;rsquo;s OpenCourseWare &amp;ndash; but we&amp;rsquo;ll make it scalable. And any student with their professor&amp;rsquo;s permission will be able to really easily get their classes&#39; lectures online.&amp;rdquo; Sounds a bit like Coursera. Or YouTube. From there on out, I gave a lot of thought to teaching at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to Khan Academy. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in programming and technology and education, and I&amp;rsquo;m all for making the world a better place. What better way than the KA way to leverage my interests to facilitate teaching at scale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait&amp;hellip; You said you were sitting in a castle?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, half the buildings on campus are castles. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the best thing about Princeton. The best thing about Princeton is Code@Night (though I&amp;rsquo;m biased &amp;ndash; I organize them). Every two to three weeks there&amp;rsquo;s a Code@Night where people gather in this beautiful non-castle building called Sherrerd to code at night. Usually a student or professor or an engineer from a sponsor company will give a tech talk or a demo. People will code all night, they&amp;rsquo;ll play PacMan and eat pizza. Sometimes they&amp;rsquo;ll write poetry. It&amp;rsquo;s really an incredible experience. There are even whiteboards all along the walls making it an ideal environment for puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have a puzzle you could share with us?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure. Here&amp;rsquo;s one that was going around the KA office recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are one hundred prisoners in a prison, and the warden is a bit too much of a puzzle enthusiast. She finds an empty jail cell, and into it puts one hundred boxes. Under each box she puts the name of one of the prisoners, so every prisoner&amp;rsquo;s name appears under precisely one box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then she tells the prisoners this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each one of you will be led individually into the jail cell with one hundred boxes. Under one of these boxes is your name. You will each be allowed to look under 50 boxes, but if even one of you doesn&amp;rsquo;t find your own name, all one hundred of you will be locked away forever. That said, if all of you find your own name then you will be freed immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prisoners are terrified, but also excited. They love puzzles too. Help them form a strategy to maximize the chance that they&amp;rsquo;ll be granted their freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some caveats: Once the prisoners start going into the cell with the boxes, no communication between the prisoners is allowed. And the prisoners cannot make any modifications to the room with the boxes either &amp;ndash; no leaving boxes turned over, no writing on the walls, and no taking boxes out of the room or moving them, even the one with your name under it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sounds tough. What&amp;rsquo;s the answer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pshhh, don&amp;rsquo;t give up yet. It&amp;rsquo;s a really good puzzle. Who&amp;rsquo;s asking these questions, anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That&amp;rsquo;d be me. David Bieber.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what you&amp;rsquo;re telling me is that I&amp;rsquo;m involved in a virtual interview&amp;hellip; with myself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to think I thought the Turing test was hard&amp;hellip; why are you writing all this anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s good to take a break from coding every now and again. Plus, I really like having people read the things I write &amp;ndash; I found this out after starting my blog a year ago (&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.davidbieber.com&#34;&gt;take a look!&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;ndash; it makes the writing process a lot more fun. It also gives you all a better feel for life at Khan Academy, and that transparency is really valuable. We’re real people who make KA run! Seeing all the awesome stuff on this blog is part of why I came to work here. But most of all, the writing really is fun! Especially the Bieber bit &amp;ndash; I had a good time writing that. And no, we’re not related.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
