<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>attention on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/attention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in attention on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/attention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Dream of Just One Inbox</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-09-26-just-one-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-09-26-just-one-inbox/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ideally I&amp;rsquo;d have just a single inbox, but in practice I have several.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I have so many that I forget about some of them, and they fade away. Especially if we count all the different Slacks I&amp;rsquo;m part of, there&amp;rsquo;s no way I could keep up with all my inboxes. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of the inboxes I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to stay on top of: Personal email, Work email, Texts and Voicemail, a Twitter DMs, Facebook Messenger. In addition to these, there are more inboxes that I check but don&amp;rsquo;t really try to stay on top of: a shared Roam graph, some Slacks, and some Discords. Beyond these are the inboxes that I simply don&amp;rsquo;t think about these days: various forums, other Slacks and Discords, old game message boards. I&amp;rsquo;m blanking on the names of some of these, that&amp;rsquo;s how much they&amp;rsquo;ve faded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in my ideal world with a single inbox, there are different kinds of items that could reside in the inbox. I think the major designations are: requires attention, deferred, and indexed. Basically my thinking is, some items (i.e. emails, texts, voicemails, etc&amp;hellip; all the items that are directly specifically toward me that I want to read) go into the actual &lt;em&gt;inbox&lt;/em&gt; part of the inbox. They form a queue of things to process. I can process them by performing the task (responding, handling, etc) or by deferring (i.e. moving into a TODO list of sorts). Other items enter the inbox differently, and let&amp;rsquo;s take messages on a giant Slack channel as an example. These don&amp;rsquo;t need to be processed individually. They don&amp;rsquo;t even need to be processed in batch, to be honest. But it is nice to know that a whole batch of messages has arrived in the last week. I think my ideal would be that across many Slack channels and across many Slack groups and even across both Slacks and Discords and Google Chats, an overall digest of all the messages missed once a week or so would be nice. Eh, honestly that&amp;rsquo;s not necessary, the messages I have in mind are safe to ignore; it would be great if they remained searchable though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize the different kinds of messages I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about, there are: (1) emails to me (each time I process the inbox, email email is an item to handle), (2) messages in large groups (these should be batched, and frozen at the time of consumption, OK to ignore lots; their presence should not indicate the need for a processing session), and (3) items I&amp;rsquo;ve saved for later (this is task tracking; tasks can appear in inbox if a system surfaces them to my attention, but can usually get out of the way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the inboxes I try to stay on top of should be combined into one inbox and all messages therein fall into category 1. All the inboxes I check but don&amp;rsquo;t stay on top of should get batched and form category 2 (perhaps together constituting a single item of category 1). And any of these if ignored or deferred can become a category 3 item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS in some ways is an effort toward constructing a single inbox out of many disparate message locations. RSS readers, however, seem to have gone out of fashion. And even in their heyday, RSS feeds never handled emails, texts, phone calls, Twitter DMs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s Sophia&amp;rsquo;s Unigraph. It shows promise as a potential unified inbox. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen as a demo it handles incoming tweets easily and is designed to be extensible to additional data sources. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t mature enough to take on One Inbox status last time I checked in on it, but perhaps with additional development it can reach that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bieber Bot does so much for me, and one of the things he does well is reducing the number of inboxes I have. Facebook Event invites, reminders about upcoming activities, and some other reminders all come through Bieber Bot, whereas without him I&amp;rsquo;d have to check Facebook and various spreadsheets and calendars as well. I already treat Facebook messenger as an inbox zero location, where all messages are processed, making Bieber Bot (who contacts me through FB Messenger) a good choice for surfacing such things. I actually treat FB Messenger more as an inbox-zero location than I do email (though to my delight I am at inbox zero for emails too these days), I guess in part because email gets a higher rate of messages making inbox zero harder to sustain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we were to build a new inbox, designed to be the One Inbox that replaces all others.
It would have to handle receiving messages in a boatload of different services and sending messages in all these services too.
It would have to handle easily adding new services that the developers didn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate.
Imagine using automation software like Browserflow to specify how the service should gather new items for an inbox.
For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to integrate Roam or Twitter into your inbox, but the One Inbox developers haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Roam or Twitter.
So you make a Browserflow flow that collects the inbox items from Roam or Twitter, and One Inbox runs it periodically on your behalf to gather new messages. You make a second Browserflow flow that shows One Inbox what it means to send messages through the new service.
Better even than that experience would be something like what the latest Adept AI demo is hinting at. In that direction, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to construct a program to show the One Inbox software how to receive and send messages; you just teach it with a combination of demonstration and natural language, and it can handle the rest from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we build the hypothetical One Inbox software, there are latency considerations. How long after a message is received on a service is it before the message appears in our One Inbox? Does this matter? Yes. The case for yes: you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss items. The case for no: if we&amp;rsquo;re following an infrequent processing workflow, several minutes of latency doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter most of the time. Clearly the yeses have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software I use that comes closest to a One Inbox (besides Bieber Bot) right now is Ferdi. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything intelligent to normalize incoming messages into a shared format across different messaging systems. That would be quite difficult (I think texts.com does this; I would like to try it, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet). Instead, Ferdi just acts as a browser, loading all your different inboxes alongside one another. When described like this, it sounds silly and pointless &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;why not just use tabs in your browser?&amp;rdquo;. Well, the experience in Ferdi is different than just using tabs in your browser because it&amp;rsquo;s a separate application from your browser, it handles loading and unloading differently, and services are pinned with little icons for easy access. These are mostly superficial things, but they add up to an improved experience compared with keeping lots of tabs for lots of inboxes open in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Your Co-Working Sessions to the Next Level</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-05-01-coworking-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-05-01-coworking-sessions/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy hosting co-working sessions.
Pre-pandemic I used to just go to a coffee shop and invite people to join me.
Now, trying to limit exposure to strangers, I&amp;rsquo;m having working sessions at my apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These working sessions are gatherings intended for people to independently work on hobbies, side projects, work, homework, future startups, catching up on emails, reading, whatever. Having other people around can make working more fun and make it easier to stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of ideas about how to take these co-working sessions to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cords and cables for charging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food prepared in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go Note Gos everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro timers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for people to declare what they&amp;rsquo;re working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated time for chitchat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A firm stance on allowing people to get to work if chitchat lingers more than several minutes outside of a planned time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a shared chat room for people to send non-interrupting messages to the whole group.
Useful for coordinating going out for lunch taking breaks etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear policy on inviting others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adequate comfortable space for everyone, including spaces just move around and switch positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to make coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do some taxonomizing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas are about providing technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cords and cables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go Note Gos everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat room for non-interrupting messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about providing nutrition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food prepared in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to make coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about establishing social norms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro timers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for people to declare what they&amp;rsquo;re working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated time for chitchat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A firm stance on allowing people to get to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat room for non-interrupting messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear policy on inviting others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are about making people comfortable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adequate comfortable space for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the food ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External monitors and Cords and cables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sold these are &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; good ideas
(e.g. pomodoro timers can be disruptive, and I considered putting &lt;em&gt;light music&lt;/em&gt; on the list but decided against it),
but I think that by implementing several of these ideas I can make my working sessions a little more welcoming and enjoyable for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inviting people in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having about 6 people in total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inviting people around a theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing updates at the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning a working session in conjunction with another activity like a hike or dinner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My strategies for keeping my attention</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-18-attention-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-03-18-attention-strategies/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve sometimes had trouble focusing. My attention will sometimes drift to one of the internet&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/&#34;&gt;infinite distractions&lt;/a&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a list of strategies I use to combat this, to better align my attention with my intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an outliner like Roam Research (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/tags/roam-research&#34;&gt;these snippets&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with another person (e.g. pair programming)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with another person present (e.g. independent coworking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-09-mobile-distraction-detection-at-last/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;distraction detection&amp;rdquo; program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentally noting the distraction-kind and returning my attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-08-phone-in-kitchen/&#34;&gt;my phone in my kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;, my headless keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending meetings/talks in &amp;ldquo;clamshell mode&amp;rdquo; (laptop closed, no keyboard or mouse available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making TODO lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And explicitly writing down the ^^active TODO^^&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to sleep at a &lt;strong&gt;specific&lt;/strong&gt; time (e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-20-sleep-no-snippet/&#34;&gt;10:10pm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercising regularly (or at least 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/tags/table-tennis/&#34;&gt;aiming to&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopping watching TV in the middle of an episode (ends of episodes are more addicting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 minute working sessions (e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://focusmate.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;focusmate.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking short deliberate breaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Pomodoro timers for working sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/intention-stop-mindless-b/dladanhaondcgpahgiflodhckhoeohoe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Intention&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; Chrome extension by DK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping all notifications on my phone turned off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking the people I live with to get my attention first before starting a conversation with me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announcing my current active goal publicly (e.g. in a chat room)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hidefeed.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“Hide feed”&lt;/a&gt; Chrome extension, also by DK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Minds Fallacy</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-07-efficient-minds-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-07-efficient-minds-fallacy/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This snippet is similar to these related snippets from March 2021: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/&#34;&gt;#1&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-10-efficient-minds-hypothesis-failing&#34;&gt;#2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about the Efficient Minds Fallacy lately, and so I read this as it relates to the EMF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Efficient Minds Fallacy occurs when someone incorrectly believes in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-10-efficient-minds-hypothesis-failing&#34;&gt;Efficient Minds Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt; or one of it&amp;rsquo;s consequences. The Efficient Minds Hypothesis is only slightly more silly than it&amp;rsquo;s namesake, the Efficient Market Hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Efficient &lt;strong&gt;Minds&lt;/strong&gt; Hypothesis (EMH) says that if you know $A$ and you know $A \rightarrow B$, then you also know $B$. On the surface this sounds reasonable, but it is demonstrably false and has pernicious consequences if believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it in plain English: the EMH states that given the information available to you, you know all the conclusions that can be deduced from that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is obviously false. If it were true, you would never lose a game of chess (no new information is introduced).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main reasons it&amp;rsquo;s false:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noticing that a reasoning step can take place requires attending to the premises; your attention may be on other information, and so you might not notice that a reasoning step can be performed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computation takes time. Even if you are acutely aware of two premises, it still requires time to perform the step of reasoning to reach the conlusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending to the premises takes time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/&#34;&gt;why do people believe it&lt;/a&gt;? And what evidence do we have that people believe it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My estimation is: it largely manifests in over confidence, allocating insufficient time for thinking deeply about things, insufficient time for thinking deeply (not about things in particular), and under-reliance on others / an under-appreciation for the power of a second brain or second perspective (e.g. not seeking advice as much)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;rsquo;ve observed these things in myself. Almost always when I do ask for someone else&amp;rsquo;s advice or perspective on something (something I&amp;rsquo;d like to do more of), I am surprised and delighted by the insight they are able to offer. I attribute the surprisal that I experience to my natural inclination toward believing the EMH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to clarify: at a logical level, I do absolutely do not believe the EMH; I think it&amp;rsquo;s preposterous and demonstrably false. Nevertheless, when I am not attending to the EMH, and am instead attending to some other problem, I forget that I have concluded the EMH is false, and so I am still liable to the EMF. So I find it useful to remind myself of the EMF periodically so that it feels more natural seeking other people&amp;rsquo;s advice, seeking collaborations, acknowledging that I may have missed many things when considering a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are the implications of EMF for meditation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letting your brain do some work is good, because good thinking takes time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatever conclusions you&amp;rsquo;ve reached about meditation and mindfulness so far are not necessarily the final conclusions you will reach, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t learn anything new about the practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone in the kitchen evaluation</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-22-phone-in-kitchen-eval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-22-phone-in-kitchen-eval/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I decided to start keeping my phone in the kitchen while I&amp;rsquo;m in the house. I said I&amp;rsquo;d evaluate the decision after 6 weeks and decide whether to recommit. It&amp;rsquo;s been six weeks, and I think it was an excellent decision. I will absolutely continue doing this going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find I get more time in the mornings, because scrolling in bed or on the toilet isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option. Similarly in the evenings, scrolling in bed before going to sleep isn&amp;rsquo;t something I can do by accident. I do find I spend more time in the kitchen, in order to use my phone. So, I haven&amp;rsquo;t eliminated mindless scrolling altogether. My phone usage has decreased considerably overall though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oddest thing about it is that I don&amp;rsquo;t always have a way of knowing the itme when I wake up. I may want to put a non-phone clock in the bedroom to compensate for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes over the last six months I would find I accidentally would bring my phone with me to my desk. Usually this would happen after going out of the house for lunch (taking my phone with me). When I would return to the house, I would have my phone in my pocket, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t always remember to put it in the kitchen. Once the phone reached my desk, sometimes I would then inadvertently scroll! Whenever I notice that I&amp;rsquo;ve brought my phone somewhere in the house outside the kitchen, it&amp;rsquo;s clear the right thing for me to do under this silly system I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen for myself, is to bring it back to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be tempting to make only small violations to the rule, but I&amp;rsquo;ve realized it&amp;rsquo;s best not to fall for such temptations. There&amp;rsquo;s a bathroom just outside the kitchen, and I am tempted often to take the phone with me from the kitchen to the bathroom. I stop at the threshold to the kitchen, and do not cross if I&amp;rsquo;m holding my phone. Perhaps I stand in the threshold for a few minutes, finishing my phone usage before leaving. I put the phone down before exiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to take the phone to the bathroom, I know what would happen. I would think, going in, that I will just use the phone for one particular purpose. However, as soon as I turn the screen on I would notice something that would put a different purpose into my mind. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a text message, or an app icon, or a notification. I think, switching tasks, that it&amp;rsquo;s a small diversion and I will momentarily return to the original purpose. However, moments later while completing the secondary task, my mental stack will erode, and the primary task will no longer be at the forefront of my brain. I&amp;rsquo;ll no longer be thinking about the one-and-done approach to phone usage, and now the potential for mindless scrolling has emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the phone stays in the kitchen. I will keep this rule for myself, at least as long as I live here in this house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping my phone in the kitchen</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-08-phone-in-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-08-phone-in-kitchen/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep my phone in the kitchen while I&amp;rsquo;m in the house.
The goal is to reduce scrolling in the morning and evening, and prevent distractions more generally.
By keeping the phone in the kitchen, I&amp;rsquo;ll be unable to scroll mindlessly when I first wake up (unless of course I go to the kitchen to do so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by putting this intention up on my website, by having it in writing, by leaving it in a place where others could theoretically have read it, I am more likely to stick to this intention (both the spirit and the letter of it) for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I don&amp;rsquo;t yet know how this will go, or when I&amp;rsquo;ll first forget about it, I&amp;rsquo;ll pick a date now to check in on it. August 19, 2021. On August 19, 2021, six weeks from today, I&amp;rsquo;ll reevaluate this decision. If I like it, probably I will recommit to it for an additional period of time. If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me, no harm done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplest Possible Case of the Efficient Minds Hypothesis Failing</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-10-efficient-minds-hypothesis-failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-10-efficient-minds-hypothesis-failing/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose you know $A$, and you know $A \to B$. Conventional wisdom suggests you also know $B$. However, this is not necessarily true. Conventional wisdom has incorrectly assumed the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/&#34;&gt;Efficient Minds Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why isn&amp;rsquo;t this true? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it the first thing you&amp;rsquo;re taught in an Introductory Logic course? The reason is that it takes time and attention to conclude $B$ given that you know (1) $A$ and (2) $A \to B$. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that you know both (1) and (2) and made the connection between them isn&amp;rsquo;t specified, so we can&amp;rsquo;t conclude that you&amp;rsquo;ve reached the conclusion $B$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might object &amp;ldquo;well if &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; knew $A$ and $A \to B$, I would conclude $B$ immediately. It&amp;rsquo;s obvious.&amp;rdquo; To this I would reply &amp;ldquo;not so fast &amp;ndash; no pun intended,&amp;rdquo; while clearly intending the pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might know thousands of facts $P_1, \cdots, P_{9000}$. Noticing that two of them collectively have the form (1) $A$ and (2) $A \to B$ is a bit like finding a needle in a haystack; there are $9000^2$ fact pairs in that set to consider. While finding the good pairs can sometimes be fast, it&amp;rsquo;s never immediate and sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you know (1) $A$ and (2) $B$, you still may not know $A\text{ and }B$. And if you know just (1) $A$, you may not realize $A\text{ or }B$. Each of these conclusions requires time and attention to reach, even if classical first order logic tells us the conclusions are trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we are often able to perform inference really quickly is a remarkable thing, attributable to our brain&amp;rsquo;s natural but imperfect tendency to index information by its important properties. While our brains are remarkable, they are not perfectly efficient, and we should behoove ourselves not to fall prey to the fallacy of the Efficient Minds Hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Games Inter-company Compact</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-08-healthy-games-inter-company-compact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-08-healthy-games-inter-company-compact/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This snippet is a silly, currently unworkable, but in my opinion still worthwhile idea to improve the healthiness of video games. Mobile games today are in an arms race. Make your game more addicting, and your game becomes more profitable. More addicting is not the same as more fun. They may be correlated, but the incentives of video game companies are not wholly aligned with the incentives of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it an &amp;ldquo;arms race&amp;rdquo;? There&amp;rsquo;s limited mindshare. Making your game addicting claims more of this mindshare. More engaging games are more profitable. And there&amp;rsquo;s no easy way for a game company to disentangle unhealthy addictive engagement from increased engagement due to increased quality of the game (is this true? will ponder&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers of these games will A/B test mechanisms and designs and select those that maximize engagement. This isn&amp;rsquo;t unique to video games; it applies to social media and advertising as well, but we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on video games for this snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the &amp;ldquo;Healthy Games Inter-company Compact&amp;rdquo;. This is a hypothetical future agreement between all the video game companies. The &amp;ldquo;Healthy Games Inter-company Compact&amp;rdquo; (HGIC for short) states that once 100% of game companies agree to the compact, all video games will simultaneously reduce the addictiveness of their games by 20% (the specific number&amp;rsquo;s not central to the idea). Signing the agreement does nothing if not all video game companies have signed. Only once all such companies are signed the agreement does it come into effect. At that point, the agreement comes into effect for all companies at once, and all games are simultaneously made less addicting. (This idea is inspired by the real 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Popular_Vote_Interstate_Compact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Popular Vote Interstate Compact&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many reasons why this can&amp;rsquo;t work in practice. In the spirit of taking silly ideas seriously, let&amp;rsquo;s go through those reasons, and perhaps we&amp;rsquo;ll find some of them weaker than first appearance might suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first reason it can&amp;rsquo;t work is that 100% of video game companies agreeing to &amp;ldquo;mutual disarmament&amp;rdquo; would be such an extraordinary feat. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_game_industry#Scope&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; estimates that in the US alone there are 2,300 development companies and over 525 publishing companies. What would a consortium of all video game companies even look like? Why would 10% of companies agree to this compact, let alone 100%? A few could agree to it out of genuine interest in the health of their addiction-prone players. A few others could agree to it if it makes strategic sense for them. Getting to 10% seems farfetched, 100% fantastical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, even if all the current video game companies did agree, the market is such that a new player could enter the video game industry at any time, disregarding the compact. This HGIC would need to be legislation, not just an inter-company compact, for it to apply to new entrants. This is something I am doubtful I would support, even though the HGIC is my idea. It would proabably even take considerable effort to make a legislative version of the HGIC constitutional! (Is game mechanism design a protected form of speech?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, even if all current video game companies signed the HGIC, acted in good faith, and even if there were no possibility of new entrants, there still remain the difficult questions of how to measure the reduction in unhealthy addictiveness of games. As a strawman, the HGIC could specify a metric, say play-time per player, and all companies would reduce their play-time per player by an agreed upon percent. I&amp;rsquo;ll readily acknowledge this sounds ridiculous; it could mean ruining the fun of some games, not making them healthier! As a second strawman, the HGIC could specify specific game mechanics and how to adjust them. E.g. it would specify that count-down timers need to be shortened by X% (does that even help?), non-deterministic rewards need to be made Y% more deterministic, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ll readily acknowledge this strawman is ridiculous too; there are likely too many possible game mechanics for an agreement of this form to be manageable to produce. Finding an equivalent reduction in addictiveness across all games is impossible because games are simply too varied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourthly and finally, &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve shared this idea with so far (three people in total) have disagreed with the premise, that the addicting nature of video games is a negative thing, and that reducing it is desirable. This is a real surprise to me. I thought it was generally accepted that the tactics employed by FarmVille, CandyCrush, Covet, and the like are deliberative exploitative and addictive, designed through experimentation to maximize engagement and profit, and that this is a negative aspect of the games. I suppose I was wrong about this (the generally accepted part, that is). Guess I need to expand my bubble.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have four solid reasons that the Healthy Games Inter-company Compact could never come into effect. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a dozen more. It&amp;rsquo;s nevertheless nice to imagine a world in which a few companies draft and sign the compact, initially thinking it will never come into effect. And then, over time, more companies are drawn to the idea of improving the health of their addiction-prone customers, until eventually the industry enacts and broadly follows guidelines for healthy game development. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a world to aspire to, albeit unrealistic. So while the HGIC in all likelihood won&amp;rsquo;t work, perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s another path there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a glimpse of what people think outside my itsy-bitsy social bubble, you can have a look at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.commonsensemedia.org/app-reviews/candy-crush-saga/user-reviews/adult&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these mixed reviews of CandyCrush from parents and children&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Efficient Minds Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Efficient Minds Hypothesis&amp;rdquo; states that a person is able to reach whatever conclusions they are able to reach in a small finite amount of time. Unless new information is presented, after that small duration no new conclusions will be reached. Stated more succinctly, the Efficient Minds Hypothesis states that &amp;ldquo;thinking is near-instantaneous.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is of course, preposterous. However, when it is not named and stated so explicitly, believing the EMH is an easy trap to fall into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are negative consequences to believing the EMH, even implicitly or subconsciously. It can lead to asking fewer questions. It can lead to scheduling less time for planning and Great Thoughts, and spending too large a proportion of your time on building and chasing short-term goals. It can lead to too much self-reliance, and a reluctance to delegate or share the burden of a project with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Efficient Minds Hypothesis is mainly a strawman that I don&amp;rsquo;t think many people would claim to believe outright, I do think it&amp;rsquo;s an idea that people (at least myself) sometimes believe implicitly. Making it explicit helps to make its status as a fallacy clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write about the Efficient Minds Hypothesis from personal experience. While I don&amp;rsquo;t consciously believe the EMH (as I stated above, I think it&amp;rsquo;s preposterous), I find that beneath the surface of my thoughts I often do believe it, and can act or think accordingly. Being surrounded by creative intelligent people at work, spending every day thinking about challenging problems, the falsity of the EMH (at least with respect to my own mind), has been crystal clear day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its falsity is most clear when a colleague suggests a solution to a problem that I have that I have not seen. The solution feels like something simple enough to arrive at quickly given my experience, but it is apparently not, for it&amp;rsquo;s a solution I did not foresee. On N occasions it has even been the case that I have not even begun to properly start thinking about the problem when a colleague presents the solution, perhaps because there are many possible problems to attend to, and selecting where to place one&amp;rsquo;s attention is a problem in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the EMH, the idea that you can present a problem to a colleague without first having given it the small finite first attempt doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. If EMH were true, you would present only problems that you cannot yourself solve to your colleagues. In the time it takes to present a problem, you would have attempted solving it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maxims of &amp;ldquo;bring me solutions, not problems&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t come to me until you&amp;rsquo;ve worked this out as much as you can on your own&amp;rdquo; are weakened by the lack of an EMH too. Sometimes you need to engage other minds simply to parallelize computation, not because one mind alone cannot solve something. The benefits of multiple minds go beyond parallelization though. Freshness and specialization are two principles that make a collaboration more than the sum of its parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why believe the EMH at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When young, when working on easier problems, when you can anticipate what comes next, when your mind is fresh, well rested, and well equipped for the tasks at hand, the EMH can appear and feel true.
A quick look at any complex task, say chess or a hard math problem, makes it apparent that it&amp;rsquo;s not universally true. But those System 2 tasks do nothing to dispel the EMH in System 1 heavy situations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that thinking takes time. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that System 1 thinking in particular takes time. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that something requires System 2 thought. And finally it isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that thinking has bandwidth, and that ideas and projects can be thought-bandwidth bottlenecked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is that we need to be deliberate with how we choose to spend our brainpower. And this starts with being mindful and intentional with our attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an exercise for the reader: Would the Efficient Minds Hypothesis imply the Efficient Market Hypothesis? How about the reverse?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;System 1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;System 2&amp;rdquo; refer to Kahneman&amp;rsquo;s dichotomy of fast intuitive (System 1) vs slow, deliberate, planned (System 2) thought from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking,_Fast_and_Slow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find yourself typing t-ENTER often?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-10-find-yourself-typing-t-enter-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-10-find-yourself-typing-t-enter-often/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common attention pitfall is to mindless type cmd-t t ENTER. cmd-t creates a new tab. &amp;ldquo;t&amp;rdquo; autocompletes to twitter.com. ENTER. Four keystrokes and you&amp;rsquo;re scrolling. &amp;ldquo;r&amp;rdquo; for reddit. &amp;ldquo;f&amp;rdquo; for facebook. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than a second of mindless activity, leading to hundreds of seconds (minutes? hours?) of scrolling that you didn&amp;rsquo;t intend to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the solution. &lt;strong&gt;Delete websites from your browser&amp;rsquo;s autocomplete.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to do. On Mac, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;fn-shift-delete&lt;/strong&gt;. On Windows, just shift-delete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just select the website from Chrome&amp;rsquo;s dropdown and press fn-shift-delete, and the website is removed from your browser&amp;rsquo;s autocomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Firefox, it&amp;rsquo;s even easier: just press shift-delete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the websites will make their way back into your autocomplete, but it will take a while for this to happen. And when it does, now you know what to do: fn-shift-delete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing my Twitter Feed</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-08-repurposing-my-twitter-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-08-repurposing-my-twitter-feed/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;rsquo;s addicting. It&amp;rsquo;s not a good use of my time, but I scroll there anyway. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be scrolling there anyway, might as well make it worthwhile. So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to repurpose my Twitter timeline and inject things I actually care about into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? You might think to do this with a Chrome extension, injecting content in between the existing tweets. There&amp;rsquo;s an easier way though. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a new, private Twitter account, and I programmatically&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; tweet as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal Twitter account is @Bieber, and I use a picture of myself for the profile. The new account goes by &amp;ldquo;Private Bieber&amp;rdquo;, and uses a deep dream-ified version of my profile picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it decide what to tweet? It chooses tweets from my Roam Research database. I already frequently write down things I&amp;rsquo;d like to learn about, and ideas I&amp;rsquo;d like to try in Roam. It&amp;rsquo;s where I keep my snippet ideas, my spaced repetition system, and my &amp;ldquo;Fleeting TODOs&amp;rdquo;. Source code available in the footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fleeting TODOs are what I call TODO items that tug at my brain in the moment, eager to take my attention away from the task at hand. Rather than do them then, I write them down. I only ever get around to doing a small fraction of my fleeting TODOs, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a record of them. It makes it easier to notice if I keep coming back to the same idea, in which case maybe it&amp;rsquo;s worth actually pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a script that occasionally &amp;ndash; currently every 10 minutes &amp;ndash; picks out one of these items from my Roam Research database and tweets it in a way that&amp;rsquo;s only visible to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have my Twitter feed configured to show me tweets chronologically, this means there&amp;rsquo;s always a tweet from Private Bieber sitting at the top, to remind me of something &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; care about, rather than something the &lt;em&gt;Twitter algorithm&lt;/em&gt; has picked out for me to care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FxD83QrK9_D.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=76f275ac-62fd-4844-829c-b44cf9cf568f&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the tweet selection is random, but already in this first 20 minutes I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy with the tweets it&amp;rsquo;s been writing. Perhaps in a future iteration I&amp;rsquo;ll make some adjustments to what it tweets and when. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have this kind of control over my attention, especially in a setting like Twitter where I&amp;rsquo;m so used to mindless scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This same technique ought to work fine for taking control of my Facebook feed too, so perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll get Private Bieber an account there next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dbieber/47660493954e62f4607cd8d19d54cf59&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Source code is here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flow for Focused Reading</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-05-focused-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-05-focused-reading/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the snippet you&amp;rsquo;re currently reading, I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented a simple tool to help with focused reading. (It&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-02-focused-reading-browserflow-flow-idea/&#34;&gt;the idea from the previous snippet&lt;/a&gt;). The majority of the page is dimmed, except for a few lines above and below your mouse cursor. As you move your mouse, the focused region follows. Give it a try; move your mouse (or touch) over the next paragraph, and watch as the light region follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is useful for staying focused when reading. If your eyes or mind wander while reading, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to quickly bring your attention back to exactly where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Browserflow&lt;/a&gt; users among you (psst&amp;hellip; DK, you need to ship Browserflow so there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; Browserflow users out there), you can enable this effect on any page using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/8c2f3de8-2666-4578-8b42-58f5cad105b0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this BrowserFlow flow I made&lt;/a&gt;. Once you get the flow you can simply type cmd-J and select &amp;ldquo;Focus Bar&amp;rdquo; from the typeahead to enable this effect anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everyone else, you can paste this script into your JavaScript console. 🤷&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;var mouseY = 0;
var scrollY = 0;
var offset = 50;
var div_below, div_above;

div_below = document.createElement(&amp;quot;div&amp;quot;);
div_below.style.position = &amp;quot;absolute&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.left = &amp;quot;0px&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.top = &amp;quot;0px&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.width = &amp;quot;100%&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.height = &amp;quot;100%&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.background = &amp;quot;black&amp;quot;;
div_below.style.opacity = &amp;quot;30%&amp;quot;;

div_above = document.createElement(&amp;quot;div&amp;quot;);
div_above.style.position = &amp;quot;absolute&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.left = &amp;quot;0px&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.bottom = &amp;quot;0px&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.width = &amp;quot;100%&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.height = &amp;quot;100%&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.background = &amp;quot;black&amp;quot;;
div_above.style.opacity = &amp;quot;30%&amp;quot;;

document.body.appendChild(div_below);
document.body.appendChild(div_above);

function adjust_divs() {
  scrollY = window.pageYOffset || document.documentElement.scrollTop || document.body.scrollTop || 0;
  div_below.style.top = (mouseY + offset + scrollY) + &#39;px&#39;;
  div_above.style.bottom = (
      &#39;calc(100% - &#39; + (mouseY - offset + scrollY) + &#39;px&#39;);
  div_below.style.height = (
      &#39;calc(100% - &#39; + (mouseY + offset) + &#39;px&#39;);
}

document.addEventListener(&#39;mousemove&#39;, function(event) {
  mouseY = event.clientY;
  adjust_divs();
}, true);

document.addEventListener(&#39;scroll&#39;, function(event) {
  adjust_divs();
}, true);
document.addEventListener(&#39;touchstart&#39;, function(event) {
  mouseY = event.touches[0].clientY;
  adjust_divs();
}, true);
document.addEventListener(&#39;touchmove&#39;, function(event) {
  mouseY = event.touches[0].clientY;
  adjust_divs();
}, true);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry about the jitter. Let me know if you know how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focused Reading Browserflow Flow Idea</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-02-focused-reading-browserflow-flow-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-02-focused-reading-browserflow-flow-idea/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This idea for an assistive technology for focused reading comes from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://accessibe.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;accessiBe&lt;/a&gt;. I stumbled upon it on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tasteofhome.com/recipes/homemade-potato-chips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tasteofhome.com&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is to make the web more accessible to folks with ADHD by dimming the part of the screen they&amp;rsquo;re not actively looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of the accessiBe implementation in action on the tasteofhome.com website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FbF12xbo8EB.gif?alt=media&amp;amp;token=d1cc35a1-8354-4859-9415-7a48e5283310&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the screen is dimmed everywhere except on the lines surrounding the mouse pointer. This helps me to regain focus more quickly if my attention is drawn away from the text I was reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this way of reading helpful, and so I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about making it for myself as a Browserflow flow. It should be easy enough to do. When the flow starts, it just has to add two large transparent rectangles to the DOM, and an event handler to update their positions whenever my mouse moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll put up another snippet if and when I build this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update Feb 5, 2021: As you may have noticed, I&amp;rsquo;ve now implemented this idea. It&amp;rsquo;s enabled on this page, and also available as a Browserflow flow. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-05-focused-reading&#34;&gt;See the snippet here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kangaroo Auto-responder</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-29-kangaroo-auto-responder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-29-kangaroo-auto-responder/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Kangaroo Auto-responder is to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid people expecting a response from me when I don&amp;rsquo;t realize they&amp;rsquo;re expecting a response, e.g. because I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about their message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should let me let my guard down a bit about feeling obligated to respond to people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will it do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will automatically respond to messages that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen but haven&amp;rsquo;t responded to for 2+ hours with a kangaroo&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time it sends someone a kangaroo, it will also explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Kangaroo] Hello! This is an automated reply from the Kangaroo Auto-responder. You&amp;rsquo;re getting this message because it looks like David might forget to reply to your message. If you want a response, you should contact him again. (Just saying &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo; is often enough!)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text for the second time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Kangaroo] Me again. David might forget to reply to your message. In the future I&amp;rsquo;ll just send you a picture of a Kangaroo to symbolize this. 🦘  If you ever get a picture of a Kangaroo from me, it just means David may have dropped the ball on your message and you should contact him again if you&amp;rsquo;re expecting a response.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequent kangaroos will be unaccompanied by explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details on exactly when to send kangaroos are still a work in progress. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to overwhelm anyone with kangaroos. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about some rules: (1) only send kangaroos if there was a message of non-trivial length, e.g. more than 20 characters, (2) only send a kangaroo after I&amp;rsquo;ve read the message; if I genuinely haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the message yet, no need for a kangaroo, as the message will still appear as unread in my inbox, (3) if you send follow-up messages, that resets the timer on the 2 hours, (4) any messages you send within 5 minutes of me sending you a message are ineligible for triggering kangaroos (this way I don&amp;rsquo;t need to get the last word), and (5) obviously, don&amp;rsquo;t send a kangaroo for a message I&amp;rsquo;ve already responded too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the rules of kangaroos are: You get a kangaroo if the &lt;strong&gt;most-recent&lt;/strong&gt; message in our chat is &lt;strong&gt;non-trivial&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;read-by-me&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;written-by-you&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;not an immediate reply&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;two-hours old&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why kangaroos? They bounce 🤷‍♂️ ? This is kind of like a message bouncing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a picture of a kangaroo, that is. Like this one: 🦘, or this: &lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FtBz98tV75N.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=66762cac-d0b0-43ba-91a8-eaefa6ef7626&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; It will not send them an actual real-life kangaroo. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notifications in Roam Research</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-25-notifications-in-roam-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-25-notifications-in-roam-research/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/RoamGames&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#RoamGames&lt;/a&gt; are upon us! The challenge: &lt;em&gt;project management&lt;/em&gt; in Roam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s talk notifications. They&amp;rsquo;re going to be essential for any multiplayer Roam scenario. They&amp;rsquo;re also ruthless attention vampires that kill productivity. We&amp;rsquo;ve got to get this right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s disentangle &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you get notified about, &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; you get notified about it, and &lt;em&gt;where/how&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re notified. This leads us to a vision where users can define &lt;em&gt;notification strategies&lt;/em&gt; and take control of their attention&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-notify-on-references-and-queries&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; to notify on (References and Queries)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we want to get notified about? First, three scenarios to motivate our discussion. Then, the primitives: references and queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scenario-1-chat&#34;&gt;Scenario 1, Chat:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re working on Secret Project X, conversing asynchronously with your teammate Abhay about Feature XX. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be big. While you&amp;rsquo;re off working on something else Abhay responds to a bunch of your earlier messages. You want to get notified about this, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scenario-2-blockers&#34;&gt;Scenario 2, Blockers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re working on Task A. But it&amp;rsquo;s blocked by Tasks B and C. You represent this in your Roam graph like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FjLpcHwI9aQ.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=eeb11581-2466-4824-a725-35a0bd720eff&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(As an aside, being able to embed a tiny piece of my Roam graph in my blog would be super helpful.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Task B and Task C are marked DONE, you want to get notified so you can resume working on Task A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scenario-3-topic-tracking&#34;&gt;Scenario 3, Topic Tracking:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re in a big multiplayer graph and you&amp;rsquo;ve carefully curated a page about your own project 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Python Fire&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;re excited when people talk about Fire, so you want notifications when people reference it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-primitives-references-and-queries&#34;&gt;The Primitives: References and Queries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic usage: Notifications when someone responds to me&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, notifications when someone references a particular page or block (linked or unlinked)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced usage: Roam queries and Datalog queries&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; are extremely expressive. I should be able to set up a query and get notified whenever the query results change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve set out what we want to get notified about, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about when we want to receive the notifications. We&amp;rsquo;ll get to how we want to configure the notifications a little bit later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-to-notify-immediately-batched-delayed-at-specific-times&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt; to notify (Immediately, Batched, Delayed, At specific times?)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most apps have minimal options for when you receive notifications. A typical message board config offers &amp;ldquo;every individual email&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;daily digest&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;weekly digest.&amp;rdquo; This is Roam. We can do better than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the messages from Abhay about Project XX, I want notifications to pop up immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I become unblocked on a task, I want a notification within the hour, but if multiple tasks become unblocked they the notifications can totally be bundled. I don&amp;rsquo;t need an &lt;em&gt;individual notification&lt;/em&gt; per task. That would just be overkill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for references to Python Fire, a daily digest at 9am is more than sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;primitive-notification-strategies&#34;&gt;Primitive: Notification Strategies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with a bit of JavaScript or Clojure knowledge can define a notification strategy. A notification strategy defines the rules for how notifications should be handled. The interface for a notification strategy is: stream of notifications in, stream of notifications out.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By allowing users to define and share notification strategies, we can empower uses to take back their attention and get more out of their Roam experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Notification strategies&amp;rdquo; approach benefits non-programmers too, because notification strategies can be shared in the Roam Depot&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for a future where RoamHacker and David Vargas and others have developed both simple and sophisticated &amp;ldquo;notification managers&amp;rdquo;: UIs where non-programmers can configure their notification settings in the level of detail best suited for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;primitive-tags-connect-references-and-queries-to-notification-strategies&#34;&gt;Primitive: Tags connect references and queries to notification strategies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, tags connect &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a notification strategy, you name it. Tag a reference of a query with the name of a notification strategy to run that strategy on that reference or query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s clarify with an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say I have a query (&amp;ldquo;all Tasks with &amp;lsquo;Blockers&amp;rsquo; where all Blockers are &amp;lsquo;DONE&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;), and a notification strategy named &amp;ldquo;Bundle on the Hour&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;bundle all incoming notifications and emit them on the hour as a single notification&amp;rdquo;). Then I can tag the query with #[[Bundle on the Hour]] to start applying that notification strategy to the results of the query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I&amp;rsquo;ve added that tag, the notification strategy will be called every time the query results change, and it will be able to start emitting notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly if I write [[Python Fire]] and tag it with #[[Digest at 9am]], then &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; notification strategy will be called whenever the references to or contents of the Python Fire page change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wherehow-actually-sending-notifications&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where/How&lt;/strong&gt;: Actually sending notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, we&amp;rsquo;ve talked about how to decide what to notify about, and when to send the notifications. How/where do the notifications actually get sent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sensible default for the first pass is to use browser notifications. But we&amp;rsquo;re thinking long term, so I won&amp;rsquo;t dwell on this &amp;ldquo;first pass&amp;rdquo; for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to use browser notifications, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do so&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. You can try this in your Roam graph (or browser console&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;function notify(text) {
  // Let&#39;s check if the browser supports notifications
  if (!(&amp;quot;Notification&amp;quot; in window)) {
    alert(text);
  }

  // Let&#39;s check whether notification permissions have already been granted
  else if (Notification.permission === &amp;quot;granted&amp;quot;) {
    // If it&#39;s okay let&#39;s create a notification
    var notification = new Notification(text);
  }

  // Otherwise, we need to ask the user for permission
  else if (Notification.permission !== &amp;quot;denied&amp;quot;) {
    Notification.requestPermission().then(function (permission) {
      // If the user accepts, let&#39;s create a notification
      if (permission === &amp;quot;granted&amp;quot;) {
        var notification = new Notification(text);
      } else {
        console.log(text);
      }
    });
  } else {
    // At last, if the user has denied notifications, and you
    // want to be respectful there is no need to bother them any more.
    console.log(text);
  }
}

notify(&amp;quot;You&#39;ve got mail.&amp;quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want browser notifications though. I want my personal digital assistant 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; to send me notifications. Now, this is no trouble in a private graph. I can use a webhook to send myself a message as Bieber Bot. In a public graph, however, this would be dangerous. Anyone could see the code and start impersonating Bieber Bot. A travesty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we need Roam to support &lt;em&gt;secrets&lt;/em&gt;. Ideally this would come from the Roam core team, not the community. First class secrets would enable me to write roam/js that communicates securely with my own services, like Bieber Bot and others, without giving other users the capability of doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an alternative approach to secrets, having all Roam graphs be &lt;em&gt;one giant graph&lt;/em&gt; with a good permissions model would also be sufficient. Then I could put my notifier code in my graph (private), but have the queries that trigger the notifier apply to a graph I share with my team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does specifying a notifier (browser notifications vs Bieber Bot) fit in with writing queries and enabling notifications? You can set your default &amp;ldquo;notify&amp;rdquo; function just by defining the function &amp;ldquo;notify&amp;rdquo; and tagging it / nesting it under roam/notify. You can also set a notify function whenever you define notifications just by adding an extra reference with the name of the notify function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-examples&#34;&gt;Some Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a lot, and reading the above it might sound complicated. And that&amp;rsquo;s because it &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be complicated; you can have as complicated a notification strategy as you like. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be complicated, and for most users it won&amp;rsquo;t be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally turning on notifications for messages could be as simple as adding a block in your graph that says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[[roam/messages]] #[[Notify me immediately]]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning on notifications for unblocked tasks could be as simple as (1) getting the unblocked tasks query from the Roam Depot, and then (2) adding a block &lt;code&gt;[[Unblocked tasks]] #[[Bundle on the Hour]]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And turning on notifications for references to Python Fire should simply mean adding a block &lt;code&gt;[[Python Fire]] #[[Digest at 9am]]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-build-it&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s build it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to build this with me? I&amp;rsquo;m 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@Bieber&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter and active as dbieber on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.slack.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And still provides sensible defaults and easy configs for non-power users. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one, while a basic use case, is actually tricky to express as a query. But we can do it, I&amp;rsquo;m confident. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-22-datalog-queries-for-roam-research/&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-04-more-datalog-queries-for-roam/&#34;&gt;snippets&lt;/a&gt; for lots of examples of what you can do with datalog queries. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;soni-sono&lt;/em&gt; for short. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has anyone taken the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fontmeme.com/the-home-depot-font/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Home Depot logo&lt;/a&gt; and replaced the word Home with Roam in the appropriate font yet? &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code courtesy of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/notification&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cmd-option-i to open your browser console on Chrome on Mac. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=how&amp;#43;to&amp;#43;open&amp;#43;the&amp;#43;browser&amp;#43;console&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Look it up here&lt;/a&gt; for other browsers or operating systems. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>am I available for conversation right now dot com</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-22-am-i-available-for-conversation-right-now-dot-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-22-am-i-available-for-conversation-right-now-dot-com/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I like this idea, but I&amp;rsquo;m giving it a try; I&amp;rsquo;ve added a &amp;ldquo;Now&amp;rdquo; page to my website (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/now/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;davidbieber.com/now&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for now pages is described at &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;&gt;https://nownownow.com/about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, a now page says what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the author&amp;rsquo;s life now. Not &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; that would be a &amp;ldquo;right now page&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; but rather, now in the broader sense of &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s are you up to these days?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&amp;rsquo;t about my new Now page though, which I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily plan to keep up (if the link 404s, you know why). Rather, this post is about an idea for a kind of &amp;ldquo;right now&amp;rdquo; page that I&amp;rsquo;m toying with building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a page that tells the reader if I&amp;rsquo;m likely available for a conversation &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d call it the &amp;ldquo;is David available to talk now&amp;rdquo; page, and here&amp;rsquo;s how it might work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-aims-only-to-give-a-best-guess-as-to-whether-i-can-talk-now&#34;&gt;It aims only to give a best guess as to whether I can talk now.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says No during work.&lt;br/&gt;
It says No during sleep hours.&lt;br/&gt;
It says No while I&amp;rsquo;m on a phone call / skype / zoom / meet etc&lt;br/&gt;
It says No if I have recently been on a call for a long time&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says Yes during explicitly set times (there would be a button I can press to set it to Yes for 30 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m deliberately in a public space (e.g. Gather Town, Clubhouse) AND looking for conversation (aka I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed the button), then it shows where to find me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rest of the time, it simply shrugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-would-i-want-such-a-system&#34;&gt;Why would I want such a system?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what I really want is for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; to use such a system. I want the &amp;ldquo;open door&amp;rdquo; system that professors so often use; if my door is open, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to come in and talk. I want to avoid people avoiding saying hi because they don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;m available. And I want to avoid the mental overhead of making plans for conversations that aren&amp;rsquo;t time sensitive. Plans are tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ideal system for when I want to talk to someone isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s pick a time to talk&amp;rdquo;, because that has scheduling overhead and will likely break up my day at an inconvenient time. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer a more flexible approach. When I&amp;rsquo;m free, I open my door (a digital, virtual, door). I send you a message that I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk; you see it when you&amp;rsquo;re free (because you have notifications disabled 👍). If I&amp;rsquo;m still free then, my door will still be open and we can talk. If I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on to another activity, my door will be closed and we&amp;rsquo;ll reconnect later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of doors, the &amp;ldquo;is David available to talk now&amp;rdquo; page is my idea for an approximation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how I would build it. The idea requires programmatically determining when I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the phone, in skype, in zoom, etc. I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into how approachable these services are to work with. And I likely won&amp;rsquo;t. This is the sort of idea that, while fun to entertain, will likely need to morph considerably before it turns into a real project. Such is the nature of the Snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugged directly into the internet</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-13-plugged-directly-into-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-13-plugged-directly-into-the-internet/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t do a lot of social media, and so over the holidays when I became active on several online discussion platforms simultaneously, I was a bit overwhelmed. I felt like I&amp;rsquo;d been plugged directly into the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, I enjoyed the conversation. I liked that there was always conversation happening. It skipped right over the step of &lt;em&gt;initiating&lt;/em&gt; a conversation, which requires an activation energy to cross. And it eliminated any need for &lt;em&gt;planning&lt;/em&gt; a conversation, which contributes to that activation energy requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was like drinking from a firehose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew that there was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lWNhg9qyTlQ?t=93&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;more to see than can ever be seen&lt;/a&gt;, but this experience lead me to reckon with that fact in a more tangible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getferdi.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ferdi&lt;/a&gt;, and loaded up all the old Slacks I&amp;rsquo;d ever been added to. I was able to log into both my Discord accounts simultaneously, and also discovered that there are &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; Discords about all sorts of things. Discourses too. And 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nano.page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;nano.page&lt;/a&gt;. Managed to mostly avoid Reddit. Signed into Gitter, which I previously rarely checked (so if you want to chat about Python Fire, join me 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/google/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;!) On top of those, and all the messaging apps I was already using before, I also fell into reading 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/&#34;&gt;my six infinite distractions&lt;/a&gt; more often. There were now more channels of information coming in than I could simultaneously keep in my head. My computer and I both ran out of RAM. Needed a reboot and a new strategy for dealing with these channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer RAM issue turned out to be easier than the personal RAM one. Ferdi supports &amp;ldquo;hibernating&amp;rdquo; chat services when they&amp;rsquo;re not in use. My computer can now keep up with the chatter; I still can&amp;rsquo;t. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Distraction Detection, at last</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-09-mobile-distraction-detection-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-09-mobile-distraction-detection-at-last/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have implemented a minimal working version of mobile &lt;em&gt;distraction detection&lt;/em&gt;, complete with a simple intervention for when I visit distracting websites on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-distraction-detection-do&#34;&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;distraction detection&amp;rdquo; do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It runs on my laptop and monitors my &lt;em&gt;phone&lt;/em&gt; for when I visit distracting websites. I give it a list of distracting websites for it to keep an eye out for. My list is: twitter, facebook, hacker news, google news, reddit, and youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can set it to perform some action whenever I&amp;rsquo;m on one of these websites. For this first iteration, I&amp;rsquo;m having Bieber Bot message me whenever it notices I&amp;rsquo;m on one of these websites. Now that it&amp;rsquo;s working though, it will be easy to customize to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In future iterations, I&amp;rsquo;ll have it wait until I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending several minutes on the website before messaging me, and I&amp;rsquo;ll only have it do this during times when I mean to be focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-this-interesting&#34;&gt;Why is this interesting?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are excellent browser extensions that help you take control of your browsing habits on your computer. I recommend DK&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getintention.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/a&gt; for this. However, there aren&amp;rsquo;t great solutions like Intention for mobile browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is that mobile browsers don&amp;rsquo;t provide good ways for developers to write extensions. I&amp;rsquo;ve built my mobile distraction detector in spite of this limitation :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use an iPhone and the Chrome browser. I&amp;rsquo;m logged into my Google Account on Chrome on both my phone and my laptop, and I have tab syncing turned on. With tab syncing, all my tab sessions from my phone are synced to my Google account, and are visible on my laptop, usually with a sub-minute latency. You can view this data in human-readable form at 
&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://history/syncedTabs&#34;&gt;chrome://history/syncedTabs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tab session data is stored along with the rest of my Chrome data. Since I use a Mac, the path is &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application\ Support/Google/Chrome/Profile\ 1/Sync\ Data/LevelDB/&lt;/code&gt;. Note that &amp;ldquo;Profile 1&amp;rdquo; may be replaced with either &amp;ldquo;Default&amp;rdquo;, or the name of your Profile, depending on how many Google accounts you have connected with Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is stored in a LevelDB database (this is unusual for Chrome; most of the rest of your Chrome data is stored in sqlite3 databases). LevelDB is an efficient key-value store, which was written by Jeff Dean and Sanjay Ghemawat back in 2011. The keys which contain the synced tab data are those prefixed with &amp;ldquo;session-dt&amp;rdquo;. The corresponding values are &lt;code&gt;SessionSpecifics&lt;/code&gt; protocol buffers. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/&amp;#43;/master:components/sync/protocol/session_specifics.proto&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The protocol buffer definition is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before parsing the sync data, I always make a copy of it first, and then I only ever open the copy. This ensures that Chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lock on the database, and isn&amp;rsquo;t editing it concurrently with my own program reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the Python library &lt;code&gt;plyvel&lt;/code&gt; to parse the LevelDB database: &lt;code&gt;db = plyvel.DB(path_to_copy_of_leveldb_directory)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to use the protobuf definition, I compiled it first with protoc: &lt;code&gt;protoc -I chromium/ chromium/components/sync/protocol/*.proto --python_out=dbieber/distraction_detection/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting these pieces together, accessing the session data looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import plyvel
from components.sync.protocol import session_specifics_pb2

db = plyvel.DB(path)

for key, value in db.iterator():
  if b&#39;sessions-dt&#39; in key:
	session = session_specifics_pb2.SessionSpecifics.FromString(value)

db.close()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, the key remaining piece to understand is how to figure out which tabs are open on which devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the SessionSpecifics protos has an attribute: &lt;code&gt;session_tag&lt;/code&gt; which uniquely identifies a session. For each &lt;code&gt;session_tag&lt;/code&gt;, there is a single SessionSpecifics proto with a &lt;code&gt;client_name&lt;/code&gt; attribute: this indicates which device the session lives on. Each of the remaining SessionSpecifics protos with that same tag correspond to a single tab, and the currently open URL for that tab comes from &lt;code&gt;session.tab.navigation[-1].virtual_url&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of matching the URLs against my list of distracting websites, and sending the data off to Bieber Bot. Distractions, detected. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tweak my own distraction detection setup to something that makes sense for me. Instead of immediate messages from Bieber Bot, I&amp;rsquo;ll have him try to keep my total senseless scrolling for a day to a moderate amount. I&amp;rsquo;ll have him be particularly vigilant about helping me keep my morning scrolling from going on too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also send this snippet around to folks interested in building similar tools. While I won&amp;rsquo;t be turning this into a product for the masses, I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that the method does get picked up by projects like Intention, ActivityWatch, and other tools that aim to help people maintain healthy browsing habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge that with account syncing, rich data about your mobile browsing is available on your computer. So today, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much tooling that takes advantage of this. If you work on a product in this space, well, now you&amp;rsquo;ve had a glimpse of what data&amp;rsquo;s available and what it can do. Consider using this approach to extend the reach of your product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distraction detection: Proto acquired!</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-08-distraction-detection-proto-acquired/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-08-distraction-detection-proto-acquired/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;inching&lt;/strong&gt; my way toward writing a distraction detector that will allow Bieber Bot to notice when I&amp;rsquo;m distracted on my phone and stage an intervention. (Wow!, I first pitched this idea (to myself) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history/&#34;&gt;in one of my very first snippets&lt;/a&gt;, back in 2019.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-01-programmatically-accessing-chromes-tabs-from-other-devices-data/&#34;&gt;I figured out where Chrome&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tabs from other devices&amp;rdquo; data is stored&lt;/a&gt;. However, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t parse the data because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the protocol buffer definition being used was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I heard back from someone who works on Chrome. I&amp;rsquo;ve acquired the proto definitions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/&amp;#43;/master:components/sync/protocol/session_specifics.proto&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;proto definitions are here&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/&amp;#43;/master:components/sync_sessions/session_store.cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the code that persists the data to disk is here&lt;/a&gt;. I can successfully bulid the protos (using protoc) and I can parse my session data from the leveldb database. Progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble now is my phone seems to have stopped syncing its tabs two days ago. Weird! One more mystery to solve I guess&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition in Roam Research</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-02-spaced-repetition-in-roam-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-02-spaced-repetition-in-roam-research/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to do spaced repetition in Roam Research. This post describes mine. I was inspired to start this two months ago by reading 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic on spaced repetition&lt;/a&gt;, and I highly recommend the read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spaced repetition&amp;rdquo; just means studying flashcards, studying the cards you know best less often, and study the cards you struggle with more often. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful technique for learning and remembering material, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a student or a lifelong learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system I use is based on a classic system called the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; method. I&amp;rsquo;ll first describe how to use the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; approach in Roam, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the adjustments I made to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-a-leitner-box&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; system of spaced repetition, there are seven boxes numbered Box 1 through Box 7. When you create a flashcard, you place it into Box 1. Every day, you use a schedule to determine which boxes of cards to review. The cards in box 1 get reviewed most often, and the cards in box 7 get reviewed least often. When you review a card, you move it up a box (e.g. from box 1 to 2 or from box 4 to 5) if you get the card right. But if you get a card wrong, you move the card back to box 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default Leitner Box schedule looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FpW7FsufOIr.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=3cbd07b1-11e5-4389-896d-9a181f6529fc&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you read this schedule?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colored circles represent the different Leitner Boxes. The red circles represent Box 1, the orange circles represent Box 2, the yellow circles represent Box 3, all the way up to the final pink circle that represents Box 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers along the bottom are &amp;ldquo;session numbers&amp;rdquo;. For your first review session, you look at the circles above &amp;ldquo;01&amp;rdquo; (Boxes 2 and 1). For your second review session, you look at the circles above &amp;ldquo;02&amp;rdquo; (Boxes 3 and 1). Always review boxes for a given day in order from highest to lowest. After completing session &amp;ldquo;64&amp;rdquo;, the schedule wraps around and your next session is session &amp;ldquo;01&amp;rdquo; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap, (1) you put new flashcards into Box 1. (2) When you get a card correct, you move it up a box. (3) When you get a card incorrect, you move it all the way back to Box 1. (4) You use the schedule made of colored dots to decide which boxes to review each day, answering questions in higher boxes first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-leitner-boxes-in-roam&#34;&gt;Setting up Leitner Boxes in Roam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system is all well and good. How do we put it into practice? Here I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly describe (1) getting set up, (2) creating new flashcards, and (3) how to do a review session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up:&lt;/strong&gt; You can use my template; simply copy and paste the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/GPfhcUug&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; text at the bottom of the page here&lt;/a&gt; into Roam Research, e.g. onto a new page named &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo;. For this to work you need to copy from the region that says &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;RAW paste data&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/zvjFKZAb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;get the enhanced template (recommended; see below) here&lt;/a&gt;. Again, be sure to copy from the region that says &amp;ldquo;RAW paste data&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default template creates a page for each of the seven Leitner boxes. It also puts the default schedule on the page, and gives you a place to keep track of what session number you&amp;rsquo;re up to. It will also add two questions to your Leitner Box 1 (one about avocados, and one about Cloze deletions), and includes some basic instructions for how to do spaced repetition in Roam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating New Flashcards:&lt;/strong&gt; You can create a new card anywhere in your Roam graph simply by tagging a note with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo;. Here are two ways to create cards in Roam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the question on one bullet, and put the answer in the child bullets. Then tag the bullet with the question with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo; to add it to your spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the syntax {{=: question | answer}} in Roam to create text that remains hidden until clicked. The text &amp;ldquo;answer&amp;rdquo; won&amp;rsquo;t appear until you click on the text &amp;ldquo;question.&amp;rdquo; Again, tag the line with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo; to add it to your spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend you 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/prompts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s notes on &amp;ldquo;How to write good prompts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for tips on how to create good flashcards. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic: &amp;ldquo;How to Remember Anything Forever-ish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; also has good suggestions for how to create good questions for spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to do a Review Session:&lt;/strong&gt; Visit your &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo; page to figure out what session number to do. Increment the session number, and use the schedule to determine which Leitner boxes you&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at in this session. Remember, do the Leitner boxes in decreasing order of their number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each Leitner box, visit its page in Roam. All your questions will appear in the Linked References section of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go through the questions one by one. If you get the answer correct, increment the box number by 1. If you get the answer incorrect or struggle with it, set the tag back to &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about sending things back to box 1; you&amp;rsquo;ll see those questions very often and soon they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in the higher numbered boxes again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enhancements-beyond-the-default-system&#34;&gt;Enhancements Beyond the Default System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made several changes to the default Leitner Box system to improve it to my taste. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to use them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leitner Boxes 0 and $\infty$:&lt;/strong&gt; I use an extra box, &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box 0&amp;rdquo; for flashcards that I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to put into my rotation yet. I try to only add at most 10 cards a day to keep the total review workload low. If I have more cards than this, I keep them in Box 0 until I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start studying them, at which point I move them to Box 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leitner Box $\infty$ is for cards that have graduated from Box 7. In theory, I will remember these cards for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra box 5s, 6s, and 7s:&lt;/strong&gt; I have decided to create two Box 5s (named 5A and 5B), four Box 6s (6A, 6B, 6C, and 6D), and eight Box 7s (7A through 7H). This prevents any individual review session from accumulating too many cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran a simulation and under the default system, adding 10 new cards a day and getting 95% of cards correct, some review sessions will require reviewing over 700 cards! Under the enhanced system, the longest review session will only ever be 140 cards (and most review sessions are much shorter than that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the modified schedule that allows me to use these extra boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2F_dSM-MMp85.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=b3682748-8ea4-4444-97df-0c4592beb1ff&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FhFRPfzGpwy.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=20b7f689-4117-4901-a806-846b0d099d7d&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this enhanced schedule, first use the review session number to figure out which column of colored circles to look at. As before, a red circle indicates Leitner Box 1, a yellow circle indicates Leitner Box 2, etc. If the circle has a letter inside it, that means to review that particular variant of the box. E.g. a blue circle with a &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; inside means to review Leitner box 5B. The arrow to the right of a box indicates which box you should move the card to if you get it correct. E.g. in review session &amp;ldquo;51&amp;rdquo; you should review box 5B and move correct cards to box 6D; you should then review boxes 2 and 1 as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed the box list:&lt;/strong&gt; I use Roam Research&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;embed block&amp;rdquo; feature to embed a list of all Leitner Boxes onto all my Leitner Box pages. This makes it easy to quickly navigate from any box to any other box. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a good way to include this in the template, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to add this yourself if you want to include it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/zvjFKZAb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;access the enhanced version of the template here&lt;/a&gt;. It includes more Leitner boxes and the more complicated schedule. To use it, simply paste it into a new page in Roam Research, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spaced-repetition-alternatives&#34;&gt;Spaced Repetition Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways of doing spaced repetition in Roam, of which this is just one. Note that most spaced repetition systems in Roam Research use the &amp;ldquo;delta&amp;rdquo; feature. However, we are not using this feature. CortexFutura provides 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cortexfutura.com/preliminary-spaced-repetition-roam/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a way of using the delta feature for spaced repetition here&lt;/a&gt;. Roam Toolkit provides another system for doing spaced repetition in Roam, which you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=08o8q_bOedw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view on YouTube here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular spaced repetition systems is called 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s great for language learning. I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss not to mention it. The reason I prefer doing spaced repetition directly in Roam is that the friction to creating cards is much lower in Roam for me, since I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes and writing my ideas in there already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally RemNote, a competitor note-taking tool to Roam, also offers a highly configurable spaced repetition system out-of-the-box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, consider joining the conversation in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam Research Slack&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;spaced-repetition&amp;rdquo; channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-advantages-of-this-system-over-traditional-spaced-repetition-systems&#34;&gt;Two advantages of this system over traditional spaced repetition systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower friction:&lt;/strong&gt; Creating cards directly in your note-taking app is substantially easier than needing to task switch to create cards. This lower mental overhead makes it easier to keep using spaced repetition for an extended period of time. I started using it two months ago myself, so finger&amp;rsquo;s crossed it indeed is something I keep up for much longer! 🤞&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robustness to vacations:&lt;/strong&gt; In traditional spaced repetition systems, taking a break for a day, week, or month, can be ruinous to your spaced repetition rhythm. After coming back from the break, you find you have too many cards to review all at once, which can be a real motivation drain. Instead of organizing cards by &lt;strong&gt;date&lt;/strong&gt;, my system organizes them by &lt;strong&gt;review session number.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that if you skip a day or a week, your reviews simply get pushed back. The review session number won&amp;rsquo;t go up while you&amp;rsquo;re away. You can even split a review session over multiple days if you like. No trouble! You&amp;rsquo;ll never be left with a review session that&amp;rsquo;s too big to handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic: &amp;ldquo;How to Remember Anything Forever-ish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is what inspired me to start using spaced repetition in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://withorbit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Orbit&amp;rdquo; system&lt;/a&gt; enables writers to incorporate spaced repetition directly into their writing, to help their readers remember what they learned forever. You can read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://quantum.country/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quantum Country&lt;/a&gt; to learn quantum computing and give it a try. You could also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/prompts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read his tips for &amp;ldquo;How to write good prompts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which is also written with Orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;get Anki here&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.remnote.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;try RemNote here&lt;/a&gt;. I also have a dozen+ other 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;snippets about Roam here&lt;/a&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducing-snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s a “snippet”?&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a good discussion about spaced repetition. You can email me at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;spaced-repetition@gmail.com&#34;&gt;david810+spaced-repetition@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, find me on Twitter (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/@Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@Bieber&lt;/a&gt;), or join the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam slack&lt;/a&gt; to keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically Accessing Chrome&#39;s “Tabs from other devices” Data</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-01-programmatically-accessing-chromes-tabs-from-other-devices-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-01-programmatically-accessing-chromes-tabs-from-other-devices-data/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use Google Chrome on my Mac laptop and on my iPhone, and I&amp;rsquo;m logged in to my Google account in both places with syncing turned on. If I go to &amp;ldquo;chrome://history/syncedTabs&amp;rdquo; on my computer I can see what tabs I have open on my phone. Now, I&amp;rsquo;d like to access this data programatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out that this data is stored in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Profile 1/Sync Data/LevelDB/&lt;/code&gt; (Probably for most people the path would be &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Default/Sync Data/LevelDB/&lt;/code&gt;). Be careful to escape the spaces in the file path!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read from a LevelDB database, I first installed leveldb with &lt;code&gt;brew install leveldb&lt;/code&gt;, and then I installed a Python LevelDB client: &lt;code&gt;pip install plyvel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then use little Python scripts like the following to access the data, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite figured out (1) how to properly parse the data; it&amp;rsquo;s probably a protocol buffer, or (2) exactly how it&amp;rsquo;s organized, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly which keys to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I have copied the LevelDB folder to a new location before opening it. This ensures that Chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lock on any of the files in the copy, and that even if we make a mistake we won&amp;rsquo;t damage Chrome&amp;rsquo;s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import plyvel
import re
import os

db = plyvel.DB(os.path.expanduser(&amp;quot;~/Profile1/Sync Data/LevelDB/&amp;quot;))

for key, value in db.iterator():
  if b&#39;sessions-dt&#39; in key:
    data = re.findall(b&#39;https?://[\x20-\x7F]+&#39;, value)
    if data:
      print(key)
      print(data)
      print()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script prints out the URLs of the synced tabs, plus some extra data and extra characters. To do this properly, the next step will be to figure out how to parse the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I want to programmatically figure out which tabs are open on my phone? I want to do automatic distraction detection. When I&amp;rsquo;m on a distracting website like Twitter for several minutes during a period when I mean to be focusing on something else, I&amp;rsquo;d like Bieber Bot to be able to stage an intervention to help me focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A variation on the script above should be sufficient for figuring out if I have any distracting websites open on my phone. So, I may be able to implement the distraction detection and intervention logic even before getting the parsing done correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Distractions and Getting a Good Sear</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days I have six &amp;ldquo;infinite distractions&amp;rdquo; — things I do mindlessly that are roughly limitless in content. They are: YouTube, YCombinator News, Google News, Reddit, Facebook, and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these are new additions to my repertoire, added I expect in response to my efforts to suppress viewing the others.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to try a strategy of writing down the distraction rather than attending to it whenever I am drawn to it. Additionally, when my brain craves something like this, I&amp;rsquo;m going to make an effort to do one of the following instead: reaching out to to a friend, or going down the rabbit hole on a particular topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former is just healthy. The latter I think satisfies the same brain cravings as e.g. mindless going on YouTube. But by selecting the topic to dive into deliberately rather than letting the whims of the YouTube/Reddit/etc algorithm select the content for me, I expect a few benefits. I expect the time will feel more valuable to me after the fact, I&amp;rsquo;ll learn something I care about, and I will remember better what I learned because it will be more connected to itself and my interests, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried this last night and learned about how to get a good sear (in brief: dry the protein, let it cool if it just cooked, and don’t move it around while searing).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Mobile Website: News Feed in Chronological Order</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-06-28-facebook-chronological-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-06-28-facebook-chronological-order/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On your phone, you can navigate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&lt;/a&gt; to view your News Feed on the Facebook website in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also excellent apps for hiding your Facebook News Feed if you find it draining on your attention, but unfortunately they don&amp;rsquo;t work on mobile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hidefeed.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hide Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/news-feed-eradicator-for/fjcldmjmjhkklehbacihaiopjklihlgg?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Facebook News Feed Eradicator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these don&amp;rsquo;t work on the Facebook mobile website, I&amp;rsquo;ve turned to this new strategy to combat the attention draining nature of News Feed: only viewing my feed in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By switching to chronological order, the &amp;ldquo;infinite scroll&amp;rdquo; of the News Feed is interrupted because either you eventually get to posts you&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, or you notice the timestamp of the posts you&amp;rsquo;re looking at slowly rising. You also get a more complete picture of what content is available, which helps fight the constant &amp;ldquo;just one more post&amp;rdquo; feeling that drives infinite scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you switch your news feed to chronological order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main Facebook website, you can click the three dots next to &amp;ldquo;News Feed&amp;rdquo; and choose &amp;ldquo;Most Recent&amp;rdquo;. However, you have to choose this option every time you visit Facebook, which can be frustrating. So instead, navigate directly to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Facebook mobile website, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an option to view posts in chronological order. Instead, you can achieve this by accessing the desktop website on your phone. Go to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/home.php?sk=h_chr&lt;/a&gt; to get the Desktop version of Facebook on your phone, with chronological order already enabled. Bookmark the page and use it as your primary way of accessing Facebook on your phone to get chronological order as your News Feed default from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Pico</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-03-14-principles-of-pico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-03-14-principles-of-pico/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an attempt at capturing and organizing my thoughts on Pico, from our conversation about it March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, an attempt at an overview of the Pico system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You enter cards through a variety of sources. You can enter cards manually, like flash cards. You can also import cards from your note taking software. Cards can also be created from your contacts list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, Pico shows you these cards in an Anki-meets-Tinder swipe-based spaced repetition manner. You get a stack of cards, and each card presents you with a suggested action you should take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with idea X from your notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to person Y from your contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a passage from book Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to perform the action on the card, swiping right. Or you can ignore the card and get the next one on the stack by swiping left. The app automatically learns which cards are good to show you. Ideally it helps you to read more, to reengage with your own ideas over time, and to keep in touch with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of things to like about this! I&amp;rsquo;m now going to take a stab at separating out the goals of Pico, the mechanism of Pico, and the specific tasks that Pico targets today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distilling-the-principles-of-pico&#34;&gt;Distilling the Principles of Pico&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals are noble. At a high level, Pico aims to help you spend less time on addictive websites with infinite scroll, and more time doing things that matter to you. I applaud anything that sets out to help you reclaim your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think mentally it helps to separate the mechanism of managing attention that Pico provides from the specific tasks it helps its users to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism seems to operate around these three principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;offloaded memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entropy injection (offloaded decision making)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific tasks it helps with are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brainstorming / reengaging with old ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(re)connecting with people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;studying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the mechanism is general enough that other specific tasks can easily be slotted in as cards in the Pico system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, stop me if I&amp;rsquo;ve misrepresented Pico so far. Let me tell you what I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-purposeness&#34;&gt;General Purposeness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Pico has some really solid ideas underlying it. Particularly I find the idea of using spaced repetition to reengage with your ideas quite compelling.
The idea of using cards to dive into passages of books is also appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using spaced repetition to reengage with your friends seems a tricky thing to get right, since it risks dehumanizing the relationships without special care taken both by the developer (you) and the user of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these different types of cards seems like it comes with lots of room for domain specific tailoring. For example, if a card represents a passage of a book, the user may want to quickly dive into the full book (not just the passage), and then to create a new card at the end of their reading session so they can continue reading from where they left off later.
If a card represents an idea from my notes, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to read the surrounding notes in my note taking software, where I&amp;rsquo;m best able to engage with the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting each of these domains right in a single app (or through clean interactions with other systems) seems like a difficult challenge, but potentially quite rewarding if done well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-entry&#34;&gt;Data Entry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect the usability of Pico will be a big part of what makes the Pico experience pleasant or not. Data entry and the whole card creation process seems like one of the tricky things to get right. If I want to create cards for studying, based on my notes, then I&amp;rsquo;ll want to be taking those notes in some other software (unless you&amp;rsquo;re also building a Roam / RemNote competitor too!). Going from this other software into Pico can be challenging because there are many possible &amp;ldquo;other softwares&amp;rdquo; that people could be coming from and many possible formats people could be taking notes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the book reading case, the experience I would want would be that when I&amp;rsquo;m reading a PDF or eBook a card is automatically created for each book I&amp;rsquo;ve opened, that is automatically kept up to date with the part of the book that I&amp;rsquo;m up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overwhelmed-by-cards&#34;&gt;Overwhelmed by Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thought comes from my inexperience with spaced-repetition software systems. It seems like with traditional spaced repetition algorithms, it can be easy to get overwhelmed by a backlog of cards to review if you take a few days (or heavens forbid a week!) off of review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing spaced repetition in Roam Research using an adhoc system I threw together for myself using Browserflow. Instead of having specific days on which to review cards, they get reviewed in a specific review session. If I skip a day, all future review sessions just come a day later; the backlog doesn&amp;rsquo;t grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pico is a method for spending your time with intention. This is fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding of the &amp;ldquo;Principles of Pico&amp;rdquo; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend less time on things you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be doing (Facebook, Twitter, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time on things you do want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use external mechanisms and automation to guide you toward these good uses of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use gamification to increase time spent on these productive uses of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn from experience what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with your own ideas using spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with people using spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn things via spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 100% on board with these principles and am very excited to see where Pico lands a year from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heads up that I wrote most of this snippet back on March 14, 2020, and then only finished it up and published it today December 20, 2020. So, forgive the delay and let&amp;rsquo;s continue the conversation some time in the next ten months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Assistant Tool Idea</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</guid>
      
        <message>A structured question-asking tool may be useful for writing effectively.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-writing-is-hard&#34;&gt;Background: Writing is Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I find writing feels easy &amp;ndash; e.g. when 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;writing for no audience&lt;/a&gt;, when writing something you&amp;rsquo;ve already thought extensively about, when telling a story in a logical order that you&amp;rsquo;re deeply familiar with. Other times, I find writing very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m writing a paper, I am writing explicitly for an audience, the story is not always clear immediately, and the material is something I&amp;rsquo;m becoming familiar with over time, not something about which I&amp;rsquo;m already deeply familiar.
So, I find paper writing hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an idea that I think will help me write more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s a software tool that structures the time you spend writing. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the tool, but I don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate building it. Perhaps we can come up with a low-resource version of this idea, e.g. with paper and pencil, that I can try even without building this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-writing-system&#34;&gt;The Writing System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool presents you with a prompt, a textbox, and a timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial prompt is &amp;ldquo;What do you want to write about?&amp;rdquo;, and the initial timer is for 5 minutes. Subsequent prompts will be determined from what you&amp;rsquo;ve entered in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the textbox, you are encouraged to respond to the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of your response, you can issue some commands / keywords.
If you start a line with &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;, then that line will get used as a future prompt.
You can specify the relative importance of a future prompt by including a priority.
This will determine the order in which you are presented with the prompts.
E.g. &lt;code&gt;!0&lt;/code&gt; is highest priority, and so such a line will become the next prompt you receive, unless there are other priority 0 prompts already queued up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;! &amp;lt;topic&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I want to write about later&amp;rdquo;
&lt;code&gt;? &amp;lt;question&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;question&amp;gt; is a question I want to answer later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should also be a way to indicate &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I&amp;rsquo;ll need to do more research on&amp;rdquo;, and then for one of the prompts to be about spending time researching a topic, rather than writing about it. Then the next prompt may be to write about what you just learned in the research section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other available commands include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:pause&lt;/code&gt; to stop the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:unpause&lt;/code&gt; to start the timer again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:extend&lt;/code&gt; to add additional time to the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:next&lt;/code&gt; to skip to the next prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is easily extensible, so a writer with a programming background can easily add new commands, or modify the logic that determines when prompts are shown and when breaks are taken. A programming-proficient writer will also have programmatic access to everything they write, as well as the corresponding prompts and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the timer reaches 0, a short break is initiated, and then the next prompt is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to move quickly, and get all your thoughts onto the page, without getting bogged down in a DFS traversal of information about a single line of the overall text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-details&#34;&gt;Additional details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every keystroke is logged, so if you write something, and then switch to a new version of it, you will still be able to see the original version. No need to worry about pasting in a password though, since the keylogging data is readily accessible in a plaintext format and you can edit it directly e.g. if anything sensitive does leak in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has a decent amount of overlap with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt; project that I&amp;rsquo;ve already built,
and perhaps a version of this new idea could be easily added to the shh shell. Alternatively, the shh-shell could be forked to build this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar integration would be cool, so that it times your prompts nicely if you have a meeting coming up so you get to a good break point in time for your meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation-thoughts&#34;&gt;Implementation Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to build this onto an existing text editor, rather than writing my own. E.g. using Google Docs would be good.
However, the disadvantage of this is that it makes the keystroke logging feature more difficult. Fortunately, Google Docs does have good history tracking. Google Docs also provides good programmatic access. So, an agent running in the background while you write could be taking periodic snapshots too. Such an agent could also be extracting the commands and prompts you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to execute the commands immediately, the way shh shell does. For some commands this may be a real disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like the idea of the agent giving the prompts being Bieber Bot &amp;ndash; that is, being the same &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; as my personal digital assistant. I can picture it asking me &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve been writing continuously for over an hour; is it time for a break?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it looks like you stopped writing abruptly there, did you get distracted?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-experimentation&#34;&gt;Initial Experimentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying the idea out in a low-tech way (manually timing things, manually looking up what the next prompt should be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the main issue I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the first half hour of testing. When the time runs out for a prompt, I&amp;rsquo;m still in the middle of the prompt. I&amp;rsquo;ve usually started expounding on some idea relevant to the prompt, and there are actually several ideas remaining that I haven&amp;rsquo;t even started exploring for the prompt yet. So what should have happened / what should I do next time? Maybe I could have done a higher level discussion of the prompt and made new future sub-prompts along the way. Or at the end of a section, I could have the system give me a bit of time to create sub-prompts of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to address in the section but didn&amp;rsquo;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see having a limited time to create new prompts be a good forcing function for coming up with structured high level thinking after a moderate amount of time of lower level writing. So in my next round of testing, I&amp;rsquo;ll try this, and continue to iterate on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do in Moments of Internet Addiction</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-moments-of-internet-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-moments-of-internet-addiction/</guid>
      
        <message>A brainstorming of potential activities to help combat mild internet addiction.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often feel addicted to YouTube, TV shows, browsing HackerNews, or social media.
When I do, I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to just keep scrolling or watching, and I can waste hours on the internet.
Afterward, and even during, I may feel an inclination to stop, but I continue consuming content anyway.
It feels unhealthy, and I generally regret when I spend my time this way.
For some reason, I do it anyway though, and so I think of this habit like an addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and fall into these unhealthy attention-consuming rabbit holes, here is a list of things we can do instead of continuing the addictive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing; doing &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; is a perfectly valid option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say hi to a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go for a walk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monologue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make plans for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate HALT (hungry? angry? lonely? tired?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-02-pyd-swyt-cf-bh-din&#34;&gt;pyd-swyt; cf-bh-din&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history&#34;&gt;toying with&lt;/a&gt; the idea of getting Bieber Bot to notice when I&amp;rsquo;m exhibiting addictive behavior. If I can get that working, I&amp;rsquo;d love for Bieber Bot to notice when I&amp;rsquo;m addicted to YouTube, Hacker News, or Twitter and suggest one of the above activities for me to perform instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning to Analyze My Browsing History</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-analyzing-my-browser-history/</guid>
      
        <message>I started a plan to analyze my browser history. This was my plan.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned recently that programmatically accessing your browsing history is rather straightforward. Really exciting! This is rich data, from which I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to learn a lot and hopefully combat unwanted distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let me describe what information is available, and how you can access it. Then, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss what you can do with this data. As I&amp;rsquo;ve written about previously 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2019-12-29-track-your-life-in-a-spreadsheet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;, I already have a chat bot system in place, which will be able to take advantage of this data to e.g. help me stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;accessing-your-browser-history&#34;&gt;Accessing Your Browser History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to GitHub user 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dropmeaword&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dropmeaword&lt;/a&gt; for compiling 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dropmeaword/9372cbeb29e8390521c2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt; explaining how to access your browser history via sqlite3. The gist covers Safari, Chrome, and Firefox. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll just focus on Chrome on OSX, since that&amp;rsquo;s my primary mode of browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Chrome browsing history is located at &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Default/History&lt;/code&gt;. Since I use multiple profiles in Chrome, each profile gets its own browsing history, e.g. located at &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Profile 1/History&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each browsing history is stored as a sqlite3 database. Before analyzing the data, I recommend making a copy of it (&lt;code&gt;cp ~/Library/Application\ Support/Google/Chrome/Default/History my-history&lt;/code&gt;); this way your history database (a) won&amp;rsquo;t be locked by Chrome while you&amp;rsquo;re trying to access it, and (b) won&amp;rsquo;t change while you&amp;rsquo;re looking at it, which could cause confusion and inconsistencies in your results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you can browse it interactively using the sqlite3 REPL by running &lt;code&gt;sqlite3 PATH_TO_DATABASE&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also libraries available for accessing sqlite3 databases in just about every language. For Python, there&amp;rsquo;s the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/sqlite3.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sqlite3&lt;/a&gt; library. Go has 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/github.com/mattn/go-sqlite3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;go-sqlite3&lt;/a&gt;. JavaScript has 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlitetutorial.net/sqlite-nodejs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this sqlite3 module&lt;/a&gt;. However you most like scripting, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a familiar way of accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-available-data&#34;&gt;The Available Data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running sqlite3 macro &lt;code&gt;.tables&lt;/code&gt;, we see the following tables are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;meta&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;urls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads_slices&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segment_usage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_source&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads_url_chains&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;keyword_search_terms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;typed_url_sync_metadata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be most interested in the &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;visits&lt;/code&gt; tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; table has these columns (found with &lt;code&gt;.schema urls&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the URL in the database.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;url&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The URL of the website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;title&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The title of website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The number of times you&amp;rsquo;ve visited the URL.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;typed_count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The number of times you&amp;rsquo;ve visited the URL by typing in the address (as opposed to by following a link.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;last_visit_time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (microseconds since the epoch)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The time of the most recent to the URL.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;hidden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boolean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what this is about.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;code&gt;visits&lt;/code&gt; table has these columns (obtained via &lt;code&gt;.schema visits&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the visit in the database.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;url&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the url in the &lt;code&gt;urls&lt;/code&gt; table.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (milliseconds since the epoch)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The time of the visit.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;from_visit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the visit that lead you to this one.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;transition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bit vector&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Represents the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/history#transition_types&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;transition type&lt;/a&gt; (how you got to the URL)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;segment_id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer Id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; of the segment in the database. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure what a segment is, but there is a &lt;code&gt;segments&lt;/code&gt; table you can look at.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;visit_duration&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integer (microseconds)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The amount of time spent at the website, or 0 if not available.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;incremented_omnibox_typed_score&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boolean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I do not know what this is about.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, we can access every visit to every website that we&amp;rsquo;ve made since the last time we cleared our browsing history. We can see what website we visited (&lt;code&gt;visits.url&lt;/code&gt;), when we visited it (&lt;code&gt;visits.visit_time&lt;/code&gt;), how many times we&amp;rsquo;ve visited it (&lt;code&gt;urls.visit_count&lt;/code&gt;), and how long each visit was for (&lt;code&gt;visits.visit_duration&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can even use &lt;code&gt;visits.from_visit&lt;/code&gt; to figure out what website linked us to each url, if that interests us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-can-we-deduce&#34;&gt;What Can We Deduce?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can (1) perform a historical analysis on the data, as well as (2) do real-time monitoring of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I brainstorm some of the historical trends we will be able to uncover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most frequently visited websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites where we spend the majority of our time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites that frequently lead to known-distractor websites (e.g. Reddit, Hacker News, Twitter, YouTube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can do an analysis by time of day (or day of week), to figure out what sites occupy my time late at night vs during daylight hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are somewhat interesting, but what I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited for is the ongoing analysis that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; can provide by accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a brainstorm of the more real-time actionable insights we might extract from this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bieber Bot could ping me if it looks like I&amp;rsquo;m spending too much time on a distraction website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He could try to detect if I went to a website with a particular purpose, but ended up getting distracted and not completing the purpose I set out to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if I&amp;rsquo;m on a productive website and then switch to a distraction website for more than a few minutes, particularly during work hours, Bieber Bot might message asking if I got distracted. Think you could do that for me Bieber Bot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could signal that I want to view a website later by opening it and immediately closing it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps we could detect if I&amp;rsquo;m researching a particular topic, and then Bieber Bot could try to help me with my research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-idea&#34;&gt;Related Idea&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reduce distractions, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to switch my browsing mode from &amp;ldquo;clicking opens links&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;clicking saves a link for later&amp;rdquo;. When in this new mode, whenever I click a link it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t open that link; instead, it would save the link to a list of deferred links.
Then I would be able to view my &amp;ldquo;saved for later&amp;rdquo; links when I have time that I&amp;rsquo;ve explicitly set aside, rather than during the time that I would rather be doing something more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve done a little bit of manual exploration of my browsing history data. I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a little Python script to be able to access the data programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I&amp;rsquo;ll do more manual analysis, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I&amp;rsquo;m able to give Bieber Bot the real-time access to the data that I described above. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited to see if I can get the &amp;ldquo;looks like you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten distracted&amp;rdquo; messages set up with Bieber Bot. As a bonus, since Bieber Bot can message other people too, this system could help me leverage social accountability to stay on task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see where this project leads? You can subscribe for infrequent email updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{
    background:#fff;
    clear:left;
    font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://gmail.us3.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75&amp;amp;id=132f89def3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_a55774562ae9fa9a1d879fa75_132f89def3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
      &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39; src=&#39;//s3.amazonaws.com/downloads.mailchimp.com/js/mc-validate.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;(function($) {window.fnames = new Array(); window.ftypes = new Array();fnames[0]=&#39;EMAIL&#39;;ftypes[0]=&#39;email&#39;;fnames[1]=&#39;FNAME&#39;;ftypes[1]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[2]=&#39;LNAME&#39;;ftypes[2]=&#39;text&#39;;fnames[3]=&#39;ADDRESS&#39;;ftypes[3]=&#39;address&#39;;fnames[4]=&#39;PHONE&#39;;ftypes[4]=&#39;phone&#39;;fnames[5]=&#39;BIRTHDAY&#39;;ftypes[5]=&#39;birthday&#39;;}(jQuery));var $mcj = jQuery.noConflict(true);&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>