<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ask-me-anywhere on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/ask-me-anywhere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ask-me-anywhere on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/ask-me-anywhere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chat by Tag</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-06-20-chat-by-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-06-20-chat-by-tag/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a comments section on my website, but I do like when people reach out to me by email.
I am thinking about an idea for adding chat to my website, but the experience I have in mind is different from any chat or comments section that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about and why &amp;ndash; please do let me know if it exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each snippet there would be a badge for each tag associated with that snippet, as there already is today.
Each badge would indicate that there is a chat thread available for that tag.
E.g. it would show the number of active users and amount of recent activity in the chatroom.
Clicking the badge would take you to the tag&amp;rsquo;s page, which would list all the snippets having that tag.
The tag page would now also house the tag&amp;rsquo;s chat thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the tag page you could engage in real time chat, and your messages would stay up for a week (or until I take them down, in the case of spam).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My website is not particularly heavily trafficked, but enough people email me about the things I write that this features interests me.
I don&amp;rsquo;t envision any of the chats having any content the majority of the time.
I would set the lifetime of a message to just one week.
Between the low traffic and ephemerality of the messages, most of the chats would be empty most of the time.
I would set up email notifications for myself though, so that I know if someone does post a message.
So at the very least, I could reply, even if few others see the messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As often happens when writing a snippet about an idea I&amp;rsquo;ve had, I start looking into how to implement it concurrently with writing it.
I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at Rocket.Chat, Slack, and Discord, and am currently investigating whether using widgetbot.io to provide access to a Discord server might be a solid solution here.
What follows is my initial attempt at including Discord directly in this snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details id=&#34;chat-details-inline&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary markdown=&#34;span&#34;&gt;Expand this to see the embedded chat.&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;widgetbot
    server=&#34;695290335823265862&#34;
    channel=&#34;988521423603654686&#34;
    width=&#34;100%&#34;
    height=&#34;600&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/widgetbot&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to be working quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given that this tool is readily available, I will compromise on my original vision some.
I think what I&amp;rsquo;ll do now is (1) find a way to lazily load the chat so people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with it aren&amp;rsquo;t bothered by it,
and then (2) I&amp;rsquo;ll add it (behind an expandable section) to every snippet and every tags page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll set up a Discord server with one channel per tag. On the tag pages, the chat will default open to that tag&amp;rsquo;s channel.
On the individual snippets, the chat will default open to the first tag present on the page.
Users can easily switch to other channels if they so desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how to lazy load? This turned out to be simple enough to implement quite quickly. I added some JavaScript to the page that loads the widgetbot JavaScript only when the collapsed chat is expanded. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;
let chatLoaded = false;
const details = document.querySelector(&#39;#chat-details&#39;);
details.addEventListener(&amp;quot;toggle&amp;quot;, event =&amp;gt; {
  if (details.open &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !chatLoaded) {
    const script = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
    script.src = &amp;quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@widgetbot/html-embed&amp;quot;;
    document.head.appendChild(script);
    chatLoaded = true;
  }
});
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Why am I showing this code? It is not germane to the story. A: This is a snippet, and so I guess I do not curate the content like I would if the goal were a proper story. It&amp;rsquo;s meant for future me as much as for anyone else.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
let chatLoadedInline = false;
const detailsInline = document.querySelector(&#39;#chat-details-inline&#39;);
detailsInline.addEventListener(&#34;toggle&#34;, event =&gt; {
  if (detailsInline.open &amp;&amp; !chatLoadedInline) {
    const script = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
    script.src = &#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@widgetbot/html-embed&#34;;
    document.head.appendChild(script);
    chatLoadedInline = true;
  }
});
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having set up the lazy loading, the next step was to create channels for each of the tags on my site.
There are a lot of tags, so I used Browserflow to do this quickly. A joy as always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to update my website so that the appropriate chat gets added to the appropriate page. (I&amp;rsquo;m back, and that&amp;rsquo;s done now :).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tagged this post with &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; because, like my original Ask Me Anywhere ideas, this is about allowing for more direct engagement between me and people on the site. I&amp;rsquo;ve also tagged this &amp;ldquo;Snippets&amp;rdquo;, because it&amp;rsquo;s primarily about a change to the snippets section of my website, and &amp;ldquo;Browserflow&amp;rdquo; because Browserflow was a joy to use for setting up this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I&amp;rsquo;m concluding the snippet. The system is up and running. That was certainly not my expectation when I started writing this, but I&amp;rsquo;m delighted by the progress I made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;As an aside, David, expand this for a reminder of how to add a new tag.&lt;/summary&gt;
There will be some maintenance work necessary whenever I add a snippet with a new tag. Let me summarize the maintenance for myself here for easy reference:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new channel in the Discord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the tag name and channel id to the map at the top of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/davidbieber.com/blob/master/hugo/layouts/partials/discussion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;discussion.html partial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site won&amp;rsquo;t fail to build if you forget to do this; it will just have a broken chat section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should be it. See you in the chats!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Next for Ask Me Anywhere?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-26-next-steps-for-ama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-26-next-steps-for-ama/</guid>
      
        <message>My next steps for Ask Me Anywhere.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I put up an early version of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/&#34;&gt;Ask Me Anywhere&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice it&amp;rsquo;s in the snippets section of the website, rather than part of the main blog. This gives me the freedom to post it even though I know it&amp;rsquo;s not as polished as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that this first pass is published, it&amp;rsquo;s time to start thinking about where to go next with Ask Me Anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-term-stylistic-improvements&#34;&gt;Short Term: Stylistic Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mobile, the &amp;ldquo;Click to React&amp;rdquo; text shows up and is improperly styled. I didn&amp;rsquo;t intend for it to show up at all. On certain mobile devices and browsers, it seems there are even larger issues than this, such as double tapping sometimes not working at all. Let me know if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with your browser so I can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Click to React&amp;rdquo; text also sometimes causes the flow of the text to change, which interrupts the reading experience somewhat. I would like to fix this so that the text flow is never changed by the presence of this message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also would like to tweak the styling to minimize the friction someone feels in deciding to leave a message. I think adding a question-mark icon, which when moused-over gives an explanation of why this feature is there in the first place could be useful. This could strike a good balance between being non-intrusive and letting people know that their thoughts are warmly welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;longer-term-socratic-tutorials&#34;&gt;Longer Term: &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; is really an MVP that came out of a larger idea: &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea is that a &lt;em&gt;Socratic Tutorial&lt;/em&gt; is a blog post structured in a very particular way. It begins with a brief introduction to a topic, followed by a series of questions you might want to ask about that topic. Click a question to reveal an answer to that question, followed by additional questions you might have about the topic. In this way, you can explore the contents of the post in the order that best suits your interests. I also hope that by having to click questions to view the answers, it will help motivate what you&amp;rsquo;re reading, since you&amp;rsquo;ll be actively wondering about the question when you read the response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a reader of a &lt;em&gt;Socratic Tutorial&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand something, or has a question that isn&amp;rsquo;t already addressed, they can choose to ask that question. The author can then add it to the list of questions available during reading if they choose to do so. In that way, &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; is almost a subset of the features planned for Socratic Tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_example&#34;&gt;
My very first blog post ever was about &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Collapsible Blog Posts&lt;/a&gt;. The premise was that you could click on a paragraph, and it would be replaced with a summary of that paragraph. This paragraph is an example; click on it, and it will be replaced with a summary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_example&#34;&gt;
This was a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Collapsible Blog Post&lt;/a&gt; paragraph. Click to un-collapse.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned early on from this experiment that the reverse process actually is more useful. Present the user with a short summary, and let them click if they want to read additional details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_reverse&#34;&gt;
Here&#39;s an example of a short paragraph that you can click to reveal additional details.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_reverse&#34;&gt;
The reason it makes more sense to show the summary first is that it empowers the user to choose how to spend their time. If they are interested in understanding more about a topic, they can choose to expand the paragraph and read the details. If instead they read the extended paragraph first, there isn&#39;t much value to them also reading the summarized version. And if they just want the summarized version, having them see the full version first isn&#39;t too useful either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways the idea for &amp;ldquo;Socratic Tutorials&amp;rdquo; is a spiritual descendent of Collapsible Blog Posts. They both share a goal: give the user control over the information they&amp;rsquo;re consuming, as they&amp;rsquo;re reading. Socratic Tutorials and Ask Me Anywhere take an additional step though, giving the user the ability to communicate directly with the author while they&amp;rsquo;re reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll likely have noticed that this post uses &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo;. That means you can double click any paragraph, or click between two paragraphs, in order to send a note directly to the author.
I hope you do this, as I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear any thoughts you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anywhere</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-25-ask-me-anywhere/</guid>
      
        <message>In this post you can ask a question at _any_ point.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With this post, I&amp;rsquo;m demoing a new work-in-progress feature for my blog called &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo;.
The feature lets you leave a comment or ask a question at &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; point while reading my writing.
The goal is to encourage readers to respond to my writing, because I&amp;rsquo;m interested in having a conversation and hearing what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try it right now. Either &lt;strong&gt;double click&lt;/strong&gt; (double-tap on mobile) on any paragraph, or click between two paragraphs, to open a comment box. Enter your thoughts, click submit, and &lt;em&gt;voila!&lt;/em&gt;, comment submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to enter your email address, name, Twitter handle, Facebook ID, or any other form of contact info if you&amp;rsquo;d like me to respond. And if you do, there is high likelihood that I will respond. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;re anonymous, and you certainly won&amp;rsquo;t receive a private response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and questions that you submit are not posted publicly anywhere. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comments section for public discussion. If you want to discuss my posts publicly, submit them on Hacker News or Reddit, or head to Twitter to engage. While this website isn&amp;rsquo;t the place for public discussions, I am curious to know about such a discussion if it&amp;rsquo;s happening. So, feel free to let me know about such a discussion via &amp;ldquo;AMA&amp;rdquo; if you&amp;rsquo;re starting one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you leave a comment? This part&amp;rsquo;s still a work in progress, but ideally my digital personal assistant 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; will notify me of the new comment at the next convenient time. If there are many comments coming in, Bieber Bot will try to be smart about batching the notifications together, and so the notification may be delayed, but I&amp;rsquo;ll soon read your message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Ask Me Anywhere is only activated for this one post. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve tested it out a bit, and perhaps made some changes, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to then activate it for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;rest of my posts&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;and snippets&lt;/a&gt; as well. So I&amp;rsquo;m particularly keen to get feedback early so I can iterate and improve it soon. Give it a try, let me know what you think. You know how to reach me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about the internals, the source is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/davidbieber.com/blob/772b5dd87da532357a1cdf04a8caa027268bfbac/hugo/assets/js-src/ask-me-anywhere.jsx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to have a poke around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the project &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anywhere&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; reflects my intention to enable readers to ask questions as they&amp;rsquo;re reading. However, I welcome all types of reactions: questions, comments, feedback, corrections, new ideas, etc. I look forward to hearing what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>