<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/list/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/projects/list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bieber Bot</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/</guid>
      <description>Bieber Bot is a highly motivated robot that assists me with my financials, tweets on my behalf, and keeps me productive when my brain feels otherwise.
Is Bieber Bot related to Justin Bieber? No, no relation. Bieber Bot is my own creation.
How does Bieber Bot work? I communicate with Bieber Bot primarily via Facebook messenger. Bieber Bot&amp;rsquo;s brain is a collection of Google Apps Scripts, and Bieber Bot&amp;rsquo;s memory is mostly spreadsheets in Google Sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Castle Heterodyne</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/escape-castle-heterodyne/</guid>
      <description>We built an Escape Room!
Serious props to Bianca Homberg and her amazing talented group of friends for making this happen. I was just a small piece of this epic endeavor. Bianca was the organizer and driving force for a really impressive piece of puzzle craftsmanship.
The premise for the escape room is based on the webcomic Girl Genius. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know:
Escape Castle Heterodyne There&amp;rsquo;s a castle, Castle Heterodyne, which is a living, breathing, talking entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Fire</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/python-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/python-fire/</guid>
      <description>Python Fire is a Python library for automatically creating command line interfaces (CLIs) from absolutely any Python object.
Check it out at https://github.com/google/python-fire.
I originally wrote Python Fire after joining Google Brain in 2016. In March 2017 we open sourced the project, and I proud and delighted by the growth and reception it has seen since.
To give it a try, simply pip install fire, and then call fire.Fire() as the main of any Python program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Day</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/tech-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/tech-day/</guid>
      <description>Tech Day is an educational program run by Googlers for high school students interested in technology and computer science.
The Tech Day website is available at techday.withgoogle.com. Information about upcoming Tech Day events will be posted there as it becomes available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>at Scheduler</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/at-scheduler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/at-scheduler/</guid>
      <description>The at-scheduler is a simple command line scheduler.
For installation instructions, see the README on GitHub.
Once it&amp;rsquo;s installed, using the at-scheduler is simple. From your shell, just run a command at &amp;lt;when&amp;gt; &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;. This will schedule your command to be run at the time specified.
The syntax for &amp;lt;when&amp;gt; is lenient. Specific times like &amp;ldquo;9:30am&amp;rdquo; work, as do named dates like &amp;ldquo;tomorrow at 10pm&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;next Tuesday at 3pm&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shh Shell</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell/</guid>
      <description>The shh shell The shh shell is a simple shell you can use while you drift off to sleep.
Notably, you can keep your eyes closed while you use it.
The shell is controlled by typing and the only output is audio; there are no visual components of shh. It is designed to minimize the mental energy required for use, to avoid disturbing your attempt at sleep as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrabble Bot</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/scrabble-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/scrabble-bot/</guid>
      <description>Scrabble Bot loves Scrabble and social media! Check out Scrab&amp;rsquo;s tumblr page full of Scrabble games it&amp;rsquo;s played against itself.
Scrabble Bot is also privacy conscious, and so uses Facebook under a pseudonym, &amp;ldquo;Scrab Blebot&amp;rdquo;. Scrab believes their identity is secure.
You can find Scrabble Bot&amp;rsquo;s source on GitHub here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teach Everyone</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/teach-everyone/</guid>
      <description>The Teach Everyone website is available at teacheveryone.org.
Note: The Save Video functionality is not currently exposed on the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton ACM</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/projects/princeton-acm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/projects/princeton-acm/</guid>
      <description>Princeton ACM is the Princeton University student chapter of the Association for Computing Machinery. Please find the Princeton ACM website at princetonacm.com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>