<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/math/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>math</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>math</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/math/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derivative of Softmax and the Softmax Cross Entropy Loss</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-12-derivative-of-softmax-and-the-softmax-cross-entropy-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-12-derivative-of-softmax-and-the-softmax-cross-entropy-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Write $y_i = \text{softmax}(\textbf{x})_i = \frac{e^{x_i}}{\sum e^{x_d}}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, $\textbf{y}$ is the softmax of $\textbf{x}$. Softmax computes a normalized exponential of its input vector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next write $L = -\sum t_i \ln(y_i)$. This is the softmax cross entropy loss. $t_i$ is a 0/1 target representing whether the correct class is class $i$. We will compute the derivative of $L$ with respect to the inputs to the softmax function $\textbf{x}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have $\frac{dL}{dx_j} = -\sum t_i \frac{1}{y_i} \frac{dy_i}{d{x_j}}$ from the chain rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compute $\frac{dy_i}{dx_j}$ using the quotient rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If $i = j$, this gives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = \frac{\sum e^{x_d} \cdot e^{x_i} - e^{x_i} \cdot e^{x_i}}{(\sum e^{x_d})^2}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = \frac{e^{x_i}}{\sum e^{x_d}} \cdot \left(\frac{\sum e^{x_d} - e^{x_i}}{\sum e^{x_d}}\right)$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = y_i \cdot (1 - y_i)$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If $i \ne j$, this gives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = \frac{\sum e^{x_d} \cdot 0 - e^{x_i} \cdot e^{x_j}}{(\sum e^{x_d})^2}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = -\frac{e^{x_i}}{\sum e^{x_d}} \cdot \frac{e^{x_j}}{\sum e^{x_d}} $&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = -y_i y_j$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together these equations give us the derivative of the softmax function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dy_i}{dx_j} = \begin{cases} y_i \cdot (1 - y_i) &amp;amp; i=j \\\ -y_i y_j &amp;amp; i \ne j \end{cases}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this result, we can finish computing the derivative of $L$. This gives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dL}{dx_j} = -\sum t_i \frac{1}{y_i} \frac{dy_i}{d{x_j}} = \sum\limits_i \begin{cases} t_i (y_i - 1) &amp;amp; i=j \\\ t_i y_j &amp;amp; i \ne j \end{cases}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since exactly one of the $t_i$s is 1 and the rest are zeros this further simplifies to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\frac{dL}{dx_j} = y_j - t_j$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have computed the derivative of the softmax cross-entropy loss $L$ with respect to the inputs to the softmax function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is an experiment in publishing directly from Roam Research. &lt;del&gt;It is incomplete, and the formatting is probably all wonky. Bear with me while I get this sorted.&lt;/del&gt; Update (December 13th, 2020): The formatting looks good now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2e-8 of All of Human Experience</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-03-4.2e-8-of-all-of-human-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-03-4.2e-8-of-all-of-human-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 107 billion people have &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across all time, the average life expectancy of a person is just under 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there have only been 3.21 trillion person-years experienced. Total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.8 billion people are alive today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average age globally is about 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So living people today collectively hold about 234 billion years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that a little &lt;strong&gt;over 7% of all human experience is held by living people&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day spent alone constitutes 8.5e-16 of all of human experience. A month is 2.6e-14 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year spent with a partner is 6.2e-13 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years spent with 1500 other students is 1.9e-9 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By a crude estimate, a whopping 4.2e-8 of all human experience was spent watching Game of Thrones. Humanity will never get that time back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are small numbers, but not &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; small. Thinking that my graduating class alone (not even counting the people a year above or below me) holds nearly 2e-9 of all human experience from our four years together is kind of mind-bending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For comparison, let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that the surface of Earth represents all of human experience. Then 4.2e-8 of human experience (the amount dedicated to watching Game of Thrones) is represented by 8.3 square miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6.2e-13 of human experience held by you and your partner quarantining for a year? That&amp;rsquo;s over 3400 square feet. And a whole lifetime (est. 80 years) covers 3.141 acres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not at all negligible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is to say: let&amp;rsquo;s treasure our existence, and let&amp;rsquo;s also not discount its significance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading the Online Encylopedia of Integer Sequences</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-06-28-oeis-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-06-28-oeis-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a way to download the entire 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oeis.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Online Encylopedia of Integer Sequences&lt;/a&gt;, you may come across advice for scraping the site, one sequence at a time. Instead of collecting the sequences one at a time, it might be sufficient to download one of their already collected archives. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oeis.org/stripped.gz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This file&lt;/a&gt; contains the integer sequences and their A-numbers, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oeis.org/names.gz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this file&lt;/a&gt; contains the names of the sequences. No need to stress the OEIS servers when these ready-made archives are ripe for downloading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found these files from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oeis.org/wiki/JSON_Format,_Compressed_Files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; of the OEIS wiki. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m linking to it here is that finding that page was difficult, and I hope to save you the trouble of finding it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future-Predicting Game Show Host</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-02-08-future-gameshow-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-02-08-future-gameshow-host/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A game show host reveals 2 boxes, box A and box B. In box A is either $1 million or $0, in box B there is $1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re told, choose either just box A or both A and B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You keep the contents of the boxes you choose.
Also, the host knows what box you will choose, and has placed $1 million in A if you will choose only A, and $0 in A if you will choose both A and B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some contestants, faced with this choice, would choose both A and B. They reason that since the money has already been placed, choosing A and B is guaranteed to yield $1000 more than choosing just A.
Others would choose only A, since per the host&amp;rsquo;s plans this option leads to a significantly better payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly choosing only A is $1000 worse than choosing both A and B, yet choosing A only is allegedly better given the host&amp;rsquo;s foresight. These statements appear contradictory, and this situation is known as 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newcomb%27s_paradox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Newcomb&amp;rsquo;s Paradox&lt;/a&gt;.
How can we reconcile these two true but contradictory statements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do so by clarifying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Right now&lt;/em&gt; choosing only A is $1000 worse than choosing both A and B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, having a brain&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;at the time the money is placed&lt;/em&gt; that will lead you to choose only A at the time of choosing gives the $1 million outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this something you have control over? Can you &lt;em&gt;decide&lt;/em&gt; at the time the money is placed to have a brain that will lead you to later choose only box A?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem like &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;, for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t even know there was a choice to make.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You surely don&amp;rsquo;t get to make choices about how your brain works, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the host is able know your choice ahead of time, that must mean it&amp;rsquo;s predetermined, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, none of these reasons are entirely valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it&amp;rsquo;s true that at the time the money is placed, you didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily know you had a choice to make. You hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet been informed that you would later be on this game show. However, it&amp;rsquo;s possible you considered the situation as a hypothetical anyway (maybe while reading a blog post, for instance). It isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary that you considered precisely the situation that you would later find yourself in, only that you&amp;rsquo;ve given conscious deliberate thought to the way you make choices. By thinking this through, you can decide now whether you have a brain that would later choose box A or one that would later choose both A and B, should the game show situation ever arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you absolutely do get to make choices about how your brain works. You can choose when to sleep, when to study, what substances to ingest, and most importantly, what to focus your attention on. All of these levers are yours to pull, and they all affect how your brain will operate in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time you choose the boxes, it&amp;rsquo;s still your decision as to which box(es) to choose. (In the sense that it&amp;rsquo;s your brain that produces the decision.)
But you must have been predictable, at least to the host, for them to have predicted what choice you would later make.
(Nothing wrong with being predictable!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that you were predictable? Does this require determinism?
One extreme way you may have been predictable is if the host knows exactly how events will play out, right down to the thoughts you will have and the choices you will make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; so extreme though. The host only claimed to have roughly one bit of information about you and the future: what binary choice you would make when confronted with the box dilemma. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t require omniscience. The host may have no idea what the weather is going to be the next day, as long as they&amp;rsquo;re able to predict whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re taking box B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe they know a little about how your mind works, or they&amp;rsquo;ve read something you&amp;rsquo;ve posted online that lets them conclude how you will handle the box situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must consider that whatever they know, they knew it at the time that they chose how to fill the boxes. (They likely also knew it at the time they chose to host the game show in the first place.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I think is most likely is that this host does know precisely how you think about this choice. They do this by understanding to a very high degree of precision how your brain is going to cope with the decision of which boxes to choose. Think of the host as a very skilled poker player, that can read you like a book. Instead of just knowing whether you&amp;rsquo;re bluffing or not, they know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to think 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/6640273&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;before you even think it&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s like weather forecasting, but instead of understanding the atmosphere, they&amp;rsquo;re understanding you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like with weather forecasting, their model is imperfect. It&amp;rsquo;s good enough to know what box you&amp;rsquo;ll choose, with certainty, but only because that only requires forecasting a small window (a week, let&amp;rsquo;s say) into the future. Like the atmospheric conditions that determine the weather, your brain is a chaotic system. Any imperfection in the model, however small, will eventually blow up and lead to large errors in the model in the future. So our host can&amp;rsquo;t model your every thought a year into the future, let alone e.g. the whole population&amp;rsquo;s behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what boxes should you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should choose to open just box A. By reaching this conclusion (and more importantly, by adopting the strategy for reasoning that leads to this conclusion), you guarantee yourself $1 million the next time you encounter a wealthy generous time traveling game show host interested in philosophy and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;brain&amp;rdquo;, but I really mean the whole of your situation and life circumstances. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does &#34;Ordinary&#34; mean in Ordinary Least Squares?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-08-ordinary-least-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-08-ordinary-least-squares/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ordinary Least Squares&amp;rdquo; regression, or OLS for short, is a method for finding a best-fit line, given a set of data points. When people refer to linear regression without additional context or qualifiers, they&amp;rsquo;re probably referring to ordinary least squares regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; mean in this context? Is it a mathematical term with a precise technical meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, no. In this case &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; means exactly what you might expect: standard, vanilla, lacking any bells and whistles. Since least squares regression is so common, there are lots of variants. Weighted Least Squares (in which each data point is given its own weight) is a such a variant. So, in OLS, the O for ordinary simply means we&amp;rsquo;re not referring to one of these variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about &amp;ldquo;ordinary differential equations&amp;rdquo; (ODEs)? What does ordinary refer to there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that context, ordinary refers to ordinary derivatives, as opposed to partial derivatives. So again, it&amp;rsquo;s not a mathematical term like a reference to ordinal numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, ordinary seems to take on its ordinary English definition &amp;ndash; its OED, if I may.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
