<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>table tennis | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/table-tennis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/table-tennis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>table tennis</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>table tennis</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/table-tennis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do table tennis strokes end at the forehead?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-10-forehand-to-forehead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-10-forehand-to-forehead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a table tennis forehand, the stroke typically ends at the forehead. The full stroke is a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ball is coming toward your forehand side; get in position early.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your body is angled slightly to the right, e.g. forming a 15 degree angle between the back edge of the table and the line through your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your elbow is bent at 90 degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your wrist is straight, so the paddle forms an extension of the arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your knees are bent, butt out. You&amp;rsquo;re low to the table, at my height almost squatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ball incoming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the ball approaches there&amp;rsquo;s a small setup phase, where you take the paddle back, and twist to your right a little to allow for a more explosive shot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stroke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soon after the ball bounces, say at the peak of the bounce or earlier, you move the paddle through the path of the ball toward where you want to take the ball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your torso rotates the same direction as your arm and paddle. The three have very little relative motion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your weight shifts forward at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can accelerate your paddle during contact with the ball for a more powerful shot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you follow through the ball, your racket moves near your forehead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I, a new player, take a forehand shot, my racket often lands near my chest, not my forehead. This feels more natural. Why is it better to move near the forehead than the chest, and how do you achieve this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-1-lower-to-the-table-is-better&#34;&gt;Reason 1: Lower to the table is better&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s better to be low to the table. Being low to the table lets you see the spin better, and gives more arm and leg mobility. It takes more energy though, being in a squat position. Too low, and the mobility decreases.
When you&amp;rsquo;re higher, the follow through to a forehand is more likely to land at your chest, whereas when you&amp;rsquo;re lower, it&amp;rsquo;s going to naturally be closer to your forehead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-2-each-stroke-should-prepare-for-the-next-stroke&#34;&gt;Reason 2: Each stroke should prepare for the next stroke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mistake I make is to take a stroke and then bring the paddle back along roughly the same path of the stroke in reverse. Instead, it is faster to make strokes in a circular pattern. Hit through the ball, and continue hitting in an egg-shape pattern until your paddle is back where it started ready for the next stroke. This reduces the need to decelerate the paddle and re-accelerate in the opposite direction. On the other hand, when this isn&amp;rsquo;t practiced so that it&amp;rsquo;s second nature, this consumes extra concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forehead might be a natural place on the path toward setting up the next stroke. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about this one. To me, the chest seems just as viable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-3-dont-cut-the-stroke-short&#34;&gt;Reason 3: Don&amp;rsquo;t cut the stroke short&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get maximum power and control, you want to hit the ball toward a particular spot on the table. You want to follow through toward that spot, so that you&amp;rsquo;re hitting in the desired direction for the entire contact with the ball. If you cut the stroke short, aka &amp;ldquo;shorting the stroke&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;ll impart some side-spin on the ball but won&amp;rsquo;t get maximum power or control.
I guess it works out that moving from the stroke earlier shorts the stroke and ends with the paddle at chest height, but doing a full stroke ends with the paddle at forehead height. This is because the forehand should be moving forward and up through the path of the ball, and a longer time moving up takes you closer to forehead height.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t want to move too far forward and up though. That would leave you with the paddle over the table and your elbow extended, unprepared for the next shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-4-balance-many-concerns&#34;&gt;Reason 4: Balance many concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we want to balance all of these concerns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staying low to the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitting up and forward through the path of the ball&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitting toward the target location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping our balance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparing early for the next shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, this leads to the classic table tennis shot, landing with a forehead height follow through and quick recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing RL table tennis points in VR</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-03-reconstructing-rl-tt-in-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-03-reconstructing-rl-tt-in-vr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://alexttbarcelona.wixsite.com/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alex TT Barcelona&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; makes table tennis drills for Eleven Table Tennis.
In a recently released batch of drills, he took a point played by table tennis pro Mima Ito and reconstructed it in VR. The ball machine would &amp;ndash; endlessly in a loop &amp;ndash; play the role of Mima Ito&amp;rsquo;s opponent. It would launch ping pong balls from the same location and with the same trajectory that Mima Ito&amp;rsquo;s opponent hit the ball during the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reconstruction is a great experience; it really demonstrates the level of play, showcasing how fast and wide the ball goes during professional matches. It also highlights the potential of Eleven Table Tennis as a practice tool for real table tennis. You can reconstruct points from your own real-life table tennis matches in virtual reality, and practice them as many times as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the process of reconstructing a point from real life in VR is a bit slow and specialized. The way to do it is to open Eleven Table Tennis on a PC (which I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have, making this difficult), and to adjust the ball machine settings on your computer in order to replicate each of your opponent&amp;rsquo;s ball trajectories consecutively.
Once a full point is done, you can play against the ball machine in VR to practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my last table tennis tournament, I took some footage of myself playing (and losing) a real table tennis match.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet tried transcribing it to VR, in part because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a PC. Soon though I hope to transcribe some points so I can practice the shots I&amp;rsquo;m weakest against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I estimate that reconstructing a single shot, once you&amp;rsquo;re practiced in the art of table tennis point transcription, takes about a minute. This means that transcribing a full 5-game match, which might have as many as 300-500 individual shots, could take 5-8 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to bring this time down. First, and simplest, is to merely transcribe a subset of the points. Only transcribing shots by your opponent immediately cuts the time in half, and you probably only will want to replay perhaps 10 points total anyway, further cutting down the reconstruction time drastically. Outsourcing the reconstruction to e.g. Fiverr seems plausible, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t save time overall, it merely pushes the time cost onto someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a way to automate the transcription process. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://stupaanalytics.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stupa Analytics&lt;/a&gt; uses AI to analyze table tennis matches to provide coaching to players. It seems likely that they model the trajectory of table tennis balls as part of this analysis. Their software works using video from a single phone camera, which is ideal if it works. Perhaps we can build on top of their existing vision systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve reached out to them to inquire, but have not heard back. I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried to use their software, which promised me analysis within 72 hours, but a week later it has still not delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some projects on GitHub also show promise for enabling automated transcription. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ckjellson/tt_tracker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ckjellson/tt_tracker&lt;/a&gt; uses OpenCV to track table tennis balls using two camera inputs. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vmarquet/table-tennis-computer-vision&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;vmarquet/table-tennis-computer-vision&lt;/a&gt; also offers ball tracking for table tennis using OpenCV, though may require specialized sensors (not clear yet). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maudzung/TTNet-Real-time-Analysis-System-for-Table-Tennis-Pytorch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;maudzung/TTNet-Real-time-Analysis-System-for-Table-Tennis-Pytorch&lt;/a&gt; uses machine learning to analyze table tennis footage, including ball tracking. These three seem the most promising. Though I don&amp;rsquo;t have any two camera input data currently, I look forward to trying out these projects and seeing if I can repurpose one for RL-to-VR point reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving in table tennis</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-serving-in-table-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-serving-in-table-tennis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a couple serves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The forehand backspin serve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The disguised left- and right-spin with a little topspin serves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key attributes in a serve are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where it goes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How fast it goes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether it reaches the back edge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The spin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the perceived depth and spin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read you should always serve to the front or back third of the opponents side, never to the middle third. The reason for preferring these regions is to force the opponent into a less comfortable stroke and maybe put them a bit off balance, as hitting the middle third gives them precisely the stroke they&amp;rsquo;ve most practiced for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Serve essentials.&lt;/em&gt; You must start the serve above the surface of the table. Does ETT check for this? (A: Yes, but not properly.)
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be in the left and right lines, and so it can be useful to move to the corner to start a serve. If you do this, get into position right away after serving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The toss must be 6 inches or more. A higher toss can give you more speed and spin.
The high toss means you contact the ball with high downward velocity, and greater overall momentum. Most of the momentum on the ball after the serve will come from the paddle, not the toss, so this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem super critical, but it does add something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding to side-spin</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-responding-to-side-spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-responding-to-side-spin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If the server moves their paddle from your left top right across the ball, then add the ball cones toward you its trajectory will bend to your left. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to hit it further left, otherwise it will bounce off your racket to the right and go out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How best to think about this?
The ball is spinning to your left; that&amp;rsquo;s why the trajectory bends to your left. By &amp;ldquo;spinning to your left&amp;rdquo;, I refer to the direction the part of the ball leading the trajectory is moving in. Since the ball&amp;rsquo;s coming toward you, it&amp;rsquo;s the part of the ball closest to you that is moving left; the part furthest from you is moving to your right. The Magnus effect cause the trajectory to bend in the direction that leading edge of the ball is traveling in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why topspin balls fall faster and backspin balls float.
When you hit a topspin ball, the leading part of the ball (furthest from you) is moving down. In a backspin shot the leading part of the ball is moving up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the side-spin ball bounces on the table, it can bounce to the left. When it bounces off your racket, however, it will move to the right. The same spin that&amp;rsquo;s left-spin when coming toward you is right-spin when moving away from you. It isn&amp;rsquo;t that the spin reversed. The spin stayed the same; just the ball&amp;rsquo;s direction reversed. The leading edge is now the one furthest from you. The part of the ball that contacted the paddle was moving left, so it pushed the paddle left and itself right. Now as it moves away it has right-spin on it and the leading edge of the ball in its new trajectory is moving to the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests a difficult but powerful attack. Send a fast left-spin ball (by moving your paddle to the right) down the right side of the table. When your opponent goes to return it, the default behavior will be for it to bounce to your right, their left, further off the right edge of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backhand flicks, drives, loops, and pushes</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-backhand-flicks-drives-loops-and-pushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-21-backhand-flicks-drives-loops-and-pushes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for potential reader: I&amp;rsquo;m new to this sport, and my commentary might not be correct or good advice :).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between backhand flicks, drives, loops, and pushes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flicks, drives, and loops all impart topspin on the ball. The backhand push typically imparts backspin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive is more of a forward motion, giving a flatter resulting ball compared with the heavier topspin of a flick or loop. A backhand drive done well might result in a flat ball entirely, rather than a topspin one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backhand flick and loop might actually refer to the same stroke, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I&amp;rsquo;ll say what I think the differences are. The backhand flick uses very heavy wrist to get topspin, while the loop drives is topspin more from forward motion of the paddle, both brushing the top of the ball to import heavy topspin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases (in all cases, really) it&amp;rsquo;s important to keep the wrist (and shoulder) relaxed, forming up most (but only a little) at the time of making contact with the ball. Remaining relaxed allows you to adjust strokes more quickly. This allows handling unexpected ball placements and decisions from the expected spin and bounce more gracefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classical advice suggests you should not reach (extending your elbow) so that you can always use the same shot, and so you have more control over the angle of your paddle. Instead of reaching, the advice goes, you should move your feet so you&amp;rsquo;re in position to hit the ball. This advice can be misleading; it&amp;rsquo;s silly to avoid reaching when reaching is necessary, and it&amp;rsquo;s bad advice to avoid learning a useful stroke. It&amp;rsquo;s good advice to use your feet. And above all, it&amp;rsquo;s a good observation that reaching can be a common failure mode for the backhand strokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also true that when this failure mode arises it can be naturally accompanied by pointing the racket face in slightly the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary ways to counter this are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practicing footwork to get into place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience so if you have to reach you get the angle right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awareness of the pitfall so you can notice it and adjust more rapidly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bad thing to do would be to avoid reaching when reaching is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another piece of advice is to avoid reaching forward. This advice is similar to that above about reaching left on backhands. You can put your leg under the table to minimize your reach, but ultimately reaching is necessary for retrieving drop shots and other short shots. The right takeaway is that footwork comes first, not that racing should be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It often gets repeated that the reason to avoid reaching is so you can reuse your strokes. This seems like you&amp;rsquo;re setting yourself up for failure. To succeed in unexpected situations you need to know exactly how your paddle behaves no matter how you&amp;rsquo;re hitting it. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to just be memorizing a small number of strokes and applying them as best as possible in whatever situation arises. If you do that, your game-play will be so fragile. It won&amp;rsquo;t work if the ball&amp;rsquo;s a little too high, too low, or too wide. Better to practice both the core strokes, the necessary footwork, AND how to use your strokes at their extreme values for when footwork and reflexes are insufficient to bring the ball into a standard position.
Is this right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas of table tennis to improve at</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-17-areas-of-table-tennis-to-improve-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-17-areas-of-table-tennis-to-improve-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now the biggest area to work on is having the confidence (and skill) to attack in a match setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this confidence in Eleven Table Tennis (ETT), usually, but in the real world its harder to demonstrate.
I guess I become conservative in the real world because you have to be responsible for your balls.
In ETT you can try an aggressive shot and if it goes into the stands or out the window, no big deal. In practice starting aggressive doesn&amp;rsquo;t go so wildly. Still, in ETT you can feed dozens of balls quickly in order to develop the proper feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s a solid idea to bring into the real world. I&amp;rsquo;ll buy 50+ practice balls and then I can serve a bunch real quickly or multi ball with a partner in order to develop that feel more quickly in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main areas I want to get good feel for quickly in the real world are backhand flicks and forehand topspin drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the tips I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up in my month of playing for the backhand flicks are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the ball with your core&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be reaching too much for the ball; you want to reuse the same stroke as much as possible each time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use shoulder, wrist, and a little torso, I think in that order. A basic shot would be mostly shoulder. For a more attacking show, a proper flick, add in a lot of wrist. Finally for max power, add a tiny bit of torso. And you should use leg power too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left foot beyond the edge of the table, closer to the table than the right foot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relaxed wrist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the ball all the way in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit the top of the ball, say 2/3 of the way up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice! Have a plan when starting the point. Always be ready to third ball attack when serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about tips for the forehand drive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move early into position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again the goal is to use the same stroke each time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As before shoulder, wrist, and torso are key.
Wow, despite looking so different the tips are remarkably similar to the backhand flick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the ball all the way in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brush up the ball&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your stroke ends in front of your face&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And your wrist points forward from your forearm, not up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I think the squat is perhaps a bit reduced compared with the backhand flick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to qualify for the US Olympic table tennis team</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-17-table-tennis-olympic-qualifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-06-17-table-tennis-olympic-qualifiers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to qualify for the US Olympic table tennis team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become the best singles table tennis player in the country, preferably by a significant margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the qualifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Win the qualifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is far more straightforward than I would have expected. Obviously step 1 presents a significant challenge, and step 2 probably involves some paperwork. Still, it came as a shock to me that a single tournament, open to any USATT player as far as I can tell, which only gets 50 entrants, is all that stands between an aspirational table tennis player and such a significant event as the Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to step 1!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Browserflow Flow for Eleven Table Tennis VR</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-05-01-table-tennis-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-05-01-table-tennis-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this snippet I chronicle making a Cloud flow that tracks my progress in Eleven Table Tennis VR, a virtual reality table tennis game I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a bunch over the last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a first pass at making the flow earlier in the week, and ran into two hiccups I&amp;rsquo;ll need to work around: (1) The css selectors for my ELO, Rank, etc change between visits to the website. How am I going to extract this data in the flow? (2) Some games have three rounds others have two, and the css selectors differ depending on which game we&amp;rsquo;re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-1-stable-css-selectors-across-page-loads&#34;&gt;Challenge 1: Stable CSS Selectors Across Page Loads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browserflow&amp;rsquo;s default CSS selector for the ELO rate on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elevenvr.net/eleven/413682&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my Eleven TT page&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;code&gt;div:nth-of-type(1) &amp;gt; .jss87 &amp;gt; .MuiTypography-root&lt;/code&gt;. The trouble with this is that the class .jss87 isn&amp;rsquo;t always there. Sometimes when I load the page, the class .jss70 is there instead. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how this class is determined, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t stable enough to use for my flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a bit of poking around, I was able to use an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/almanac/selectors/n/nth-child/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nth-child&lt;/code&gt; rule&lt;/a&gt; to write a more stable selector. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with: &lt;code&gt;div.MuiGrid-container &amp;gt; .MuiPaper-root:nth-child(1) .MuiTypography-root&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new strategy in place, I can easily complete the first half of the flow (which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably actually split into two flows): regularly logging my Eleven Elo, Rank, Win and Loss count, and Win rate into a spreadsheet automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what the completed flow looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-05-01-table-tennis-flow.png&#34; alt=&#34;Complete table tennis ranking tracker flow&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-2-varying-css-selectors-across-rows&#34;&gt;Challenge 2: Varying CSS Selectors Across Rows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up I have the challenge of selecting game data from the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elevenvr.net/eleven/413682&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;same page&lt;/a&gt;. Browserflow makes it easy to loop over the match data with its Loop Elements command. The trouble is that some matches have three rounds while others have just two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default CSS selects for the game data are e.g. &lt;code&gt;$match tr:nth-of-type(1) &amp;gt; td:nth-of-type(3)&lt;/code&gt; for the Match Score. Two of the columns: &amp;ldquo;ELO +-&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Round 3&amp;rdquo; only show up in certain matches. &amp;ldquo;ELO +-&amp;rdquo; only shows up for ranked matches, and &amp;ldquo;Round 3&amp;rdquo; only shows up if the first two matches are split between the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect that in rare cases there are matches with only 1 round (e.g. because a player leaves early), and that in the future there might be matches with additional rounds too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements themselves don&amp;rsquo;t contain any additional information indicating what column they belong to. I might have to take this slightly painstaking approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I&amp;rsquo;ll use &lt;code&gt;Get Element Text&lt;/code&gt; to get the text of the first six column headers, and I&amp;rsquo;ll have it use blank text if there are fewer than six headers. In some cases these will be USERNAME, ELO +-, MATCH SCORE, ROUND 1, ROUND 2, ROUND 3. In other cases it will just be a subset of this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, for each player I&amp;rsquo;ll get the first six entries in their row. I&amp;rsquo;ll use the headers to determine what these entries describe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brief programming interlude&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. Here&amp;rsquo;s the completed flow. It works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-05-01-table-tennis-spreadsheet.png&#34; alt=&#34;Complete table tennis games flow with collected data&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to make 19 &lt;code&gt;Get Element Text&lt;/code&gt; actions and a &lt;code&gt;Run Script&lt;/code&gt;, even though I only needed data from 13 different elements. Collecting tabular data is a pretty common task, so there&amp;rsquo;s room to make this simpler for future flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the script I ended up writing for populating fields based on the header data, just for reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;let $player1 = $row1field1;
let $player2 = $row2field1;

let $elo1 = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
let $elo2 = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
let $elo1change = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
let $elo2change = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
let score_index = 1;

if ($header2 == &amp;quot;ELO +-&amp;quot;) {
  let elo1 = $row1field2;
  let elo2 = $row2field2;
  $elo1 = elo1.split(&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)[0];
  $elo2 = elo2.split(&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)[0];
  let elo1change = elo1.split(&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)[1];
  let elo2change = elo2.split(&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)[1];
  // Remove the parentheses (+16) -&amp;gt; +16.
  $elo1change = elo1change.substring(1, elo1change.length - 1);
  $elo2change = elo2change.substring(1, elo2change.length - 1);
  score_index = 2;
}

var row1fields = [
  $row1field1,
  $row1field2,
  $row1field3,
  $row1field4,
  $row1field5,
  $row1field6,
];
var row2fields = [
  $row2field1,
  $row2field2,
  $row2field3,
  $row2field4,
  $row2field5,
  $row2field6,
];

var $matchscore1 = row1fields[score_index];
var $matchscore2 = row2fields[score_index];
var $round1player1 = row1fields[score_index + 1];
var $round1player2 = row2fields[score_index + 1];
var $round2player1 = row1fields[score_index + 2];
var $round2player2 = row2fields[score_index + 2];
var $round3player1 = row1fields[score_index + 3];
var $round3player2 = row2fields[score_index + 3];

var gameidanddate_parts = $gameidanddate.split(&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;, 2);
let $gameid = gameidanddate_parts[0];
// TODO(dbieber): Parse timestamp.
let $timestamp = gameidanddate_parts[1];

// formatDate definition elided.
let $today = formatDate(new Date());
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-challenge-record-every-game-exactly-once&#34;&gt;Future Challenge: Record every game exactly once&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current instance of the flow just collects all the games on page 1 into the spreadsheet. What I&amp;rsquo;d really like the flow to do is collect every game once.
My flow will run once a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could do this by parsing the dates, and having the flow collect all the flows less than one day old each time it runs. This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be robust to missing a day though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another approach would be to have the flow look in the spreadsheet for the last game collected, and then keep collecting games until that most recently collected game is reached. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss these options with DK before proceeding. For now, it&amp;rsquo;ll just collect a subset of my games, or collect some games twice if I play fewer than 10 on some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the flows 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/4a8c4303-ad21-420e-8414-5de57e0692d4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/4e3fd160-6665-46b7-ad2b-0a6be9121649&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you have Browserflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual table tennis coaching</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-18-virtual-table-tennis-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-18-virtual-table-tennis-coaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing virtual reality table tennis quite a lot. It&amp;rsquo;s competitive; some highly ranked real-life table tennis players from around the world play this game. My ranking has been going up: my ELO recently reached 2000+, bringing me (at least temporarily) into the top 1500 ranked players online (out of upwards of 440,000 players total.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make my number go up. So I practice. I play ranked and unranked games against people around the world. I practice against AI opponents. I use the virtual  ball machine. And I watch YouTube videos on how to hit the strokes appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t done though is get a coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have started offering in game virtual reality table tennis coaching. I think this is incredible. The coach and player play at the table simultaneously. They can stand on the same side of the table or opposite each other. They can use a ball machine together or hit with one another. They can discuss table tennis and do exercises together all in game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in giving virtual lessons a try. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how good I&amp;rsquo;d be at receiving coaching though, and this is something I&amp;rsquo;d like to improve at. What makes for a good coach/player relationship? Players need psychological safety. Coaches need to be observant and knowledgeable. Players need to want to improve and ask good questions. Players need to be receptive to the suggestions of the coach. Players need to trust that the coach is focusing on the important aspects of play, so they can focus on the drill at hand. Coaches need to establish this trust. Players have to put in the time to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table tennis quest game is still under active development, and the features that make coaching possible are still young. As I understand it, there aren&amp;rsquo;t special coaching features &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s just the capability for two people to use around a table optionally with a ball machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose the game developers were to add features to improve the coaching experience. What features would be essential? (1) Record and replay hits from a game or practice (2) Track stats during practice (3) Coach multiple people simultaneously across multiple tables (4) Mix and match replays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;record-and-replay&#34;&gt;Record and Replay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two reasons to want to record and replay hits from a game or practice. One is to learn to defend against them. Say you play against an opponent with a powerful serve or forehand smash. By recording and replaying their attack you can practice defending against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason to record and replay is to mimic or correct a shot. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you tend to hit your backhand loops into the net. It would be useful to replay the hit as a &amp;ldquo;ghost&amp;rdquo; that you can overlay your real paddle against. In this way you can make subtle adjustments in order to improve this shot. Similarly, you can take the powerful serve or forehand smash from the previous example and learn to mimic it by replaying it repeatedly and following along the motions with your own paddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;track-stats-during-practice&#34;&gt;Track stats during practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essential tool for self improvement is numbers that go up: ELO ratings, win counts, balls returned, etc. Giving the ball machine the capability of tracking how many balls you return successfully (where &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; is something you can define, such as hitting a certain region of the table, perhaps with a certain minimum speed or spin) and how many you miss creates a new metric to improve. And once there&amp;rsquo;s a metric to improve, putting in the time to improve it becomes all the more satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love if the game could track a metric like this over time. This feature would pair especially well with the next one, allowing a coach to coach multiple people simultaneously, because it would give the coach quick visibility into the progress of the players towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coaching-multiple-people-across-multiple-tables&#34;&gt;Coaching multiple people across multiple tables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently coaching is a one on one affair. This is virtual reality though, so the potential for tools for coaching go way beyond what&amp;rsquo;s possible in the real world. A simple place to start is allowing the coach to simultaneously coach multiple people. The coach would do this by having all their students at various tables. The coach could have a multi-table view, where they can monitor all tables at once. Then, through VR magic the coach can quickly teleport to any of the tables to provide individual instruction. The coach can speak with players one on one, or to the whole group simultaneously. Similarly, the coach can set the ball machine settings for individual players or for the whole group. And the coach can pair off players to hit together or play matches or do exercises as they deem appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ball replay feature is of course also essential in this setting. If the coach observes a particularly good shot on any of the tables, they can capture this and replay it for all the players. Everyone can practice returning this one shot, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a smash, loop, or lob, to improve their table tennis game together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mixing-and-matching-replays&#34;&gt;Mixing and matching replays&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The record and replay feature is going to be essential to the future of practice. Replaying a single ball over and over is useful, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture the dynamic nature of table tennis. So, one useful feature to pair with replaying a shot is the ability to add variance to the shot. In the original recording, the smash has X speed and Y spin and hits precisely position Z. In the replays, all these values can be perturbed slightly to practice variations on the theme. Also, being able to build sequences of replay shots, much in the way you can turn on multiple ball machine settings today, would be a welcome addition for practicing in game situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know which of these the game developers have planned. And of those that they have planned (they seem to have &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; planned), I wonder which are planned first. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve had my first coaching session, I&amp;rsquo;m sure my feature requests will only grow. Looking forward to it all. 🏓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eleven: Table Tennis VR</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-16-table-tennis-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-16-table-tennis-vr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adriana and I recently acquired a VR headset (an Oculus Quest 2), and I bought the game &amp;ldquo;Eleven: Table Tennis VR&amp;rdquo;.
My mind is blown. It&amp;rsquo;s like having a ping pong table that fits in your hands. You can bring it anywhere; it travels well. And if you do, you not only have everything you need to play ping pong (a table, paddles, $\infty$ balls, etc.) you also have thousands of people of every possible skill level always ready and eager to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you enter the game, it&amp;rsquo;s like standing at a ping pong table. Toss the ball from one hand, hit it with the paddle in the other. Simple. The physics is realistic. Lag, when present, is handled pretty well. When you hit the ball into the net, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to reach over and pick it up. When you hit the ball out, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to walk over and pick it up. You have infinity balls, and can play against AI opponents with infinity patience. You can play against real people too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m beyond excited by this game. Being able to play ping pong with anyone around the world from the comfort of my own home is a science fiction future turned reality I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I was missing. If you have the game &amp;ndash; it works on all sorts of different VR systems with cross-system play handled just fine &amp;ndash; do let me know. I would love to say hi over a game of table tennis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect multiple future snippets will contain musings about directions the game could go in, and I very much looking forward to seeing the game develop. 🏓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
