<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spaced-repetition | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/spaced-repetition/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/spaced-repetition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>spaced-repetition</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>spaced-repetition</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/spaced-repetition/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition Update</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-05-spaced-repetition-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-05-spaced-repetition-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously I&amp;rsquo;ve written about 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-02-spaced-repetition-in-roam-research/&#34;&gt;how I do spaced repetition in Roam Research&lt;/a&gt; using Leitner Boxes. I&amp;rsquo;m still doing spaced repetition daily, but my methods have changed a bit. So, let me give you the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still doing spaced repetition in Roam, but I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from the Leitner Box approach. Now instead I use 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aidam38/roamsr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adam Krivka&amp;rsquo;s roam/sr&lt;/a&gt;. With this approach, each card has it&amp;rsquo;s own review schedule instead of being lumped together into a small total number of review buckets. Also, the review process is nicer looking and lower friction (especially on mobile) compared to my original Leitner Box approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made the switch to roam/sr on July 5, and haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day since. It&amp;rsquo;s been three months so far. Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it up! In that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve created 1383 cards. That&amp;rsquo;s 15 new cards a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main way in which I make cards these days is with my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-29-note-taking-flow/&#34;&gt;Browserflow Note-taking Flow&lt;/a&gt;. With this flow, I highlight &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of a sentence or paragraph and press c (for a sentence) or b (for a paragraph) to turn that sentence or paragraph  into a &amp;ldquo;cloze&amp;rdquo; task. The highlighted part becomes a fill-in-the-blank and the whole sentence/paragraph becomes a card in my spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also using Adam Krivka&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/roam-depot-developers/page/fIR-UkBAL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;image occlusion plugin&lt;/a&gt; for Roam to create visual cloze tasks. With it, I&amp;rsquo;ll mask out part of an image to create a spaced repetition card asking me to predict what&amp;rsquo;s missing in the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m mainly using spaced repetition to study Croatian. I also have plenty of cards relating to medicine, astrophysics, economics, science in the news, computer science and machine learning, math, and more. There&amp;rsquo;s a long tail of topics I dove into, taking notes with Browserflow, that now populate my cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical review session is about 50-80 cards, with a couple of days peaking over 100 cards. I add cards in clusters, so my &amp;ldquo;new cards&amp;rdquo; pile varies from having 0 cards to having about 100 cards. I limit myself to studying 25 new cards per day, occasionally allowing this to reach up to 50 or 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaced repetition has become a morning habit for me. Usually the first thing I do each morning is a review session, whereas I more often make new cards at night. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve kept the habit up for over 90 days consecutively (and have been doing SRS for over a year now off-and-on), I expect the real challenge to my habit will come the next time I travel extensively. Hopefully by being aware of this challenge now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep the habit through it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-3 for Spaced Repetition</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-08-gpt-3-for-spaced-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-08-gpt-3-for-spaced-repetition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Browserflow to create spaced repetition flashcards quickly while browsing the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a card, I highlight a bit of text and press &amp;ldquo;c&amp;rdquo;. This copies the sentence containing the highlight into the card, with the part I highlighted masked out.
It&amp;rsquo;s a cloze task, as in a masked language model.
If instead I push &amp;ldquo;b&amp;rdquo;, it copies the full paragraph containing the highlight, again with the highlight masked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually this is a great way to quickly create my flashcards. However, sometimes I get sentences where the subject is unclear without context, e.g. &amp;ldquo;this&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;Usually this is a great way to quickly create the flashcards.&amp;rdquo; For these, it would be great to automatically rewrite the sentence with the subject pulled in from the surrounding context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &amp;ldquo;Usually this is a great way to quickly create the flashcards&amp;rdquo; could be rewritten as &amp;ldquo;Usually &lt;mark&gt;using &amp;ldquo;b&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;c&amp;rdquo; with Browserflow&lt;/mark&gt; is a great way to quickly create the flashcards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a second example, consider this 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Solar/meteor.html#c3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HyperPhysics page on the Murchison Meteorite&lt;/a&gt;. Speaking about the Murchison Meteorite, the page says &amp;ldquo;Seventy four amino acids were found in it, compared to the 20 which are characteristic of life.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d love to make a card saying &amp;ldquo;Seventy four &lt;mark&gt;amino acids&lt;/mark&gt; were found in the Murchison Meteorite, compared to the 20 which are characteristic of life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if I highlight &lt;mark&gt;amino acids&lt;/mark&gt; and press &amp;ldquo;c&amp;rdquo;, the generated card instead reads: &amp;ldquo;Seventy four &lt;mark&gt;amino acids&lt;/mark&gt; were found in &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt;, compared to the 20 which are characteristic of life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the challenge I present you with is: write a program that takes a sentence, and it&amp;rsquo;s surrounding context, and rewrites the sentence so that it is clear even out of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played with GPT-3 and Codex recently, this seems well within the scope of large pretrained language models. I expect that with some careful prompting, a large language model could excel at this task without even any fine-tuning, just taking advantage of few shot learning. Is this the best or simplest approach? Likely it isn&amp;rsquo;t, but it may be the approach that minimizes development time and is easiest to repurpose for other similar (or dissimilar) projects in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Global Spaced Repetition (incomplete)</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-16-dgsrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-16-dgsrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I envision a decentralized global spaced repetition system (DGSRS).
Anyone in the world can participate, submitting entries that they&amp;rsquo;d like the world to remember.
To participate, you both need to review entries that others want reviewed, and submit an occasional entry yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main benefits to the individual participating in the DGSRS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can ensure that the idea you care about is never forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can be exposed to interesting new ideas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly, the system acts like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each participant can submit entries. When an entry is submitted, provided the submitter is in good standing and the entry doesn&amp;rsquo;t get flagged as being inappropriate or out of scope (too hard for a single entry, nonsense, etc), the system guarantees the entry will be remembered forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is appealing to countries trying to preserve a language, to researchers who think they have a good idea that the world isn&amp;rsquo;t latching on to,
to conlang enthusiasts trying to bring a new language into existance, to first-time authors, and to creatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition at a Community Scale</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-15-community-spaced-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-15-community-spaced-repetition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spaced repetition is great for individual learners, but can we apply it to the preservation of institutional knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would that look like? Maybe it means dedicating some fraction of some employee time to revisiting old documentation and bringing it up to date.
Maybe it involves periodic runthroughs of playbooks to ensure they&amp;rsquo;re still working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a reason to want the exponential backoff property of individual spaced repetition when applying it to institutions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many people need to be familiar with an idea to adequately ensure that idea will be &amp;ldquo;cross-pollinated&amp;rdquo; with other ideas it pairs well with?
Are there old but important ideas that have fallen out of favor, that a global &amp;ldquo;spaced repetition&amp;rdquo; employed by the whole scientific community would have pointed us to, leading to useful connections otherwise unseen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a multiplayer system, how is it decided what ideas are worth revisiting, and how often? Is it an automated system based on citations, or based on committees? Is it decentralized, with each participant in control of their own SRS and its algorithm, or is a central governing body required. I expect a decentralized system requiring little to no trust could be devised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to revisit this idea and consider it a little more deeply &amp;ndash; after some delay, of course &amp;ndash; in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition in Roam Research</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-02-spaced-repetition-in-roam-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-02-spaced-repetition-in-roam-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to do spaced repetition in Roam Research. This post describes mine. I was inspired to start this two months ago by reading 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic on spaced repetition&lt;/a&gt;, and I highly recommend the read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spaced repetition&amp;rdquo; just means studying flashcards, studying the cards you know best less often, and study the cards you struggle with more often. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful technique for learning and remembering material, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a student or a lifelong learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system I use is based on a classic system called the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; method. I&amp;rsquo;ll first describe how to use the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; approach in Roam, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the adjustments I made to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-a-leitner-box&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box&amp;rdquo; system of spaced repetition, there are seven boxes numbered Box 1 through Box 7. When you create a flashcard, you place it into Box 1. Every day, you use a schedule to determine which boxes of cards to review. The cards in box 1 get reviewed most often, and the cards in box 7 get reviewed least often. When you review a card, you move it up a box (e.g. from box 1 to 2 or from box 4 to 5) if you get the card right. But if you get a card wrong, you move the card back to box 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default Leitner Box schedule looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FpW7FsufOIr.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=3cbd07b1-11e5-4389-896d-9a181f6529fc&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you read this schedule?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colored circles represent the different Leitner Boxes. The red circles represent Box 1, the orange circles represent Box 2, the yellow circles represent Box 3, all the way up to the final pink circle that represents Box 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers along the bottom are &amp;ldquo;session numbers&amp;rdquo;. For your first review session, you look at the circles above &amp;ldquo;01&amp;rdquo; (Boxes 2 and 1). For your second review session, you look at the circles above &amp;ldquo;02&amp;rdquo; (Boxes 3 and 1). Always review boxes for a given day in order from highest to lowest. After completing session &amp;ldquo;64&amp;rdquo;, the schedule wraps around and your next session is session &amp;ldquo;01&amp;rdquo; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap, (1) you put new flashcards into Box 1. (2) When you get a card correct, you move it up a box. (3) When you get a card incorrect, you move it all the way back to Box 1. (4) You use the schedule made of colored dots to decide which boxes to review each day, answering questions in higher boxes first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-leitner-boxes-in-roam&#34;&gt;Setting up Leitner Boxes in Roam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system is all well and good. How do we put it into practice? Here I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly describe (1) getting set up, (2) creating new flashcards, and (3) how to do a review session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up:&lt;/strong&gt; You can use my template; simply copy and paste the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/GPfhcUug&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; text at the bottom of the page here&lt;/a&gt; into Roam Research, e.g. onto a new page named &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo;. For this to work you need to copy from the region that says &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;RAW paste data&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/zvjFKZAb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;get the enhanced template (recommended; see below) here&lt;/a&gt;. Again, be sure to copy from the region that says &amp;ldquo;RAW paste data&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default template creates a page for each of the seven Leitner boxes. It also puts the default schedule on the page, and gives you a place to keep track of what session number you&amp;rsquo;re up to. It will also add two questions to your Leitner Box 1 (one about avocados, and one about Cloze deletions), and includes some basic instructions for how to do spaced repetition in Roam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating New Flashcards:&lt;/strong&gt; You can create a new card anywhere in your Roam graph simply by tagging a note with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo;. Here are two ways to create cards in Roam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the question on one bullet, and put the answer in the child bullets. Then tag the bullet with the question with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo; to add it to your spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the syntax {{=: question | answer}} in Roam to create text that remains hidden until clicked. The text &amp;ldquo;answer&amp;rdquo; won&amp;rsquo;t appear until you click on the text &amp;ldquo;question.&amp;rdquo; Again, tag the line with &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo; to add it to your spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend you 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/prompts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s notes on &amp;ldquo;How to write good prompts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for tips on how to create good flashcards. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic: &amp;ldquo;How to Remember Anything Forever-ish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; also has good suggestions for how to create good questions for spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to do a Review Session:&lt;/strong&gt; Visit your &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo; page to figure out what session number to do. Increment the session number, and use the schedule to determine which Leitner boxes you&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at in this session. Remember, do the Leitner boxes in decreasing order of their number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each Leitner box, visit its page in Roam. All your questions will appear in the Linked References section of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go through the questions one by one. If you get the answer correct, increment the box number by 1. If you get the answer incorrect or struggle with it, set the tag back to &amp;ldquo;#[[Leitner Box 1]]&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about sending things back to box 1; you&amp;rsquo;ll see those questions very often and soon they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in the higher numbered boxes again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enhancements-beyond-the-default-system&#34;&gt;Enhancements Beyond the Default System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made several changes to the default Leitner Box system to improve it to my taste. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to use them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leitner Boxes 0 and $\infty$:&lt;/strong&gt; I use an extra box, &amp;ldquo;Leitner Box 0&amp;rdquo; for flashcards that I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to put into my rotation yet. I try to only add at most 10 cards a day to keep the total review workload low. If I have more cards than this, I keep them in Box 0 until I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start studying them, at which point I move them to Box 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leitner Box $\infty$ is for cards that have graduated from Box 7. In theory, I will remember these cards for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra box 5s, 6s, and 7s:&lt;/strong&gt; I have decided to create two Box 5s (named 5A and 5B), four Box 6s (6A, 6B, 6C, and 6D), and eight Box 7s (7A through 7H). This prevents any individual review session from accumulating too many cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran a simulation and under the default system, adding 10 new cards a day and getting 95% of cards correct, some review sessions will require reviewing over 700 cards! Under the enhanced system, the longest review session will only ever be 140 cards (and most review sessions are much shorter than that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the modified schedule that allows me to use these extra boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2F_dSM-MMp85.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=b3682748-8ea4-4444-97df-0c4592beb1ff&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FhFRPfzGpwy.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=20b7f689-4117-4901-a806-846b0d099d7d&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this enhanced schedule, first use the review session number to figure out which column of colored circles to look at. As before, a red circle indicates Leitner Box 1, a yellow circle indicates Leitner Box 2, etc. If the circle has a letter inside it, that means to review that particular variant of the box. E.g. a blue circle with a &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; inside means to review Leitner box 5B. The arrow to the right of a box indicates which box you should move the card to if you get it correct. E.g. in review session &amp;ldquo;51&amp;rdquo; you should review box 5B and move correct cards to box 6D; you should then review boxes 2 and 1 as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed the box list:&lt;/strong&gt; I use Roam Research&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;embed block&amp;rdquo; feature to embed a list of all Leitner Boxes onto all my Leitner Box pages. This makes it easy to quickly navigate from any box to any other box. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a good way to include this in the template, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to add this yourself if you want to include it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pastebin.com/zvjFKZAb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;access the enhanced version of the template here&lt;/a&gt;. It includes more Leitner boxes and the more complicated schedule. To use it, simply paste it into a new page in Roam Research, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Spaced Repetition&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spaced-repetition-alternatives&#34;&gt;Spaced Repetition Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways of doing spaced repetition in Roam, of which this is just one. Note that most spaced repetition systems in Roam Research use the &amp;ldquo;delta&amp;rdquo; feature. However, we are not using this feature. CortexFutura provides 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cortexfutura.com/preliminary-spaced-repetition-roam/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a way of using the delta feature for spaced repetition here&lt;/a&gt;. Roam Toolkit provides another system for doing spaced repetition in Roam, which you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=08o8q_bOedw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view on YouTube here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular spaced repetition systems is called 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s great for language learning. I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss not to mention it. The reason I prefer doing spaced repetition directly in Roam is that the friction to creating cards is much lower in Roam for me, since I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes and writing my ideas in there already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally RemNote, a competitor note-taking tool to Roam, also offers a highly configurable spaced repetition system out-of-the-box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, consider joining the conversation in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam Research Slack&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;spaced-repetition&amp;rdquo; channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-advantages-of-this-system-over-traditional-spaced-repetition-systems&#34;&gt;Two advantages of this system over traditional spaced repetition systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower friction:&lt;/strong&gt; Creating cards directly in your note-taking app is substantially easier than needing to task switch to create cards. This lower mental overhead makes it easier to keep using spaced repetition for an extended period of time. I started using it two months ago myself, so finger&amp;rsquo;s crossed it indeed is something I keep up for much longer! 🤞&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robustness to vacations:&lt;/strong&gt; In traditional spaced repetition systems, taking a break for a day, week, or month, can be ruinous to your spaced repetition rhythm. After coming back from the break, you find you have too many cards to review all at once, which can be a real motivation drain. Instead of organizing cards by &lt;strong&gt;date&lt;/strong&gt;, my system organizes them by &lt;strong&gt;review session number.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that if you skip a day or a week, your reviews simply get pushed back. The review session number won&amp;rsquo;t go up while you&amp;rsquo;re away. You can even split a review session over multiple days if you like. No trouble! You&amp;rsquo;ll never be left with a review session that&amp;rsquo;s too big to handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/remember/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&amp;rsquo;s comic: &amp;ldquo;How to Remember Anything Forever-ish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is what inspired me to start using spaced repetition in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://withorbit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Orbit&amp;rdquo; system&lt;/a&gt; enables writers to incorporate spaced repetition directly into their writing, to help their readers remember what they learned forever. You can read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://quantum.country/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quantum Country&lt;/a&gt; to learn quantum computing and give it a try. You could also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/prompts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read his tips for &amp;ldquo;How to write good prompts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which is also written with Orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;get Anki here&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.remnote.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;try RemNote here&lt;/a&gt;. I also have a dozen+ other 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;snippets about Roam here&lt;/a&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-25-introducing-snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s a “snippet”?&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a good discussion about spaced repetition. You can email me at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;spaced-repetition@gmail.com&#34;&gt;david810+spaced-repetition@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, find me on Twitter (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/@Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@Bieber&lt;/a&gt;), or join the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam slack&lt;/a&gt; to keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Adriana put things in my Leitner Box</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-07-letting-adriana-put-things-in-my-leitner-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 08:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-07-letting-adriana-put-things-in-my-leitner-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using spaced repetition for 2-3 weeks now. I’m not using Anki or any of the prebuilt systems that track your queue of items for you. Instead, I’m keeping the things I want to study in Roam Research and using a make-shift system of tags and Browserflow Flows to make the spaced repetition system relatively frictionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll save the details of the system for another snippet. Today, I just want to jot down the idea of allowing Adriana (through the use of Bieber Bot) to add items to my spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is relatively simple, but it does involve one new component that may be tricky to implement robustly. Under this idea, Adriana would be able to send Bieber Bot a message saying e.g. “help David to learn the names of the planets” and a card would be added to my spaced repetition system saying “learn the names of the planets. -Adriana”. I could then split this card into multiple cards as I usually do when I encounter a card with too much content simultaneously, or Adriana could have Bieber Bot add smaller cards one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new component that would be necessary is giving Bieber Bot edit access to my Roam Research database. Currently he has delayed read access through Roam-to-Git, but giving him write access might mean teaching him how to use Roam in a (headless, most likely) browser. Nothing he can’t handle, but it would increase the amount of time needed to get this system up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Adriana (or any of Bieber Bot’s friends) can add cards into my spaced repetition system, this can be a fun way to learn about new topics and share new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Pico</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-03-14-principles-of-pico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-03-14-principles-of-pico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an attempt at capturing and organizing my thoughts on Pico, from our conversation about it March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, an attempt at an overview of the Pico system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You enter cards through a variety of sources. You can enter cards manually, like flash cards. You can also import cards from your note taking software. Cards can also be created from your contacts list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, Pico shows you these cards in an Anki-meets-Tinder swipe-based spaced repetition manner. You get a stack of cards, and each card presents you with a suggested action you should take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with idea X from your notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to person Y from your contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a passage from book Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to perform the action on the card, swiping right. Or you can ignore the card and get the next one on the stack by swiping left. The app automatically learns which cards are good to show you. Ideally it helps you to read more, to reengage with your own ideas over time, and to keep in touch with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of things to like about this! I&amp;rsquo;m now going to take a stab at separating out the goals of Pico, the mechanism of Pico, and the specific tasks that Pico targets today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distilling-the-principles-of-pico&#34;&gt;Distilling the Principles of Pico&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals are noble. At a high level, Pico aims to help you spend less time on addictive websites with infinite scroll, and more time doing things that matter to you. I applaud anything that sets out to help you reclaim your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think mentally it helps to separate the mechanism of managing attention that Pico provides from the specific tasks it helps its users to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism seems to operate around these three principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;offloaded memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entropy injection (offloaded decision making)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific tasks it helps with are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brainstorming / reengaging with old ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(re)connecting with people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;studying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the mechanism is general enough that other specific tasks can easily be slotted in as cards in the Pico system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, stop me if I&amp;rsquo;ve misrepresented Pico so far. Let me tell you what I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-purposeness&#34;&gt;General Purposeness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Pico has some really solid ideas underlying it. Particularly I find the idea of using spaced repetition to reengage with your ideas quite compelling.
The idea of using cards to dive into passages of books is also appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using spaced repetition to reengage with your friends seems a tricky thing to get right, since it risks dehumanizing the relationships without special care taken both by the developer (you) and the user of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these different types of cards seems like it comes with lots of room for domain specific tailoring. For example, if a card represents a passage of a book, the user may want to quickly dive into the full book (not just the passage), and then to create a new card at the end of their reading session so they can continue reading from where they left off later.
If a card represents an idea from my notes, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to read the surrounding notes in my note taking software, where I&amp;rsquo;m best able to engage with the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting each of these domains right in a single app (or through clean interactions with other systems) seems like a difficult challenge, but potentially quite rewarding if done well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-entry&#34;&gt;Data Entry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect the usability of Pico will be a big part of what makes the Pico experience pleasant or not. Data entry and the whole card creation process seems like one of the tricky things to get right. If I want to create cards for studying, based on my notes, then I&amp;rsquo;ll want to be taking those notes in some other software (unless you&amp;rsquo;re also building a Roam / RemNote competitor too!). Going from this other software into Pico can be challenging because there are many possible &amp;ldquo;other softwares&amp;rdquo; that people could be coming from and many possible formats people could be taking notes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the book reading case, the experience I would want would be that when I&amp;rsquo;m reading a PDF or eBook a card is automatically created for each book I&amp;rsquo;ve opened, that is automatically kept up to date with the part of the book that I&amp;rsquo;m up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overwhelmed-by-cards&#34;&gt;Overwhelmed by Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thought comes from my inexperience with spaced-repetition software systems. It seems like with traditional spaced repetition algorithms, it can be easy to get overwhelmed by a backlog of cards to review if you take a few days (or heavens forbid a week!) off of review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing spaced repetition in Roam Research using an adhoc system I threw together for myself using Browserflow. Instead of having specific days on which to review cards, they get reviewed in a specific review session. If I skip a day, all future review sessions just come a day later; the backlog doesn&amp;rsquo;t grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pico is a method for spending your time with intention. This is fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding of the &amp;ldquo;Principles of Pico&amp;rdquo; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend less time on things you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be doing (Facebook, Twitter, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time on things you do want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use external mechanisms and automation to guide you toward these good uses of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use gamification to increase time spent on these productive uses of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn from experience what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with your own ideas using spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reengage with people using spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn things via spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 100% on board with these principles and am very excited to see where Pico lands a year from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heads up that I wrote most of this snippet back on March 14, 2020, and then only finished it up and published it today December 20, 2020. So, forgive the delay and let&amp;rsquo;s continue the conversation some time in the next ten months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
