<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>peer-learning-group | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>peer-learning-group</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>peer-learning-group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning about LASIK</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-08-laser-eye-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-08-laser-eye-surgery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My topic for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-11-peer-learning-group-topics/&#34;&gt;March 2021 Peer Learning Group&lt;/a&gt; was &amp;ldquo;Laser Eye Surgery.&amp;rdquo; So, I spent an hour learning about LASIK. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-name-lasik&#34;&gt;The name &amp;ldquo;LASIK&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LASIK stands for Laser-assisted in situ keratomileusis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lasers&lt;/strong&gt;, which you&amp;rsquo;re probably familiar, emit high power beams of light. This is useful for laser eye surgery because a computer-guided laser can be used to precisely burn away pieces of your cornea in order to reshape your eye and correct your vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In situ&lt;/strong&gt; is Latin for &amp;ldquo;on site&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;in position&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keratomileusis&lt;/strong&gt; comes from the Greek &lt;em&gt;κέρας&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;kéras&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;horn&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;σμίλευσις&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;smileusis&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;carving&lt;/em&gt;, and refers to the reshaping of the cornea that is central to LASIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-lasik-work&#34;&gt;How does LASIK work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laser eye surgery uses a laser to reshape the cornea in your eye. By reshaping the cornea, it changes how your eye refracts light. And if done correctly (as it usually is!), this improves your vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access the cornea, the eye surgeon first cuts a flap into the surface of the cornea. This allows the surgeon to move that part of the cornea out of the way, exposing the remainder of the cornea. Once the flap is lifted, the surgeon uses a laser to reshape the cornea. Finally, the flap is returned to its original position and allowed to heal naturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we summarize the process of LASIK with three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut a flap into the cornea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reshape the cornea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reposition the flap to heal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the steps one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-cutting-a-flap-into-the-cornea&#34;&gt;1. Cutting a flap into the cornea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main approaches used for cutting this initial flap into the cornea: using a microkeratome or a femtosecond laser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A microkeratome is not a laser: it&amp;rsquo;s a mechanical device, basically a knife. That&amp;rsquo;s right, with the microkeratome approach the surgeon is more-or-less taking a knife to your eye.
It&amp;rsquo;s a special knife though, designed to create the micron-thin slip in the cornea needed to prepare your eye for LASIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second approach is the femtosecond laser, so called because its pulses last a few femtoseconds. That&amp;rsquo;s less than a picosecond! ($1\text{ fs} = 10^{-15}\text{ s}$)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flap we&amp;rsquo;re making here is really thin, measuring just 83 to 200 micrometers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4089871/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; discusses common considerations in management and complications of the flap-cutting step in femtosecond laser LASIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the possible complications? The paper lists &amp;ldquo;incomplete or partial flaps, free flaps, buttonholes, and small irregular flaps&amp;rdquo; as possible complications when using a microkeratome. The paper also describes the complications as &amp;ldquo;plaguing refractive surgeons&amp;rdquo; rather than plaguing the patients, which I think may be misdirected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding is that femtosecond laser LASIK was steadily on the rise in 2008, and perhaps at this point is the standard approach to LASIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper linked above lists these advantages of femtosecond LASIK over microkeratome LASIK: flap thickness reproducibility, wavefront measurements, stromal bed quality, and biomechanical outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what approach to cutting the flap the surgeon uses, this step takes just a couple of seconds. In fact, the whole procedure is rather short, lasting no more than a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-reshaping-the-cornea&#34;&gt;2. Reshaping the cornea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the central step of LASIK! This is the step that can actually improve your vision. A computer-guided excimer laser removes part of the cornea, reshaping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;computer-guided excimer laser&amp;rdquo;? It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful and precise laser capable of removing as little as 0.25 microns of tissue at a time. The &amp;ldquo;computer-guided&amp;rdquo; part of the laser uses eye-tracking to adjust where it cuts in response to any eye-movements you make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the perks of using a computer-guided laser is that it can respond quickly to any eye or head movements you make. If you move a little, it adjusts where it cuts. If you move too much, it shuts off the laser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia informs me that the term &amp;ldquo;excimer&amp;rdquo; in excimer laser is a bit of a misnomer, and that &amp;ldquo;exciplex&amp;rdquo; would be more correct. An exciplex is an &lt;em&gt;excited complex&lt;/em&gt;, in our case an excited noble gas halide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this step of LASIK, the excimer laser adjusts the shape of the cornea in order to correct the patient&amp;rsquo;s vision. Reshaping the cornea is an effective technique for correcting nearsightedness, farsightedness, and astigmatism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearsightedness occurs when the shape of your eye causes light to refract incorrectly such that images are focused in front of your retina, rather than directly &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; your retina. Similarly, farsightedness occurs when your the shape of your eye causes the image to focus behind your retina. Vision impairments like these are perfect candidates for fixing with LASIK, since they can be remedied simply by modifying the shape of your cornea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To correct nearsightedness, the excimer laser is used to flatten the cornea. This causes incoming light to refract less, such that the focal point is moved further back, toward your retina. For farsightedness, the laser makes the cornea steeper, bringing the focal point forward in your eye. For an astigmatism, it aims to smooth the cornea into a more symmetrical shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-repositioning-the-flap-to-heal&#34;&gt;3. Repositioning the flap to heal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the cornea has been reshaped, the surgeon repositions the flap over the cornea. This acts as a natural bandage, and the cornea heals quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-anesthesia-used&#34;&gt;Is anesthesia used?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, eye numbing drops are given. You&amp;rsquo;re awake the whole time though. If you move a little, the computer-guidance will account for it. If you move too much, the laser will shut off automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks&#34;&gt;Risks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loss of vision is very rare. Dry eyes is common. Temporary vision problems like glare are common too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the complete list of risks I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dry eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glare, halos, double vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undercorrections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcorrections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astigmatism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flap problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision loss or changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For myself, I would (naively) be primarily worried about regression. That said, it does seem to be an uncommon issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;costs&#34;&gt;Costs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LASIK is not usually covered by insurance, as it is typically considered elective surgery. The cost of LASIK is reported to be between $\text{\$1,000}$ and $\text{\$3,000}$ per eye. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vsp.com/eyewear-wellness/lasik-glasses-lenses/lasik-eye-surgery-cost&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSP has this page&lt;/a&gt; with a list of questions you should ask to understand exactly what is included in the cost of LASIK (Pre- and post- operative care? Follow-up procedures if fine-tuning is needed? One eye or two?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-questions&#34;&gt;Open questions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind I only spent about an hour researching LASIK. There are many questions I am not qualified to answer. Here are some of the questions I still have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How common are each of the risks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the flap moved out of the way? How is it repositioned?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do the medical devices and surgery actually look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For myself, I would be concerned that my vision changes too quickly. Is there a way to measure this to verify or invalidate this concern?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;peer-learning-group&#34;&gt;Peer Learning Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote up this topic at the conclusion to the March 2021 Peer Learning Group. We&amp;rsquo;re in between Peer Learning Groups right now. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in participating in the next one, you can email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810@gmail.com&#34;&gt;david810@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; to be notified when sign-ups for the next Peer Learning Group session open up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the PLG, I took my notes on Laser Eye Surgery 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/vgNgwbZlz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;in Roam Research here&lt;/a&gt;. The notes are publicly visible (and editable), so feel free to have a look. You can also see an image preview of them below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/vgNgwbZlz&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-08-lasiknotes.png&#34; alt=&#34;My Roam Research notes on Laser Eye Surgery.&#34; height=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2021 Peer Learning Group Topics</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-11-peer-learning-group-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-11-peer-learning-group-topics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have two simultaneous Peer Learning Groups running this month, one on all manner of miscellaneous topics, and one specifically on climate change. Here are the topics we&amp;rsquo;re learning about in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
March 2: Laser eye surgery&lt;br&gt;
March 12: Open-endedness in AI, evolution, and generative art&lt;br&gt;
March 15: The Alexander technique&lt;br&gt;
March 18: Game theory&lt;br&gt;
March 21: A taxonomy of humor&lt;br&gt;
March 22: Perspectives on finance and law&lt;br&gt;
March 24: Postmodernism through Lyotard&lt;br&gt;
March 27: Aging Biology&lt;br&gt;
March 28: Nutrition science&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
March 3: Oil pricing&lt;br&gt;
March 8: Forecasts uncertainties (and expected values)&lt;br&gt;
March 13: Physics of climate change&lt;br&gt;
March 13: Greenhouse effect and atmospheric circulation&lt;br&gt;
March 17: Organizational climate change efforts&lt;br&gt;
March 22: Synthetic meat&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Learning Group Sign Up</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peer Learning Group is an experiment for learning new things and meeting new people. I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to join.
The experiment will last for four weeks, and requires only a small time commitment during this period (just a few hours total).
During these four weeks, you will learn about several topics, and you will also teach the group about one or two topics yourself.
The next peer learning group session will be March 1 - March 28, 2021.
If this interests you, I encourage you to sign up here.
Additional details about &amp;ldquo;how it works&amp;rdquo; below the fold. We&amp;rsquo;re 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/&#34;&gt;making some changes&lt;/a&gt; compared to the first group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfxG5T0ljW4DAKTM5M0nedNnkMmxxAPgywwv0VZcFAAlWR0yQ/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;920&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 1, everyone will be added to a Facebook Messenger group chat. I&amp;rsquo;m targeting a group of about 6-8 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, I will be contacting everyone to learn what they are interested in learning about. I&amp;rsquo;ll coordinate with you to figure out 1 or 2 topics for you to teach the group about. We&amp;rsquo;ll try to choose topics that both excite you &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;em&gt;someone else&lt;/em&gt; in the group is interested in. We&amp;rsquo;ll also select a day for you to do the learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the chosen day, you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to spend about an hour learning about the selected topic, and sharing what you learn with the group chat. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to learn about the topic in advance, but that&amp;rsquo;s absolutely not required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned with the group is up to you, but the bar is low. There&amp;rsquo;s no expectation of putting together a lesson plan. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m envisioning you &amp;ldquo;live tweeting&amp;rdquo; interesting things as you learn them, putting quotes, images, and explanations into the chat that you think communicate the main ideas clearly. But I&amp;rsquo;ll reiterate: how you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned is completely up to you, and we&amp;rsquo;re setting our expectations low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone else is welcome to discuss, ask questions, share insights, etc. The chat is there for you to use how you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since an hour is a relatively short period of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to allocate topics to you that are at the fringes of your expertise already. My theory is that while an hour is fairly short, it will still be really rewarding to hear what someone else learns from a concentrated hour of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the four week period, you&amp;rsquo;ll have &amp;ldquo;presented&amp;rdquo; once or twice, and collectively we&amp;rsquo;ll have learned about ~10 different topics in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to meet people and learn new things, and also to have fun. So come curious and with an open mind, and we&amp;rsquo;ll do our best to make this an interesting and enjoyable month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways to improve Peer Learning Group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this snippet I list out things I plan to do to improve Peer Learning Group for a future iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-fewer-topics-per-day&#34;&gt;1. Fewer topics per day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round of Peer Learning Group, we had a topic almost every single day, with just two days off in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next round, I&amp;rsquo;ll either have fewer people or a longer period of time for the program (e.g. 4-6 weeks), such that there&amp;rsquo;s only ever someone teaching every 3-5 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives more time to think, reflect, and breathe. More time to have adhoc discussions without feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re talking out of turn. More time for questions and connections between topics to bubble up. More time for unrelated topics to come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-give-people-topics-theyre-interested-in&#34;&gt;2. Give people topics they&amp;rsquo;re interested in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round of Peer Learning Group, I aimed to give people topics at the edge of their expertise. I tried to give people a topic that would really interest &lt;em&gt;someone else&lt;/em&gt; in the group. In the next iteration, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to pick topics for people that more closely align with their own interests. Still not things that they&amp;rsquo;re experts in already, but rather topics that they&amp;rsquo;re excited to learn about themselves. I&amp;rsquo;ll still aim to make sure the topics we choose are interesting to other people in the group too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-choose-a-unifying-theme-for-the-group-maybe&#34;&gt;3. Choose a unifying theme for the group, maybe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round, the topics were pretty diverse: we had &amp;ldquo;cultivating conscious leadership&amp;rdquo;, the Ethereum EVM, Jungian archetypes, Microbubbles, carcinisation, complexity management, and several more. There was minimal overlap in the ~40 topic suggestions I received while setting up the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next round, I&amp;rsquo;m toying with the idea of picking an overarching topic, like climate change, machine learning, math, or physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious to hear what people think of this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-encourage-use-of-background-knowledge&#34;&gt;4. Encourage use of background knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more about my own teaching experience than running the group overall. As I was teaching my topic (Asynchronous Teaching), I was initially reticent to share things I already knew, instead focusing on sharing only what I learned during my teaching session. In retrospect, it is definitely valuable to share background knowledge, not just newly obtained information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious to hear if other people had a similar experience to myself on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-include-a-synchronous-component&#34;&gt;5. Include a synchronous component&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much everything was asynchronous in the first group. Not too late to change this though! Even though our Peer Learning Group experiment is coming to a close, we can still set up a synchronous social gathering for next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-ask-more-questions&#34;&gt;6. Ask more questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a personal change I would make, not a group change. In the next round, I&amp;rsquo;m going to make more of an effort to ask well thought out questions on many of the topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thank-you&#34;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the first Peer Learning Group. Every evening there was a new thread about an interesting topic delivered to my inbox via messenger. We learned so much, and I had a great time with it. Big &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt; to all the participants for making this experiment a success 🙏 🎉. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it at all without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/&#34;&gt;leave feedback on Peer Learning Group here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up&#34;&gt;sign up for the next Peer Learning Group here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Learning Group Feedback</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can use this form to submit feedback about the January 25, 2021 - February 7, 2021 Peer Learning Group. Make sure to leave your name or email if you want a response, otherwise its anonymous. You can also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://messenger.com/t/dbieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;message me directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSe3kh5uq6OFLakI4Uf7GEMn0POuDqfMUwumKactjHaixfdEAQ/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Peer Learning Group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-14-peer-learning-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-14-peer-learning-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alright. I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with this idea for months now. Perfection is the enemy of the good. It&amp;rsquo;s time to launch a peer learning experiment. Here we go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello!
Peer Learning Group is an experiment for learning new things and meeting new people. And I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to join.
The experiment lasts for two weeks, and requires only a small time commitment during this period (just a few hours total).
During these two weeks, you will learn about several topics, and you will also teach the group about one or two topics yourself.
The first peer learning group session will be January 25 - February 7, 2021.
If this interests you, I encourage you to sign up here.
Additional details about &amp;ldquo;how it works&amp;rdquo; below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf32hojaa3E-v0w8jHXpLThnPJUAQrnFcRHk9kCuGW7pMQZeg/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 25, everyone will be added to a Facebook Messenger group chat. I&amp;rsquo;m targeting a group of about 6-8 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, I will be contacting everyone to learn what they are interested in learning about. I&amp;rsquo;ll coordinate with you to figure out 1 or 2 topics for you to teach the group about. These will be topics that someone &lt;em&gt;else&lt;/em&gt; in the group is interested in. We&amp;rsquo;ll also select a day for you to do the learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the chosen day, you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to spend about an hour learning about the selected topic, and sharing what you learn with the group chat. (You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to learn about the topic in advance, but that&amp;rsquo;s not required!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned with the group is up to you, but the bar is low. There&amp;rsquo;s no expectation of putting together a lesson plan. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m envisioning you &amp;ldquo;live tweeting&amp;rdquo; interesting things as you learn them, putting quotes, images, and explanations into the chat that you think communicate the main ideas clearly. But I&amp;rsquo;ll reiterate: how you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned is completely up to you, and we&amp;rsquo;re setting our expectations low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone else is welcome to discuss, ask questions, share insights, etc. The chat is there for you to use how you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since an hour is a relatively short period of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to allocate topics to you that are at the fringes of your expertise already. My theory is that while an hour is fairly short, it will still be really rewarding to hear what someone else learns from a concentrated hour of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the two week period, you&amp;rsquo;ll have &amp;ldquo;presented&amp;rdquo; once or twice, and collectively we&amp;rsquo;ll have learned about ~10 different topics in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to meet people and learn new things, and also to have fun. So come curious and with an open mind, and we&amp;rsquo;ll do our best to make this an interesting and enjoyable two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
