<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>peer-learning-group | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>peer-learning-group</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>peer-learning-group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/peer-learning-group/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2021 Peer Learning Group Topics</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-11-peer-learning-group-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-11-peer-learning-group-topics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have two simultaneous Peer Learning Groups running this month, one on all manner of miscellaneous topics, and one specifically on climate change. Here are the topics we&amp;rsquo;re learning about in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
March 2: Laser eye surgery&lt;br&gt;
March 12: Open-endedness in AI, evolution, and generative art&lt;br&gt;
March 15: The Alexander technique&lt;br&gt;
March 18: Game theory&lt;br&gt;
March 21: A taxonomy of humor&lt;br&gt;
March 22: Perspectives on finance and law&lt;br&gt;
March 24: Postmodernism through Lyotard&lt;br&gt;
March 27: Aging Biology&lt;br&gt;
March 28: Nutrition science&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
March 3: Oil pricing&lt;br&gt;
March 8: Forecasts uncertainties (and expected values)&lt;br&gt;
March 13: Physics of climate change&lt;br&gt;
March 13: Greenhouse effect and atmospheric circulation&lt;br&gt;
March 17: Organizational climate change efforts&lt;br&gt;
March 22: Synthetic meat&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Learning Group Sign Up</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peer Learning Group is an experiment for learning new things and meeting new people. I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to join.
The experiment will last for four weeks, and requires only a small time commitment during this period (just a few hours total).
During these four weeks, you will learn about several topics, and you will also teach the group about one or two topics yourself.
The next peer learning group session will be March 1 - March 28, 2021.
If this interests you, I encourage you to sign up here.
Additional details about &amp;ldquo;how it works&amp;rdquo; below the fold. We&amp;rsquo;re 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/&#34;&gt;making some changes&lt;/a&gt; compared to the first group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfxG5T0ljW4DAKTM5M0nedNnkMmxxAPgywwv0VZcFAAlWR0yQ/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;920&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 1, everyone will be added to a Facebook Messenger group chat. I&amp;rsquo;m targeting a group of about 6-8 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, I will be contacting everyone to learn what they are interested in learning about. I&amp;rsquo;ll coordinate with you to figure out 1 or 2 topics for you to teach the group about. We&amp;rsquo;ll try to choose topics that both excite you &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;em&gt;someone else&lt;/em&gt; in the group is interested in. We&amp;rsquo;ll also select a day for you to do the learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the chosen day, you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to spend about an hour learning about the selected topic, and sharing what you learn with the group chat. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to learn about the topic in advance, but that&amp;rsquo;s absolutely not required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned with the group is up to you, but the bar is low. There&amp;rsquo;s no expectation of putting together a lesson plan. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m envisioning you &amp;ldquo;live tweeting&amp;rdquo; interesting things as you learn them, putting quotes, images, and explanations into the chat that you think communicate the main ideas clearly. But I&amp;rsquo;ll reiterate: how you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned is completely up to you, and we&amp;rsquo;re setting our expectations low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone else is welcome to discuss, ask questions, share insights, etc. The chat is there for you to use how you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since an hour is a relatively short period of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to allocate topics to you that are at the fringes of your expertise already. My theory is that while an hour is fairly short, it will still be really rewarding to hear what someone else learns from a concentrated hour of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the four week period, you&amp;rsquo;ll have &amp;ldquo;presented&amp;rdquo; once or twice, and collectively we&amp;rsquo;ll have learned about ~10 different topics in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to meet people and learn new things, and also to have fun. So come curious and with an open mind, and we&amp;rsquo;ll do our best to make this an interesting and enjoyable month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways to improve Peer Learning Group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-ways-to-improve-peer-learning-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this snippet I list out things I plan to do to improve Peer Learning Group for a future iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-fewer-topics-per-day&#34;&gt;1. Fewer topics per day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round of Peer Learning Group, we had a topic almost every single day, with just two days off in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next round, I&amp;rsquo;ll either have fewer people or a longer period of time for the program (e.g. 4-6 weeks), such that there&amp;rsquo;s only ever someone teaching every 3-5 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives more time to think, reflect, and breathe. More time to have adhoc discussions without feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re talking out of turn. More time for questions and connections between topics to bubble up. More time for unrelated topics to come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-give-people-topics-theyre-interested-in&#34;&gt;2. Give people topics they&amp;rsquo;re interested in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round of Peer Learning Group, I aimed to give people topics at the edge of their expertise. I tried to give people a topic that would really interest &lt;em&gt;someone else&lt;/em&gt; in the group. In the next iteration, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to pick topics for people that more closely align with their own interests. Still not things that they&amp;rsquo;re experts in already, but rather topics that they&amp;rsquo;re excited to learn about themselves. I&amp;rsquo;ll still aim to make sure the topics we choose are interesting to other people in the group too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-choose-a-unifying-theme-for-the-group-maybe&#34;&gt;3. Choose a unifying theme for the group, maybe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first round, the topics were pretty diverse: we had &amp;ldquo;cultivating conscious leadership&amp;rdquo;, the Ethereum EVM, Jungian archetypes, Microbubbles, carcinisation, complexity management, and several more. There was minimal overlap in the ~40 topic suggestions I received while setting up the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next round, I&amp;rsquo;m toying with the idea of picking an overarching topic, like climate change, machine learning, math, or physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious to hear what people think of this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-encourage-use-of-background-knowledge&#34;&gt;4. Encourage use of background knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more about my own teaching experience than running the group overall. As I was teaching my topic (Asynchronous Teaching), I was initially reticent to share things I already knew, instead focusing on sharing only what I learned during my teaching session. In retrospect, it is definitely valuable to share background knowledge, not just newly obtained information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious to hear if other people had a similar experience to myself on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-include-a-synchronous-component&#34;&gt;5. Include a synchronous component&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much everything was asynchronous in the first group. Not too late to change this though! Even though our Peer Learning Group experiment is coming to a close, we can still set up a synchronous social gathering for next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-ask-more-questions&#34;&gt;6. Ask more questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a personal change I would make, not a group change. In the next round, I&amp;rsquo;m going to make more of an effort to ask well thought out questions on many of the topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thank-you&#34;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the first Peer Learning Group. Every evening there was a new thread about an interesting topic delivered to my inbox via messenger. We learned so much, and I had a great time with it. Big &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt; to all the participants for making this experiment a success 🙏 🎉. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it at all without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/&#34;&gt;leave feedback on Peer Learning Group here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-07-peer-learning-group-sign-up&#34;&gt;sign up for the next Peer Learning Group here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Learning Group Feedback</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-24-peer-learning-group-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can use this form to submit feedback about the January 25, 2021 - February 7, 2021 Peer Learning Group. Make sure to leave your name or email if you want a response, otherwise its anonymous. You can also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://messenger.com/t/dbieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;message me directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSe3kh5uq6OFLakI4Uf7GEMn0POuDqfMUwumKactjHaixfdEAQ/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Peer Learning Group</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-14-peer-learning-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-14-peer-learning-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alright. I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with this idea for months now. Perfection is the enemy of the good. It&amp;rsquo;s time to launch a peer learning experiment. Here we go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello!
Peer Learning Group is an experiment for learning new things and meeting new people. And I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to join.
The experiment lasts for two weeks, and requires only a small time commitment during this period (just a few hours total).
During these two weeks, you will learn about several topics, and you will also teach the group about one or two topics yourself.
The first peer learning group session will be January 25 - February 7, 2021.
If this interests you, I encourage you to sign up here.
Additional details about &amp;ldquo;how it works&amp;rdquo; below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf32hojaa3E-v0w8jHXpLThnPJUAQrnFcRHk9kCuGW7pMQZeg/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 25, everyone will be added to a Facebook Messenger group chat. I&amp;rsquo;m targeting a group of about 6-8 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, I will be contacting everyone to learn what they are interested in learning about. I&amp;rsquo;ll coordinate with you to figure out 1 or 2 topics for you to teach the group about. These will be topics that someone &lt;em&gt;else&lt;/em&gt; in the group is interested in. We&amp;rsquo;ll also select a day for you to do the learning and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the chosen day, you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to spend about an hour learning about the selected topic, and sharing what you learn with the group chat. (You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to learn about the topic in advance, but that&amp;rsquo;s not required!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned with the group is up to you, but the bar is low. There&amp;rsquo;s no expectation of putting together a lesson plan. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m envisioning you &amp;ldquo;live tweeting&amp;rdquo; interesting things as you learn them, putting quotes, images, and explanations into the chat that you think communicate the main ideas clearly. But I&amp;rsquo;ll reiterate: how you share what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned is completely up to you, and we&amp;rsquo;re setting our expectations low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone else is welcome to discuss, ask questions, share insights, etc. The chat is there for you to use how you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since an hour is a relatively short period of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to allocate topics to you that are at the fringes of your expertise already. My theory is that while an hour is fairly short, it will still be really rewarding to hear what someone else learns from a concentrated hour of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the two week period, you&amp;rsquo;ll have &amp;ldquo;presented&amp;rdquo; once or twice, and collectively we&amp;rsquo;ll have learned about ~10 different topics in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to meet people and learn new things, and also to have fun. So come curious and with an open mind, and we&amp;rsquo;ll do our best to make this an interesting and enjoyable two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
