<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>taking-silly-ideas-seriously | David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/taking-silly-ideas-seriously/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/taking-silly-ideas-seriously/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>taking-silly-ideas-seriously</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=true) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>taking-silly-ideas-seriously</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/taking-silly-ideas-seriously/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Insurance DAOs</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-20-health-insurance-daos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-20-health-insurance-daos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been learning about blockchain tech including Ethereum, smart contracts, and DAOs (distributed autonomous organizations).
With this snippet I want to explore the idea of using a DAO as a substitute for traditional health insurance.
Brainstroming here, I&amp;rsquo;m also intrigued by the ideas of (1) bringing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-11-democratic-delegation-optional-voting/&#34;&gt;democratic delegation-optional voting (DDoV)&lt;/a&gt; into a DAO, (2) implementing a union as a DAO for collective bargaining, and (3) using smart contracts for international agreements 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/20/climate/fossil-fuel-drilling-pledges.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;to avoid climate problems like this&lt;/a&gt;. These are ideas for future snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health insurance at its core is about pooling people&amp;rsquo;s resources to collectively pay for their healthcare.
Typically pooling takes the form of paying premiums to an insurance company.
When healthcare is necessary, someone files a claim and &amp;ndash; subject to the claim&amp;rsquo;s approval &amp;ndash; the insurance company pays for the customer&amp;rsquo;s healthcare.
Most users of health insurance pay more in premiums than is paid out by the health insurance company, and so overall the health insurance company makes money.
But if a customer ever incurs high costs of healthcare, they don&amp;rsquo;t have to bear those costs themself; the insurance company will pay the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re to use a DAO in place of a traditional health insurance company, the overall structure remains the same.
Customers become members of the health insurance DAO (henceforth, &amp;ldquo;HIDAO&amp;rdquo;) by regularly paying a premium to the HIDAO.
Every month in exchange for paying your premium to the HIDAO, you receive a token.
This token indicates your membership in the HIDAO, enabling you to file a claim to receive reimbursement for healthcare costs.
In the first version of the HIDAO, an existing claims adjudication company can be used to validate claims.
A smart contract would use 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/oracles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the oracle pattern&lt;/a&gt; to interface with the adjudicators.
When the adjudicators approve a claim, the HIDAO&amp;rsquo;s smart contract automatically processes it, thereby paying the customer for their healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This set up enables some interesting possibilities beyond what&amp;rsquo;s possible with traditional health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First is lower costs. Since there is no centralized for-profit institution here, all excess premiums can be returned to shareholders (the customers themselves!) as dividends. The HIDAO needs to keep some reserves in order to be able to process any unexpected spike in claims or healthcare costs. Beyond this reserve level are funds that would traditionally be operating expenses or profit. Operating expenses are quite low in a DAO (the main ones for the HIDAO would be gas and adjudication costs). By returning the profits to the customers, and by keeping operating expenses low with smart contracts, the costs of health insurance can be kept low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second is collective negotiation of rates. Traditional insurance companies negotiate rates with providers. This process can be distributed, taking advantage of the distributed governance that DAOs enable to allow participants in the DAO to collectively negotiate rates. This idea requires elaboration in a future snippet. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-11-democratic-delegation-optional-voting/&#34;&gt;DDoV&lt;/a&gt; may be essential to allowing governance to continue smoothly despite potential voter apathy. We can write the smart contract with a mechanism to incentivize participants to negotiate good rates for the HIDAO, e.g. by monetarily rewarding those who negotiate favorable rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third is &lt;strong&gt;Collective Adjudication Overriding&lt;/strong&gt;. Insurance companies notoriously get adjudication wrong some of the time. With a HIDAO, the risk of this could be greater if we&amp;rsquo;re not careful about setting up an appeal process, because the logic of a smart contract by default cannot be overruled. However, we have the option of building into the HIDAO&amp;rsquo;s smart contracts the ability to collectively override the normal adjudication process. We can writ the smart contract such that if members of the HIDAO collectively decide that a claim adjudication decision was invalid, they can collectively override that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth is supporting investing in the HIDAO. The HIDAO could issue tokens (e.g. the tokens given to customers each month) that indicate who is to receive the dividends mentioned in the first point above. Perhaps this could improve the robustness of the HIDAO. This is something to explore more later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifth is &lt;strong&gt;Distributed Adjudication&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a potential way to replace the traditional adjudication company described in the core idea above. The idea here is that we can incentivize people to submit only valid claims, and we can incentivize people to do proper claims adjudication. This idea deserves further elaboration in a future snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly I have an open question: How do you handle someone who has both traditional and HIDAO health insurance? How is double filing of claims prevented in traditional health insurance? Let&amp;rsquo;s say someone expects high healthcare costs. What&amp;rsquo;s stopping them from signing up with two health insurance companies and filing claims with both of them? Probably the terms and conditions and the law. This sounds difficult to account for in the HIDAO smart contract, which ideally need not know about people&amp;rsquo;s other real world contracts with other health insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimistic about this idea. I think that if done well, it could outcompete traditional health insurance. Obviously health insurance is a complicated industry and this is just a quick brainstorming, so the idea has many iterations to go. The ultimate goal is to ensure good health outcomes for everyone, and a part of the story necessarily is bringing down healthcare costs across the board. This is just one piece of that story, but I suspect it may be an importance piece.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Global Spaced Repetition (incomplete)</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-16-dgsrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-16-dgsrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I envision a decentralized global spaced repetition system (DGSRS).
Anyone in the world can participate, submitting entries that they&amp;rsquo;d like the world to remember.
To participate, you both need to review entries that others want reviewed, and submit an occasional entry yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main benefits to the individual participating in the DGSRS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can ensure that the idea you care about is never forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can be exposed to interesting new ideas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly, the system acts like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each participant can submit entries. When an entry is submitted, provided the submitter is in good standing and the entry doesn&amp;rsquo;t get flagged as being inappropriate or out of scope (too hard for a single entry, nonsense, etc), the system guarantees the entry will be remembered forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is appealing to countries trying to preserve a language, to researchers who think they have a good idea that the world isn&amp;rsquo;t latching on to,
to conlang enthusiasts trying to bring a new language into existance, to first-time authors, and to creatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR Gardening</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-09-crispr-gardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-08-09-crispr-gardening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone likes their veggies crisp, so who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want CRISPR veggies?
After reading The Code Breaker, I&amp;rsquo;ve become progressively more excited about the possibilities that gene editing will bring in the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or sooner? The technology has matured remarkably quickly and is developing incredibly fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a full grasp of where things stand today, but this is just a snippet, so I won&amp;rsquo;t let that stop me from speculating about where we&amp;rsquo;re heading. Take everything here with a grain of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we can perform germline gene editing somewhat reliably. It&amp;rsquo;s been done on human beings; the scientist who performed this first, I believe has gone to jail for the ethics violations involved in doing so. Our interest in this snippet, however, doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the full set of ethical qualms that applying gene editing to humans has. We&amp;rsquo;re interested in applying gene editing to plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMOs aren&amp;rsquo;t knew, but they&amp;rsquo;re (at least in the big picture) in their infancy. Today, particular seeds have been patented, leading to monopolistic anti-competitive practices by, for example, Monsanto. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the way gene-editing looks in the future. There&amp;rsquo;s a chance it&amp;rsquo;s more widely accessible and commonly used in ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s homes in the future. Not just through people purchasing GMO seeds (already modified) from a store and planting them, but rather by modifying the genome of a seed in their own home and then planting it in their own garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a very hand-wavy sort of way, here&amp;rsquo;s a bit of what this future history looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COVID makes in-home PCR more affordable more common. Since there&amp;rsquo;s demand for in-home viral testing, the components and skills involved in bioengineering start becoming more commonplace. This is already happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our understanding of the genome is increasing every week. This is already happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will be able to modify the genome of plants using a library of known edits. E.g. take the basil genome, replace GAAT at positive 1004 with TAAG, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get freeze-resistant basil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually people will be able to use software to create genomes using higher-level constructs than directly writing the base-pairs in the desired DNS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First this will mean listing out proteins instead of individual base-pairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later it will involve listing out multi-protein mechanisms, or higher level traits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually it will shift from being &amp;ldquo;like programming&amp;rdquo; to a no-code process, where even children will be able to design plants. They&amp;rsquo;ll sketch the desired leaf shapes, choose the yummiest flavor profiles, select the environment in which the plant should thrive, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages of CRISPR gardening over traditional gardening include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can customize plants that are tailor made for your diet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for your climate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for your aesthetic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; to express your creativity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily share a custom genome on the internet. Sharing the diff from a known genome takes less bandwidth, but even sharing a full genome is easy. This is far easier and more scalable than sharing physical seeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get to this point, it would be useful to have &amp;ldquo;factories&amp;rdquo; / robot-biotech-gardens systematically mutating plant genomes, growing the resultant plants in various ways, and recording the effects. The individual components of this vision are already underway. Companies like IronOx use robots to grow vegetables in warehouses without human intervention. Other companies provide robot-performanced wetlab experiments. Now what we need is to bring these players together, so that we can most efficiently more toward fully understanding plant genomes and the CRISPR gardening era that awaits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, when I have my own house and CRISPR garden, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have garden gnomes &amp;ndash; or g-gnomes for short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Games Inter-company Compact</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-08-healthy-games-inter-company-compact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-08-healthy-games-inter-company-compact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This snippet is a silly, currently unworkable, but in my opinion still worthwhile idea to improve the healthiness of video games. Mobile games today are in an arms race. Make your game more addicting, and your game becomes more profitable. More addicting is not the same as more fun. They may be correlated, but the incentives of video game companies are not wholly aligned with the incentives of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it an &amp;ldquo;arms race&amp;rdquo;? There&amp;rsquo;s limited mindshare. Making your game addicting claims more of this mindshare. More engaging games are more profitable. And there&amp;rsquo;s no easy way for a game company to disentangle unhealthy addictive engagement from increased engagement due to increased quality of the game (is this true? will ponder&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers of these games will A/B test mechanisms and designs and select those that maximize engagement. This isn&amp;rsquo;t unique to video games; it applies to social media and advertising as well, but we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on video games for this snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the &amp;ldquo;Healthy Games Inter-company Compact&amp;rdquo;. This is a hypothetical future agreement between all the video game companies. The &amp;ldquo;Healthy Games Inter-company Compact&amp;rdquo; (HGIC for short) states that once 100% of game companies agree to the compact, all video games will simultaneously reduce the addictiveness of their games by 20% (the specific number&amp;rsquo;s not central to the idea). Signing the agreement does nothing if not all video game companies have signed. Only once all such companies are signed the agreement does it come into effect. At that point, the agreement comes into effect for all companies at once, and all games are simultaneously made less addicting. (This idea is inspired by the real 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Popular_Vote_Interstate_Compact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Popular Vote Interstate Compact&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many reasons why this can&amp;rsquo;t work in practice. In the spirit of taking silly ideas seriously, let&amp;rsquo;s go through those reasons, and perhaps we&amp;rsquo;ll find some of them weaker than first appearance might suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first reason it can&amp;rsquo;t work is that 100% of video game companies agreeing to &amp;ldquo;mutual disarmament&amp;rdquo; would be such an extraordinary feat. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_game_industry#Scope&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; estimates that in the US alone there are 2,300 development companies and over 525 publishing companies. What would a consortium of all video game companies even look like? Why would 10% of companies agree to this compact, let alone 100%? A few could agree to it out of genuine interest in the health of their addiction-prone players. A few others could agree to it if it makes strategic sense for them. Getting to 10% seems farfetched, 100% fantastical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, even if all the current video game companies did agree, the market is such that a new player could enter the video game industry at any time, disregarding the compact. This HGIC would need to be legislation, not just an inter-company compact, for it to apply to new entrants. This is something I am doubtful I would support, even though the HGIC is my idea. It would proabably even take considerable effort to make a legislative version of the HGIC constitutional! (Is game mechanism design a protected form of speech?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, even if all current video game companies signed the HGIC, acted in good faith, and even if there were no possibility of new entrants, there still remain the difficult questions of how to measure the reduction in unhealthy addictiveness of games. As a strawman, the HGIC could specify a metric, say play-time per player, and all companies would reduce their play-time per player by an agreed upon percent. I&amp;rsquo;ll readily acknowledge this sounds ridiculous; it could mean ruining the fun of some games, not making them healthier! As a second strawman, the HGIC could specify specific game mechanics and how to adjust them. E.g. it would specify that count-down timers need to be shortened by X% (does that even help?), non-deterministic rewards need to be made Y% more deterministic, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ll readily acknowledge this strawman is ridiculous too; there are likely too many possible game mechanics for an agreement of this form to be manageable to produce. Finding an equivalent reduction in addictiveness across all games is impossible because games are simply too varied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourthly and finally, &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve shared this idea with so far (three people in total) have disagreed with the premise, that the addicting nature of video games is a negative thing, and that reducing it is desirable. This is a real surprise to me. I thought it was generally accepted that the tactics employed by FarmVille, CandyCrush, Covet, and the like are deliberative exploitative and addictive, designed through experimentation to maximize engagement and profit, and that this is a negative aspect of the games. I suppose I was wrong about this (the generally accepted part, that is). Guess I need to expand my bubble.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have four solid reasons that the Healthy Games Inter-company Compact could never come into effect. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a dozen more. It&amp;rsquo;s nevertheless nice to imagine a world in which a few companies draft and sign the compact, initially thinking it will never come into effect. And then, over time, more companies are drawn to the idea of improving the health of their addiction-prone customers, until eventually the industry enacts and broadly follows guidelines for healthy game development. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a world to aspire to, albeit unrealistic. So while the HGIC in all likelihood won&amp;rsquo;t work, perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s another path there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a glimpse of what people think outside my itsy-bitsy social bubble, you can have a look at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.commonsensemedia.org/app-reviews/candy-crush-saga/user-reviews/adult&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these mixed reviews of CandyCrush from parents and children&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Efficient Minds Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-03-04-the-efficient-minds-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Efficient Minds Hypothesis&amp;rdquo; states that a person is able to reach whatever conclusions they are able to reach in a small finite amount of time. Unless new information is presented, after that small duration no new conclusions will be reached. Stated more succinctly, the Efficient Minds Hypothesis states that &amp;ldquo;thinking is near-instantaneous.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is of course, preposterous. However, when it is not named and stated so explicitly, believing the EMH is an easy trap to fall into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are negative consequences to believing the EMH, even implicitly or subconsciously. It can lead to asking fewer questions. It can lead to scheduling less time for planning and Great Thoughts, and spending too large a proportion of your time on building and chasing short-term goals. It can lead to too much self-reliance, and a reluctance to delegate or share the burden of a project with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Efficient Minds Hypothesis is mainly a strawman that I don&amp;rsquo;t think many people would claim to believe outright, I do think it&amp;rsquo;s an idea that people (at least myself) sometimes believe implicitly. Making it explicit helps to make its status as a fallacy clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write about the Efficient Minds Hypothesis from personal experience. While I don&amp;rsquo;t consciously believe the EMH (as I stated above, I think it&amp;rsquo;s preposterous), I find that beneath the surface of my thoughts I often do believe it, and can act or think accordingly. Being surrounded by creative intelligent people at work, spending every day thinking about challenging problems, the falsity of the EMH (at least with respect to my own mind), has been crystal clear day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its falsity is most clear when a colleague suggests a solution to a problem that I have that I have not seen. The solution feels like something simple enough to arrive at quickly given my experience, but it is apparently not, for it&amp;rsquo;s a solution I did not foresee. On N occasions it has even been the case that I have not even begun to properly start thinking about the problem when a colleague presents the solution, perhaps because there are many possible problems to attend to, and selecting where to place one&amp;rsquo;s attention is a problem in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the EMH, the idea that you can present a problem to a colleague without first having given it the small finite first attempt doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. If EMH were true, you would present only problems that you cannot yourself solve to your colleagues. In the time it takes to present a problem, you would have attempted solving it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maxims of &amp;ldquo;bring me solutions, not problems&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t come to me until you&amp;rsquo;ve worked this out as much as you can on your own&amp;rdquo; are weakened by the lack of an EMH too. Sometimes you need to engage other minds simply to parallelize computation, not because one mind alone cannot solve something. The benefits of multiple minds go beyond parallelization though. Freshness and specialization are two principles that make a collaboration more than the sum of its parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why believe the EMH at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When young, when working on easier problems, when you can anticipate what comes next, when your mind is fresh, well rested, and well equipped for the tasks at hand, the EMH can appear and feel true.
A quick look at any complex task, say chess or a hard math problem, makes it apparent that it&amp;rsquo;s not universally true. But those System 2 tasks do nothing to dispel the EMH in System 1 heavy situations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that thinking takes time. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that System 1 thinking in particular takes time. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that something requires System 2 thought. And finally it isn&amp;rsquo;t always apparent that thinking has bandwidth, and that ideas and projects can be thought-bandwidth bottlenecked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is that we need to be deliberate with how we choose to spend our brainpower. And this starts with being mindful and intentional with our attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an exercise for the reader: Would the Efficient Minds Hypothesis imply the Efficient Market Hypothesis? How about the reverse?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;System 1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;System 2&amp;rdquo; refer to Kahneman&amp;rsquo;s dichotomy of fast intuitive (System 1) vs slow, deliberate, planned (System 2) thought from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking,_Fast_and_Slow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainstorming: Roam Terminal</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-24-brainstorming-roam-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-24-brainstorming-roam-terminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Roam Research, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to type &amp;ldquo;/terminal&amp;rdquo; to insert a shell into my current block. Each command issued in the shell will become a block hidden behind the terminal (nested but collapsed). The output of each command will become a block as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sorts of commands do you want to be able to issue from within Roam? Deploying snippets. Querying the Roam graph. sshing into another machine and using it natively. Treating Roam like a file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I&amp;rsquo;d like all the basic shell features (history, basic unix commands sed/grep/ls/cd/awk/&amp;hellip;, piping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also like my commands to be able to use my Roam content as inputs. I&amp;rsquo;d like a new type of shell expansion &amp;ndash; expanding block references. echo $((7yNZl3Gf-)) will echo the contents of that block (precise syntax tbd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages in the Roam database can be treated like files. cat [[Roam Research]] will output the full contents of the Roam Research page of my graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll have new primitives too, like the unix classics, more suited for the Roam data structure. List all references on a page. grep that list for a keyword. Sort by date. &lt;code&gt;refs Roam Research | grep Conor | sort -t&lt;/code&gt;. There would be primitives for accessing a block&amp;rsquo;s children, parents, refs, backrefs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you can write your own commands too. Like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/python-fire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Python Fire&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide a mechanism to trivially translate any javascript/closure function in your roam/js into a command line utility. The function name becomes the command name. The function arguments become its flags. Help is generated automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real power comes from being able to apply the unix philosophy simultaneously on Roam and on a remote machine. How does this look? Maybe the Roam graph is mounted as a filesystem on the remote machine. /roam/pages/Roam Research.md views [[Roam Research]] as a markdown file. Also viewable as json or edn. Syntactic sugar provided by the shell allows you to operate directly on &amp;ldquo;[[Roam Research]]&amp;rdquo; allowing for natural commands like the one above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write to pages and blocks via these unix utilities too. Makes it super easy to copy data between the remote machine and your graph in both directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to implement this? roam/render may be essential. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell-app/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Secure shell app&lt;/a&gt; (chrome extension) suggests feasibility. There&amp;rsquo;s a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web-based_SSH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wikipedia page on Web-based SSH&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://xtermjs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;xterm.js&lt;/a&gt; is used in loads of places for javascript-based terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rerunning a command from your shell history? Appears as a block reference. Even works for modified commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This just comes for free for being in Roam: you can tag your commands to make them easy to find later. In bash # starts a comment, so the syntax for tagging tag-teams nicely with bash&amp;rsquo;s syntax. Similarly using block and page references in your commands pages it easy to resurface them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For v0 we don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need a roam/render UI. Instead we could just write some roam/js that listens for ENTER on blocks nested below &amp;ldquo;{{roam/terminal}}&amp;rdquo;. When ENTER is pressed, the block&amp;rsquo;s contents are parsed, the command gets run, output gets streamed to a new block nested below the command. I think a specialized UI could go a long way though. At the very least history search and tab completion are pretty essential shell features, and there are so many more (e.g. curses, colors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrap up this idea, I&amp;rsquo;ll also point out the deep similarity between terminal UIs and chat UIs. Both are at their core just call and response. In one you communicate with the computer, in the other with human beings. (With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; and my Messager project, it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear which is which 😃.) Details like the number of participants, the format of messages, and whether a response can be issued without a corresponding call are just that: details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could get a solid terminal experience, legitimately enabling developers to make Roam their default shell, the fusing of note-taking, thinking, and command-issuing that would result would be super powerful. All just a half-baked idea, for now. For now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Functions in Python</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-17-python-magic-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-17-python-magic-functions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this snippet I introduce and implement, but do not condone, Python &amp;ldquo;Magic functions&amp;rdquo;.
Magic functions are interesting to think about and to study, but I discourage their use in anything but the most experimental of code. You&amp;rsquo;ll soon see why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;magic function&lt;/strong&gt; is a function where the arguments and return values are both implicit, handled through the magic of Python&amp;rsquo;s powerful stack introspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following example, which implements the quadratic formula. Pay special attention to where quadratic_formula is called. No arguments are passed, and the result is not assigned to anything. Still, the program works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import math
import magic

def quadratic_formula(context):
  magic.unpack(context)
  discriminant = b**2 - 4*a*c
  x0, x1 = (
      (-b + math.sqrt(discriminant)) / (2*a),
      (-b - math.sqrt(discriminant)) / (2*a),
  )
  return magic.context()


def main():
  a, b, c = 1, -1, -12
  magic.call(quadratic_formula)
  print(f&#39;x = {x0} or {x1}  (Discriminant is {discriminant})&#39;)

if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;:
  main()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We say quadratic_formula is a &amp;ldquo;magic function&amp;rdquo;, and it is called by invoking magic.call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we run this program, the result is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;x = 4.0 or -3.0  (Discriminant is 49)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did a, b, and c get passed to quadratic_formula? How did x0, x1, and discriminant find their way back to main? This is the magic of magic functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement a magic function, simply write a function that accepts a single argument &lt;code&gt;context&lt;/code&gt;, calls &lt;code&gt;magic.unpack(context)&lt;/code&gt; as its first line, and returns with &lt;code&gt;return magic.context()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To call a magic function, use &lt;code&gt;magic.call(fn)&lt;/code&gt; as in the example above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To &amp;ldquo;install&amp;rdquo; magic, so that you can import it as in the example above, simply save the following three-function Python file as &lt;code&gt;magic.py&lt;/code&gt; in the directory where you&amp;rsquo;d like to use magic functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import inspect

def call(fn, n=1):
  c = context(n=n+1)
  result = fn(c)
  unpack(result, n=n+1)

def context(n=1):
  c = {}
  caller = inspect.stack()[n]
  caller_frame = caller[0]
  caller_globals = caller_frame.f_globals
  caller_locals = caller_frame.f_locals
  c.update(caller_globals)
  c.update(caller_locals)
  return c

def unpack(c, n=1):
  caller = inspect.stack()[n]
  caller_frame = caller[0]
  caller_frame.f_globals.update(c)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These twenty lines of code comprise the complete implementation of the magic module.
Magic works by inspecting the stack to get the locals and globals when calling a magic function and when returning from a magic function &amp;ndash; this is done in the &lt;code&gt;context&lt;/code&gt; function. Magic then makes use of stack inspection a second time to update the globals in the caller after a magic function returns &amp;ndash; this is done in &lt;code&gt;unpack&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What purpose does this all serve? Why would you ever want to use magic functions?
The short answer is that you should &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; use magic functions.
They will confuse readers of your code and are error prone.
Nevertheless, I will explain the situation that prompted me to write this module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a machine learning training loop and reuse it for many different machine learning training pipelines. Each of the training pipelines needed to track metrics in its own way, save summaries in its own way, make plots in its own way, etc. A natural way to support all of these different needs is with hooks. A hook is a user provided callback function that the training loop library can call each iteration through the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble with hooks in this situation is that they require either very long argument lists, or bundling of many arguments into a single argument. If different functions need different bundles of arguments, the bundling approach can be quite cumbersome. Also, if two hooks wish to communicate with one another, that needs to be accommodated too. Magic functions provide one mechanism for dealing with this complexity. Different magic hooks can make use of different parts of the training loop&amp;rsquo;s state. A magic hook can also use state set by another hook.
While this approach does satisfactorily address the complexity of writing a training loop library,
I must stress that I do not recommend this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with real magic, use &lt;code&gt;magic&lt;/code&gt; at your own peril. 🧙‍♀️ 😉&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing my Twitter Feed</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-08-repurposing-my-twitter-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-08-repurposing-my-twitter-feed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;rsquo;s addicting. It&amp;rsquo;s not a good use of my time, but I scroll there anyway. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be scrolling there anyway, might as well make it worthwhile. So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to repurpose my Twitter timeline and inject things I actually care about into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? You might think to do this with a Chrome extension, injecting content in between the existing tweets. There&amp;rsquo;s an easier way though. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a new, private Twitter account, and I programmatically&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; tweet as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal Twitter account is @Bieber, and I use a picture of myself for the profile. The new account goes by &amp;ldquo;Private Bieber&amp;rdquo;, and uses a deep dream-ified version of my profile picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it decide what to tweet? It chooses tweets from my Roam Research database. I already frequently write down things I&amp;rsquo;d like to learn about, and ideas I&amp;rsquo;d like to try in Roam. It&amp;rsquo;s where I keep my snippet ideas, my spaced repetition system, and my &amp;ldquo;Fleeting TODOs&amp;rdquo;. Source code available in the footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fleeting TODOs are what I call TODO items that tug at my brain in the moment, eager to take my attention away from the task at hand. Rather than do them then, I write them down. I only ever get around to doing a small fraction of my fleeting TODOs, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a record of them. It makes it easier to notice if I keep coming back to the same idea, in which case maybe it&amp;rsquo;s worth actually pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a script that occasionally &amp;ndash; currently every 10 minutes &amp;ndash; picks out one of these items from my Roam Research database and tweets it in a way that&amp;rsquo;s only visible to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have my Twitter feed configured to show me tweets chronologically, this means there&amp;rsquo;s always a tweet from Private Bieber sitting at the top, to remind me of something &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; care about, rather than something the &lt;em&gt;Twitter algorithm&lt;/em&gt; has picked out for me to care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FxD83QrK9_D.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=76f275ac-62fd-4844-829c-b44cf9cf568f&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the tweet selection is random, but already in this first 20 minutes I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy with the tweets it&amp;rsquo;s been writing. Perhaps in a future iteration I&amp;rsquo;ll make some adjustments to what it tweets and when. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have this kind of control over my attention, especially in a setting like Twitter where I&amp;rsquo;m so used to mindless scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This same technique ought to work fine for taking control of my Facebook feed too, so perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll get Private Bieber an account there next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dbieber/47660493954e62f4607cd8d19d54cf59&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Source code is here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL for the Kangaroo Auto-responder</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-30-sql-for-the-kangaroo-auto-responder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-30-sql-for-the-kangaroo-auto-responder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I turned on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-29-kangaroo-auto-responder/&#34;&gt;Kangaroo Auto-responder&lt;/a&gt; this morning. The rules for when to send a kangaroo 🦘 are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get a kangaroo if the &lt;strong&gt;most-recent&lt;/strong&gt; message in our chat (ignoring trivial messages from you) is &lt;strong&gt;non-trivial&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;read-by-me&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;written-by-you&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;not a response&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;eight-hours old&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these criteria in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-recent-message&#34;&gt;Most-recent message&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criteria are being applied to the most recent message in our chat ignoring trivial messages from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In SQL, this looks like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;select thread_id, max(timestamp) as timestamp
from messenger
where (author = &#39;1409114395&#39; or (author &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &#39;1409114395&#39; and LENGTH(text) &amp;gt; 15))
group by thread_id;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1409114395 is my Facebook ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query selects the most recent timestamp from only a single message in each thread. It considers all messages from me, but only non-trivial (more than 15 characters) messages from the other participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that if I have sent the most recent message in a conversation (regardless of the length of the message), then no kangaroo is needed. If the other person has sent the most recent message, a kangaroo might be in order, but trivial messages should not trigger kangaroos. So we ignore them, and see if the most recent message is still from the other person even when ignoring their trivial messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-trivial&#34;&gt;Non-trivial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We choose 15-characters as the threshold for what makes a message trivial. The reason we ignore trivial messages is because they often don&amp;rsquo;t warrant a response. I am considering removing this constraint, as the &amp;ldquo;Not a response&amp;rdquo; constraint seems to obviate the need for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows up as &lt;code&gt;LENGTH(text) &amp;gt; 15)&lt;/code&gt; in the query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-by-me&#34;&gt;Read-by-me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I do not have read receipt information in my messages database, so I did not include this rule in the first version of the Kangaroo Auto-responder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;written-by-you&#34;&gt;Written-by-you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if the most recent message is from you is a kangaroo necessary. If its from me, I&amp;rsquo;ve already responded!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this query, this is a simple check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;WHERE messenger.author &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &#39;1409114395&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-a-response&#34;&gt;Not-a-response&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting piece. When I wrote out the rules for the auto-responder yesterday, I was thinking I&amp;rsquo;d ignore messages sent within 5 minutes of a message I sent. My thinking was that this small filter would prevent me from needing to get the last word in every conversation to avoid oversending of kangaroos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking I&amp;rsquo;ll ignore messages sent within &lt;em&gt;36 hours&lt;/em&gt; of a message I sent. This is a much tighter restriction. It means that I may miss sending some kangaroos that I ought to have sent, but it also means that if someone takes two hours to reply to me and that&amp;rsquo;s the end of the conversation, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to reply to prevent a kangaroo from going out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like striking a good balance between the non-trivial message criteria and the not-a-response criteria is key, and I may adjust these going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine if a message is a response, I first determine the time of my own most recent message in the chat. In SQL, this is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;select thread_id, max(timestamp) as outgoing_timestamp
from messenger
where author = &#39;1409114395&#39; -- my FB id
group by thread_id;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then compare this message&amp;rsquo;s timestamp with that of the most recent message in the thread, which we selected earlier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;(  -- The reply is at least X minutes after my latest message.
  (latest_messages.timestamp - outgoing_timestamp)/1000 &amp;gt; 36*60*60
  or outgoing_timestamp IS NULL
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-hours-old&#34;&gt;8-hours old&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final criteria for whether to send a kangaroo is that the message must be eight hours old. Yesterday I was initially planning for 2-hours old, but I decided to give myself more time to respond manually before the kangaroo would go out. Here&amp;rsquo;s the SQL for that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;-- Message is 8 hours old:
AND NOW() - to_timestamp(messenger.timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;gt; INTERVAL &#39;8 HOURS&#39;
AND NOW() - to_timestamp(messenger.timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;lt; INTERVAL &#39;8.25 HOURS&#39;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;putting-it-all-together&#34;&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the complete SQL query that finds messages which warrant an automated kangaroo response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;-- Select the most recent message per thread
-- (ignoring trivial messages from you),
-- and the most recent message per thread specifically from me.
-- If the most recent message (ignoring trivial messages from you)
-- is non-trivial,
-- written-by-you,
-- not a reply to my message,
-- and a specific age,
-- then we&#39;ve got ourselves a Kangaroo!
--
-- In a future iteration we will also ensure the message has been read-by-me.

SELECT * FROM

-- The first sub-query:
-- Selects the most recent message from each thread that is either:
-- (A) from me, or (B) from you and non-trivial in length
-- And is also less than 8 hours old.
((select thread_id, max(timestamp) as timestamp
 from messenger
 where (author = &#39;1409114395&#39; or (author &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &#39;1409114395&#39; and LENGTH(text) &amp;gt; 15))
 -- and to_timestamp(timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;gt; NOW() - INTERVAL &#39;800 HOURS&#39;
 group by thread_id) AS latest_messages
INNER JOIN
  messenger
ON
  messenger.thread_id = latest_messages.thread_id AND
  messenger.timestamp = latest_messages.timestamp)
LEFT JOIN
    -- Selects the most recent message from each thread from me:
    (select thread_id, max(timestamp) as outgoing_timestamp
     from messenger
     where author = &#39;1409114395&#39;
     -- and to_timestamp(timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;gt; NOW() - INTERVAL &#39;800 HOURS&#39;
     group by thread_id) AS latest_outgoing_messages
ON
  messenger.thread_id = latest_outgoing_messages.thread_id
WHERE messenger.author &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &#39;1409114395&#39; -- David Bieber
AND messenger.author &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &#39;1985867351654140&#39; -- Bieber Bot
AND (  -- The reply is at least X minutes after my latest message.
  (latest_messages.timestamp - outgoing_timestamp)/1000 &amp;gt; 36*60*60
  or outgoing_timestamp IS NULL
)
AND thread_type = &#39;USER&#39; -- Message is a 1:1 chat, not a group chat
-- Message is 8 hours old:
AND NOW() - to_timestamp(messenger.timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;gt; INTERVAL &#39;8 HOURS&#39;
AND NOW() - to_timestamp(messenger.timestamp/1000) at time zone &#39;UTC&#39; &amp;lt; INTERVAL &#39;8.25 HOURS&#39;
ORDER BY messenger.timestamp desc;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This checks all the criteria for whether a message needs a kangaroo. I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a script that runs this query every ten minutes, and sends kangaroos as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, no kangaroos have been sent yet. I hope it works 🤞!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kangaroo Auto-responder</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-29-kangaroo-auto-responder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-29-kangaroo-auto-responder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Kangaroo Auto-responder is to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid people expecting a response from me when I don&amp;rsquo;t realize they&amp;rsquo;re expecting a response, e.g. because I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about their message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should let me let my guard down a bit about feeling obligated to respond to people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will it do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will automatically respond to messages that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen but haven&amp;rsquo;t responded to for 2+ hours with a kangaroo&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time it sends someone a kangaroo, it will also explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Kangaroo] Hello! This is an automated reply from the Kangaroo Auto-responder. You&amp;rsquo;re getting this message because it looks like David might forget to reply to your message. If you want a response, you should contact him again. (Just saying &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo; is often enough!)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text for the second time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Kangaroo] Me again. David might forget to reply to your message. In the future I&amp;rsquo;ll just send you a picture of a Kangaroo to symbolize this. 🦘  If you ever get a picture of a Kangaroo from me, it just means David may have dropped the ball on your message and you should contact him again if you&amp;rsquo;re expecting a response.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequent kangaroos will be unaccompanied by explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details on exactly when to send kangaroos are still a work in progress. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to overwhelm anyone with kangaroos. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about some rules: (1) only send kangaroos if there was a message of non-trivial length, e.g. more than 20 characters, (2) only send a kangaroo after I&amp;rsquo;ve read the message; if I genuinely haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the message yet, no need for a kangaroo, as the message will still appear as unread in my inbox, (3) if you send follow-up messages, that resets the timer on the 2 hours, (4) any messages you send within 5 minutes of me sending you a message are ineligible for triggering kangaroos (this way I don&amp;rsquo;t need to get the last word), and (5) obviously, don&amp;rsquo;t send a kangaroo for a message I&amp;rsquo;ve already responded too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the rules of kangaroos are: You get a kangaroo if the &lt;strong&gt;most-recent&lt;/strong&gt; message in our chat is &lt;strong&gt;non-trivial&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;read-by-me&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;written-by-you&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;not an immediate reply&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;two-hours old&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why kangaroos? They bounce 🤷‍♂️ ? This is kind of like a message bouncing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a picture of a kangaroo, that is. Like this one: 🦘, or this: &lt;img src=&#34;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fplayground%2FtBz98tV75N.png?alt=media&amp;amp;token=66762cac-d0b0-43ba-91a8-eaefa6ef7626&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; It will not send them an actual real-life kangaroo. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>am I available for conversation right now dot com</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-22-am-i-available-for-conversation-right-now-dot-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-22-am-i-available-for-conversation-right-now-dot-com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I like this idea, but I&amp;rsquo;m giving it a try; I&amp;rsquo;ve added a &amp;ldquo;Now&amp;rdquo; page to my website (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/now/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;davidbieber.com/now&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for now pages is described at &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;&gt;https://nownownow.com/about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, a now page says what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the author&amp;rsquo;s life now. Not &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; that would be a &amp;ldquo;right now page&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; but rather, now in the broader sense of &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s are you up to these days?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&amp;rsquo;t about my new Now page though, which I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily plan to keep up (if the link 404s, you know why). Rather, this post is about an idea for a kind of &amp;ldquo;right now&amp;rdquo; page that I&amp;rsquo;m toying with building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a page that tells the reader if I&amp;rsquo;m likely available for a conversation &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d call it the &amp;ldquo;is David available to talk now&amp;rdquo; page, and here&amp;rsquo;s how it might work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-aims-only-to-give-a-best-guess-as-to-whether-i-can-talk-now&#34;&gt;It aims only to give a best guess as to whether I can talk now.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says No during work.&lt;br/&gt;
It says No during sleep hours.&lt;br/&gt;
It says No while I&amp;rsquo;m on a phone call / skype / zoom / meet etc&lt;br/&gt;
It says No if I have recently been on a call for a long time&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says Yes during explicitly set times (there would be a button I can press to set it to Yes for 30 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m deliberately in a public space (e.g. Gather Town, Clubhouse) AND looking for conversation (aka I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed the button), then it shows where to find me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rest of the time, it simply shrugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-would-i-want-such-a-system&#34;&gt;Why would I want such a system?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what I really want is for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; to use such a system. I want the &amp;ldquo;open door&amp;rdquo; system that professors so often use; if my door is open, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to come in and talk. I want to avoid people avoiding saying hi because they don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;m available. And I want to avoid the mental overhead of making plans for conversations that aren&amp;rsquo;t time sensitive. Plans are tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ideal system for when I want to talk to someone isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s pick a time to talk&amp;rdquo;, because that has scheduling overhead and will likely break up my day at an inconvenient time. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer a more flexible approach. When I&amp;rsquo;m free, I open my door (a digital, virtual, door). I send you a message that I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk; you see it when you&amp;rsquo;re free (because you have notifications disabled 👍). If I&amp;rsquo;m still free then, my door will still be open and we can talk. If I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on to another activity, my door will be closed and we&amp;rsquo;ll reconnect later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of doors, the &amp;ldquo;is David available to talk now&amp;rdquo; page is my idea for an approximation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how I would build it. The idea requires programmatically determining when I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the phone, in skype, in zoom, etc. I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into how approachable these services are to work with. And I likely won&amp;rsquo;t. This is the sort of idea that, while fun to entertain, will likely need to morph considerably before it turns into a real project. Such is the nature of the Snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clubhouse feature request: save last 60 seconds</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-20-clubhouse-feature-request-save-last-60-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-20-clubhouse-feature-request-save-last-60-seconds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a feature request for Clubhouse. Zoom, Meet, Skype, if you&amp;rsquo;re listening, this is a feature request for you all too. The request is a button to save the &lt;em&gt;previous&lt;/em&gt; 60 seconds of audio. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re interested because people will share the clips on social media and drive more traffic back to CH 📈🤷‍♂️. I just want the feature for note-taking 📝. Details follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-button&#34;&gt;The button&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little floppy disk save icon. 💾. Non intrusive. When clicked, it triggers a save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-60-seconds&#34;&gt;Just 60 seconds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous 60 seconds of audio are saved. This means a circular buffer of 60 seconds of audio is being stored at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just blindly save everything, because that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of data to wade through (and to store). I just want to save the good parts. So when someone says something insightful, I click save. The rest is lost to history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;respecting-privacy&#34;&gt;Respecting Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no one clicks save, the audio is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone does click save, the speakers still can choose not to have their own audio saved. Since everyone&amp;rsquo;s on their own phone, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to save an audio clip with e.g. everyone-except-David&amp;rsquo;s audio, if David decides they don&amp;rsquo;t want their audio saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe David never wants their audio saved except when he explicitly allows it. That&amp;rsquo;s fine. That&amp;rsquo;s a setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-points&#34;&gt;Bonus points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus points for automatic transcription. Additional bonus points for saving the audio clip and its transcription to a Roam database. Still more bonus points for allowing sharing the clips to TikTok or Instagram or wherever, but I don&amp;rsquo;t use those, so someone else will have to provide the points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prior-art&#34;&gt;Prior Art&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt; has a feature for recording a circular video buffer. They call it the &amp;ldquo;replay buffer.&amp;rdquo; Streamers use it for instant replays, for example. I use it myself for screen recordings sometimes, so I can decide retroactively that something was worth saving, without having to waste gigabytes of storage recording everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/heard/id615420427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; for a long time now offering cameras and audio recorders with this circular buffer feature to allow capturing the past. However, it&amp;rsquo;s never been integrated into a social product before, as far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware. Clubhouse, let&amp;rsquo;s change that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python hoist: immediate locals only</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-18-python-hoist-locals-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-18-python-hoist-locals-only/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The implementation of &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt; in my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-16-python-hoist/&#34;&gt;earlier snippet&lt;/a&gt; returned the values of local variables of all functions called by the hoisted function. This new version only returns the locals of the hoisted function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, you can use it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;def f(x):
  y = x + 1
  z = y * 2
  return z + 1

f(4) == 11
hoist(f)(4) == {&#39;x&#39;: 4, &#39;y&#39;: 5, &#39;z&#39;: 10, &#39;return&#39;: 11}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another usage example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;def f(x):
  y = messy_g(x + 1)
  return y + 1

def messy_g(z):
  q = z * 9
  w = q / 3
  return w + 1

f(1) == 8
hoist(f)(1) == {&#39;x&#39;: 1, &#39;y&#39;: 7, &#39;return&#39;: 8}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice in this example that the local variables used by &lt;code&gt;messy_g&lt;/code&gt; are not returned by &lt;code&gt;hoist(f)&lt;/code&gt;. Only &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s local variables are returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import functools
import inspect
import sys

def make_trace(results, f, original_trace_fn):
  def trace_local(frame, event, arg):
    # event: &#39;call&#39;, &#39;line&#39;, &#39;return&#39;, &#39;exception&#39; or &#39;opcode&#39;
    if event == &#39;line&#39;:
      arg_info = inspect.getargvalues(frame)
      results.update(arg_info.locals.copy())
    if event == &#39;return&#39;:
      arg_info = inspect.getargvalues(frame)
      values = arg_info.locals.copy()
      results.update(values)
      results[&#39;return&#39;] = arg
    if event == &#39;call&#39;:
      return original_trace_fn

  def trace_global(frame, event, arg):
    if event == &#39;call&#39;:
      info = inspect.getframeinfo(frame)
      info_parent = inspect.getframeinfo(frame.f_back)
      if info.function == f.__name__ and info_parent.function == &#39;hoisted_f__&#39;:
        return trace_local
  return trace_global


def hoist(f):

  @functools.wraps(f)
  def hoisted_f__(*args, **kwargs):
    original_trace_fn = sys.gettrace()

    results = {}
    trace_fn = make_trace(results, f, original_trace_fn)

    sys.settrace(trace_fn)
    f(*args, **kwargs)
    sys.settrace(original_trace_fn)

    return results

  return hoisted_f__
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python hoist()</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-16-python-hoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-16-python-hoist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a little decorator function called &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt;. Calling &lt;code&gt;hoist(f)&lt;/code&gt; transforms &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;, such that instead of returning the return value of &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;, it returns the values of all local variables in addition to the return value of &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;def f(x):
  y = x + 1
  z = y * 2
  return z + 1

f(4) == 11
hoist(f)(4) == {&#39;x&#39;: 4, &#39;y&#39;: 5, &#39;z&#39;: 10, &#39;return&#39;: 11}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sense? The result of &lt;code&gt;f(4)&lt;/code&gt; is just the return value, whereas &lt;code&gt;hoist(f)(4)&lt;/code&gt; gives the values of all local variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be a useful debugging tool, allowing access to the internal state of a function. It works by setting a trace function with Python&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;sys.settrace&lt;/code&gt;, as you can see in its definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the definition of &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import inspect
import functools


class Collection(object):
  &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;The full set of variables over time.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;

  def __init__(self):
    self.values = {}

  def update(self, values):
    self.values.update(values)

  def set_return(self, arg):
    self.values[&#39;return&#39;] = arg

  def __repr__(self):
    return repr(self.values)


def make_trace(results, fn):
  def trace_local(frame, event, arg):
    # event: &#39;call&#39;, &#39;line&#39;, &#39;return&#39;, &#39;exception&#39; or &#39;opcode&#39;
    if event == &#39;line&#39;:
      arg_info = inspect.getargvalues(frame)
      results.update(arg_info.locals.copy())
    if event == &#39;return&#39;:
      arg_info = inspect.getargvalues(frame)
      values = arg_info.locals.copy()
      results.update(values)
      results.set_return(arg)
    if event == &#39;call&#39;:
      return fn

  def trace_global(frame, event, arg):
    if event == &#39;call&#39;:
      return trace_local
  return trace_global


def hoist(f):

  @functools.wraps(f)
  def new_f(*args, **kwargs):
    original_trace_fn = sys.gettrace()

    results = Collection()
    trace_fn = make_trace(results, original_trace_fn)

    sys.settrace(trace_fn)
    f(*args, **kwargs)
    sys.settrace(original_trace_fn)

    return results

  return new_f
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ideas for extensions to &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt; follow. Feel free to go ahead and implement these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) Modify &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt; so the outputs are accessible via dot-notation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) Modify &lt;code&gt;hoist&lt;/code&gt; so it returns all values taken on by all variables during the execution of &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;.
Make it so that &lt;code&gt;hoist(f)(x)[&#39;value.3&#39;]&lt;/code&gt; returns the third value taken on by the variable &lt;code&gt;value&lt;/code&gt; in the call to &lt;code&gt;f(x)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Delegation-optional Voting</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-11-democratic-delegation-optional-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-11-democratic-delegation-optional-voting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this snippet I propose a novel voting system, which I call &amp;ldquo;Democratic Delegation-optional Voting&amp;rdquo;. The core idea of the voting system is that anyone can choose to delegate their vote to a group or individual that they trust. They may change their delegate selection at any time and for any reason (including for a brief period after votes are cast, as we will see), or they may choose to cast a vote themselves rather than delegating their vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-problem-does-this-voting-system-solve&#34;&gt;What problem does this voting system solve?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual voters don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time or energy to research every issue up for vote. So, delegation is crucial. At the same time, voters shouldn&amp;rsquo;t yield their power to delegates entirely. If a voter feels passionately about an issue, they should not have to hope their representative&amp;rsquo;s views align with theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-the-system-work&#34;&gt;How does the system work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahead of a Vote, an individual or organization can register themselves as a Delegate. They need only do this once even if there will be many Votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On its own, a Delegate has no voting power. Each voter gets one ballot. Each voter may choose to cast that ballot themselves, or they may delegate their ballot to a Delegate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a Delegate may choose to cast its ballots itself, or it may choose to delegate them to another Delegate. If ten people have delegated their ballots to a Delegate, then it has ten times the voting power of an individual. A Delegate&amp;rsquo;s votes or delegation selections are public, whereas an individual&amp;rsquo;s votes or delegation selections are private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Votes may be cast or a Delegate selected at any time leading up to a Vote deadline. Votes may be modified and Delegate selections may be changed up until this deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the Vote deadline arrives, votes and delegation-selections made by Delegates are made public. Delegates can no longer change their selections at this point. Individual voters then have an additional 48 hours following the Vote deadline during which they may choose to modify their ballot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is flexible, in that it is compatible with winner-take-all voting, ranked choice voting, approval voting, proportional representation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;toy-example-playground-election&#34;&gt;Toy Example: Playground Election&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now demonstrate the voting system in a playground setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron, Brianna, Chloe, Daniel, and Emily are playing on the playground. Aaron and Brianna both want to use the swing. There&amp;rsquo;s only one swing. &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s vote!&amp;rdquo; suggests Emily. &amp;ldquo;Whoever gets more votes gets to swing.&amp;rdquo; Aaron and Brianna agree: whoever gets three or more votes wins. Daniel shrugs. &amp;ldquo;Chloe can have my vote!&amp;rdquo; he shouts, and he runs off to play alone on the seesaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Aaron, Brianna, Chloe and Emily each vote: Aaron and Brianna each for themselves, Chloe for Aaron and Emily for Brianna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Aaron wins, 3-2, since Chloe&amp;rsquo;s vote also counts for Daniel!&amp;rdquo; Emily shouts. She&amp;rsquo;s really getting into this election thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just then Daniel comes tearing around the corner. &amp;ldquo;Wait! I thought you were going to vote for Brianna&amp;rdquo;, he tells Chloe. &amp;ldquo;Can I change my vote?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily, having studied &lt;em&gt;Democratic Delegation-optional Voting&lt;/em&gt; says &amp;ldquo;Sure, no trouble. Anyone else?&amp;rdquo; Hearing no other vote-changes, she proclaims Brianna the winner, and Aaron spends the rest of recess helping push Brianna higher on the swing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-example-local-and-state-legislation&#34;&gt;Another Example: Local and State Legislation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example, consider a hypothetical local government and state government both using &lt;em&gt;Democratic Delegation-optional Voting&lt;/em&gt;. Over the next two weeks, the local government will be voting on two issues (the school budget and a commercial cannabis restriction ordinance), and the state government will also be voting on two issues (an unpopular jaywalking penalty and an obscure contract law thingy that affects very few people and is hard to understand).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the residents have set up simple &lt;em&gt;rules&lt;/em&gt; for choosing default Delegates. Several republican residents, they have selected their local republican Delegate as their default Delegate, and similarly several democratic residents have selected the local democratic Delegate as their default Delegate. Some residents have a rule-based system, where e.g. education-related issues are delegated to one Delegate while penal code issues are delegated to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vote deadlines are set as follows, and the text of each issue is made available to the public two weeks prior to its Vote deadline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local school budget: January 21, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State unpopular jaywalking penalty: January 22, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local commercial cannabis restriction ordinance: January 28, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State obscure contract law thingy that affects very few people and is hard to understand: January 29, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the residents hear about the unpopular jaywalking penalty, and they see how awful an idea it is, and so they directly submit a Nay vote on that issue. The penalty is overwhelmingly voted down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school budget is a popular but particularly nuanced issue. While many residents chose to vote on it directly, we also see many residents choose a Delegate that they trust with school board issues, since they know this vote is important but complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, the commercial cannabis restriction ordinance is an important issue too, but they trust their default Delegate will vote appropriately. The day after the election they&amp;rsquo;re surprised to read on their social media newsfeed of choice that one of the common default Delegates didn&amp;rsquo;t vote as expected, so they double check their vote. The vote looks fine. Clickbait post, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the residents don&amp;rsquo;t care about the obscure contract law thingy that affects very few people and is hard to understand, and so they leave their default Delegate selected. Some of the common default Delegates also don&amp;rsquo;t have time for obscure contract law, and so they choose to delegate their votes to still further, more specialized Delegates that they trust. (This is good because not only do most voters not have time to look into contract law, they also don&amp;rsquo;t have time to look into people who do have time to look into contract law, so they trust their Delegate to do &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;.) Most of the voters are fine with how their vote ends up being cast, though a few don&amp;rsquo;t like the sub-Delegate their default-Delegate chose, and so those few can change their vote if they like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all cases, the final votes are in and the election is tallied 48 hours after the election deadline. The school budget passes. The jaywalking penalty is voted down. The commercial cannabis restriction ordinance will go into effect immediately. And the obscure contract law thingy that affects very few people and is hard to understand&amp;hellip; well, to be honest I didn&amp;rsquo;t really follow that one too closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-observations&#34;&gt;Some observations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve seen the &lt;em&gt;Democratic Delegation-optional Voting&lt;/em&gt; in action now. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo;, because it gives everyone an equal voice in every election. Everyone gets precisely one vote. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;delegation-optional&amp;rdquo; because voters and Delegates alike have the choice of whether to vote directly, delegate their vote, or even skip voting altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that there are no explicit elected representatives in this system. There are merely different degrees of being an elected representative (the number of ballots you are responsible for as a Delegate). Anyone can register as a Delegate, and whether you make this a full-time job, investigating every single issue on the table, or whether you often delegate your votes further is up to you as a Delegate. Under this system, some common Delegates will be responsible for casting huge numbers of votes, while other Delegates will be responsible for casting just a handful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned that either an individual or an organization can register as a Delegate. If an organization registers as a Delegate they can select their votes through whatever process they choose (e.g. an internal election is fair game), and they are held to the same deadlines as every other Delegate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-edge-cases-and-minor-details&#34;&gt;Some edge-cases and minor details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the Local and State Legislation example, a voter can set up simple rules for selecting their default Delegate. The voting system can also be extended to allow a voter to additionally specify &amp;ldquo;fall-through&amp;rdquo; backup Delegates. A ballot is given to a fall-through Delegate in the case that a voter&amp;rsquo;s higher-priority Delegate does not take an action on a particular piece of legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if a major Delegate delegates their ballots to a trusted specialized delegate, but isn&amp;rsquo;t happy with how that trusted specialized delegate votes? They can contact their constituents and let them know. The constituents will have 48 hours during which they can change their vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if a Delegate A delegates their ballots to Delegate B, and Delegate B delegates their ballots to Delegate A? This should be easy to avoid in practice, because I expect Delegates will naturally have clear roles / specializations. Should it occur, however, no vote will be cast for voters delegating their ballot to those Delegates (unless a voter listed a backup Delegate), and the voters will have the usual 48 hours during which to place their vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Democratic Delegation-optional Voting&lt;/em&gt; truly puts governance in the hands of the people, without needing everyone to be an expert on everything. It makes Delegates accountable to their constituents, because a constituent can change their Delegates at any time. It allows people to perform their civic duty to precisely the extent that is appropriate for them. On the issues that matter most to them, they can cast an explicit vote. For the majority of issues, though, individuals don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn the details of every piece of legislation. They have the option to trust those to their Delegates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A filesystem for social media</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-10-a-filesystem-for-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-10-a-filesystem-for-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://omar.website/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Omar Riswan&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent project called 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://omar.website/tabfs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TabFS&lt;/a&gt; that takes your browser tabs and exposes them to you as a filesystem. When you run &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;, you see a list of all your open tabs. &lt;code&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt; on a tab directory closes the tab. Inspecting the tab with standard tools (&lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt;, etc) allow you to do things like reading the title or contents of the tab (yes, the whole tab&amp;rsquo;s contents!), closing the tab, or running javascript in the tab. The whole thing is quite clever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by TabFS, I envision another non-conventional filesystem: Social Media FS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you mount smfs and authenticate with your social media providers. Then if you &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; the mounted directory, you can see each of the places you can read from and write to on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a directory full of your chat threads. The timestamps indicate when they were created and when they were most recently modified. You can read the contents of the chat, or send a new message just as easily (and via the same tools) as you would write a file to disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a directory of all the Facebook posts made by all your friends and all the groups you follow. Each post has a file with its contents, and also one with all the comments and reactions to it. You can make a new post or add a new comment the same way you&amp;rsquo;d make a new file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use standard tools for monitoring for new content. I like to use 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pythonhosted.org/watchdog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Python&amp;rsquo;s watchdog&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a directory for ads too, which you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to peruse or delete as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reacting to a twitter post, sending a DM, receiving discord or slack or signal messages&amp;hellip; all of these are organized as files and folders, and actions can be performed simply through file reads and writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d sure love to use a filesystem like this, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt; would too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Distraction Detection, at last</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-09-mobile-distraction-detection-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-09-mobile-distraction-detection-at-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have implemented a minimal working version of mobile &lt;em&gt;distraction detection&lt;/em&gt;, complete with a simple intervention for when I visit distracting websites on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-distraction-detection-do&#34;&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;distraction detection&amp;rdquo; do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It runs on my laptop and monitors my &lt;em&gt;phone&lt;/em&gt; for when I visit distracting websites. I give it a list of distracting websites for it to keep an eye out for. My list is: twitter, facebook, hacker news, google news, reddit, and youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can set it to perform some action whenever I&amp;rsquo;m on one of these websites. For this first iteration, I&amp;rsquo;m having Bieber Bot message me whenever it notices I&amp;rsquo;m on one of these websites. Now that it&amp;rsquo;s working though, it will be easy to customize to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In future iterations, I&amp;rsquo;ll have it wait until I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending several minutes on the website before messaging me, and I&amp;rsquo;ll only have it do this during times when I mean to be focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-this-interesting&#34;&gt;Why is this interesting?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are excellent browser extensions that help you take control of your browsing habits on your computer. I recommend DK&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getintention.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/a&gt; for this. However, there aren&amp;rsquo;t great solutions like Intention for mobile browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is that mobile browsers don&amp;rsquo;t provide good ways for developers to write extensions. I&amp;rsquo;ve built my mobile distraction detector in spite of this limitation :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use an iPhone and the Chrome browser. I&amp;rsquo;m logged into my Google Account on Chrome on both my phone and my laptop, and I have tab syncing turned on. With tab syncing, all my tab sessions from my phone are synced to my Google account, and are visible on my laptop, usually with a sub-minute latency. You can view this data in human-readable form at 
&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://history/syncedTabs&#34;&gt;chrome://history/syncedTabs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tab session data is stored along with the rest of my Chrome data. Since I use a Mac, the path is &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application\ Support/Google/Chrome/Profile\ 1/Sync\ Data/LevelDB/&lt;/code&gt;. Note that &amp;ldquo;Profile 1&amp;rdquo; may be replaced with either &amp;ldquo;Default&amp;rdquo;, or the name of your Profile, depending on how many Google accounts you have connected with Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is stored in a LevelDB database (this is unusual for Chrome; most of the rest of your Chrome data is stored in sqlite3 databases). LevelDB is an efficient key-value store, which was written by Jeff Dean and Sanjay Ghemawat back in 2011. The keys which contain the synced tab data are those prefixed with &amp;ldquo;session-dt&amp;rdquo;. The corresponding values are &lt;code&gt;SessionSpecifics&lt;/code&gt; protocol buffers. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/&amp;#43;/master:components/sync/protocol/session_specifics.proto&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The protocol buffer definition is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before parsing the sync data, I always make a copy of it first, and then I only ever open the copy. This ensures that Chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lock on the database, and isn&amp;rsquo;t editing it concurrently with my own program reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the Python library &lt;code&gt;plyvel&lt;/code&gt; to parse the LevelDB database: &lt;code&gt;db = plyvel.DB(path_to_copy_of_leveldb_directory)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to use the protobuf definition, I compiled it first with protoc: &lt;code&gt;protoc -I chromium/ chromium/components/sync/protocol/*.proto --python_out=dbieber/distraction_detection/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting these pieces together, accessing the session data looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import plyvel
from components.sync.protocol import session_specifics_pb2

db = plyvel.DB(path)

for key, value in db.iterator():
  if b&#39;sessions-dt&#39; in key:
	session = session_specifics_pb2.SessionSpecifics.FromString(value)

db.close()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, the key remaining piece to understand is how to figure out which tabs are open on which devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the SessionSpecifics protos has an attribute: &lt;code&gt;session_tag&lt;/code&gt; which uniquely identifies a session. For each &lt;code&gt;session_tag&lt;/code&gt;, there is a single SessionSpecifics proto with a &lt;code&gt;client_name&lt;/code&gt; attribute: this indicates which device the session lives on. Each of the remaining SessionSpecifics protos with that same tag correspond to a single tab, and the currently open URL for that tab comes from &lt;code&gt;session.tab.navigation[-1].virtual_url&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of matching the URLs against my list of distracting websites, and sending the data off to Bieber Bot. Distractions, detected. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tweak my own distraction detection setup to something that makes sense for me. Instead of immediate messages from Bieber Bot, I&amp;rsquo;ll have him try to keep my total senseless scrolling for a day to a moderate amount. I&amp;rsquo;ll have him be particularly vigilant about helping me keep my morning scrolling from going on too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also send this snippet around to folks interested in building similar tools. While I won&amp;rsquo;t be turning this into a product for the masses, I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that the method does get picked up by projects like Intention, ActivityWatch, and other tools that aim to help people maintain healthy browsing habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge that with account syncing, rich data about your mobile browsing is available on your computer. So today, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much tooling that takes advantage of this. If you work on a product in this space, well, now you&amp;rsquo;ve had a glimpse of what data&amp;rsquo;s available and what it can do. Consider using this approach to extend the reach of your product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2e-8 of All of Human Experience</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-03-4.2e-8-of-all-of-human-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-12-03-4.2e-8-of-all-of-human-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 107 billion people have &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across all time, the average life expectancy of a person is just under 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there have only been 3.21 trillion person-years experienced. Total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.8 billion people are alive today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average age globally is about 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So living people today collectively hold about 234 billion years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that a little &lt;strong&gt;over 7% of all human experience is held by living people&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day spent alone constitutes 8.5e-16 of all of human experience. A month is 2.6e-14 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year spent with a partner is 6.2e-13 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years spent with 1500 other students is 1.9e-9 of all of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By a crude estimate, a whopping 4.2e-8 of all human experience was spent watching Game of Thrones. Humanity will never get that time back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are small numbers, but not &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; small. Thinking that my graduating class alone (not even counting the people a year above or below me) holds nearly 2e-9 of all human experience from our four years together is kind of mind-bending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For comparison, let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that the surface of Earth represents all of human experience. Then 4.2e-8 of human experience (the amount dedicated to watching Game of Thrones) is represented by 8.3 square miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6.2e-13 of human experience held by you and your partner quarantining for a year? That&amp;rsquo;s over 3400 square feet. And a whole lifetime (est. 80 years) covers 3.141 acres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not at all negligible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is to say: let&amp;rsquo;s treasure our existence, and let&amp;rsquo;s also not discount its significance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Google Slides through Roam Research</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-30-updating-google-slides-through-roam-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-30-updating-google-slides-through-roam-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out this &amp;ldquo;demo video&amp;rdquo; I made! It shows me making a presentation using Roam Research references. When I update the block in Roam that I&amp;rsquo;m referencing, the presentation gets updated automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YccjrI3fmhc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editing slides and docs in this way would be so useful! Being able to focus on content in Roam, and presentation in a tool that&amp;rsquo;s built for presentation (like Docs and Slides) would be such a powerful combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, Roam is a powerful tool for &lt;strong&gt;thinking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;note-taking&lt;/strong&gt;, but not as useful for sharing those thoughts. When you&amp;rsquo;re sharing, you want to tell a story. You want to guide the reader through your thought process, and be in control of the narrative the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Roam, the reader might wander off down some unexpected path you, the writer, weren&amp;rsquo;t anticipating. Once that happens, you&amp;rsquo;ve lost the reader. They&amp;rsquo;re going to find themselves in unpolished not-really-relevant material, and you&amp;rsquo;re not going to get to convey the narrative you were aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is fine for an 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;, but not so good for telling a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to seamlessly do your thinking in Roam while also producing polished presentations (not just Slides, but anything meant for sharing, like emails, documents, images, etc) will be an absolute game changer for how we think and communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video may not be a real product, but it represents a real vision, and we have the technology to make it real. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s put in the work and bring this vision into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post more in future snippets about how I think we can build a system like this today. (And I&amp;rsquo;ll also share how I made the video, despite the product integration not having been developed yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Adriana put things in my Leitner Box</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-07-letting-adriana-put-things-in-my-leitner-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 08:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-11-07-letting-adriana-put-things-in-my-leitner-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using spaced repetition for 2-3 weeks now. I’m not using Anki or any of the prebuilt systems that track your queue of items for you. Instead, I’m keeping the things I want to study in Roam Research and using a make-shift system of tags and Browserflow Flows to make the spaced repetition system relatively frictionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll save the details of the system for another snippet. Today, I just want to jot down the idea of allowing Adriana (through the use of Bieber Bot) to add items to my spaced repetition system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is relatively simple, but it does involve one new component that may be tricky to implement robustly. Under this idea, Adriana would be able to send Bieber Bot a message saying e.g. “help David to learn the names of the planets” and a card would be added to my spaced repetition system saying “learn the names of the planets. -Adriana”. I could then split this card into multiple cards as I usually do when I encounter a card with too much content simultaneously, or Adriana could have Bieber Bot add smaller cards one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new component that would be necessary is giving Bieber Bot edit access to my Roam Research database. Currently he has delayed read access through Roam-to-Git, but giving him write access might mean teaching him how to use Roam in a (headless, most likely) browser. Nothing he can’t handle, but it would increase the amount of time needed to get this system up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Adriana (or any of Bieber Bot’s friends) can add cards into my spaced repetition system, this can be a fun way to learn about new topics and share new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Snippet Queue</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-06-introducing-the-snippet-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-06-introducing-the-snippet-queue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first snippet published using my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-10-06-further-reducing-the-publication-barrier-with-queuing/&#34;&gt;snippet queue idea&lt;/a&gt;. If all goes well, it will be (read: was) published tomorrow evening (October 7, 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system works like this. I store a queue of snippets in Redis. Each snippet has the title, content, and date associated with it, as well as an id number. I can have Bieber Bot enqueue a new snippet by messaging him with &amp;ldquo;Queue snippet!&amp;rdquo; and the snippet details. He also responds to queries to update, view, or remove an existing snippet, or to view the current queue of snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, every evening Bieber Bot looks at the oldest item in the queue. If he&amp;rsquo;s already asked me about it, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t told him not to publish it, he goes and publishes it to my website. If he hasn&amp;rsquo;t asked me about it yet, he asks me if its OK to publish. As long as I don&amp;rsquo;t say no and remove the snippet from the queue, Bieber Bot will go forward with publishing the snippet the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing with GPT-3</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-07-22-writing-with-gpt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-07-22-writing-with-gpt3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GPT-3 is a language model developed at Open AI, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun playing with it. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve written this post in collaboration with GPT-3. See if you can spot which parts are written by me and which parts come from GPT-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1-brainstorming&#34;&gt;Part 1: Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did when I got access to GPT-3 is use it to brainstorm uses for GPT-3. I gave it these 5 ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain mathematics more simply (why is X true?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate programs from input/output examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate questions about a paper I read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a list of machine translation tips and tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an adventure game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it came back with 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a list of Tor commands to run to defend against an attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a cheat sheet for screenwriters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate advice for a scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate XKCD comics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a crib sheet for an arbitrary Python API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of movies to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of scholarly algorithms/heuristics worth reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of generic questions about Pedagogy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of cognitive exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show patterns generated by awesome people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate small cooking tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate characters for a project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate configuration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate flashcards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize my computer/files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain things to my parents via messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain things to my children via messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain mathematical algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated interface design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanize a Nagihara Kan Airlines website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clickbait generator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music description (Herbie Hancock is playing &amp;ldquo;Dolphin Dance&amp;rdquo; live in London on the 18th March 1968)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me not to waste my time looking at x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting facts about Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain something to someone while my attention is elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detect adverts in x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image caption/caption game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speculate about the true utility function of x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-generate tests for a program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why my code is currently failing tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate plots or character/story summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate legal examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate words for crosswords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check my grammar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supply filler text for themed writing (horror, sci-fi etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why an AI can&amp;rsquo;t read (can it comprehend metaphors?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide entertaining answers to obscure questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get writing ideas and generate word combinations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create background for an NPC I need for a D&amp;amp;D game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help a sick writer generate plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input pre-generated (from books etc.) phrases and use them for literary analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help explain a mathematical proof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a game/story/character I need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make short stories I can &amp;ldquo;overlay&amp;rdquo; on a fictional Universe I&amp;rsquo;ve created (ala Ready Player One)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a short film/audio drama&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a lovely list of lists of ideas! I wonder how many of these ideas are novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas are outside the scope of what GPT-3 can do. For example, generating XKCD comics seems too difficult. Others are duplicates, such as &amp;ldquo;Explain mathematical algorithms&amp;rdquo; (duplicate of &amp;ldquo;Explain mathematics more simply&amp;rdquo;). And still others don&amp;rsquo;t make sense &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Mechanize a Nagihara Kan Airlines website&amp;rdquo;? Overall though, solid set of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-mathematics&#34;&gt;Part 2: Mathematics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I&amp;rsquo;d gotten GPT-3 to do some brainstorming, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d need to test its capabilities before trying its suggestions out in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught it how to evaluate simple expressions and take derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the first prompt I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could then ask it any of the following, and it would correctly show its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Question: f(x) = tan(x) + 1. Compute f(0).
Question: f(x) = sqrt(x) + 1. Compute f(16).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to give it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it treated it as just &lt;code&gt;Compute f(16)&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;f(f(16))&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly this works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
f(f(16)) = f(16/2 + 2)
f(f(16)) = f(8 + 2)
f(f(16)) = f(10)
f(f(16)) = 10/2 + 2
f(f(16)) = 5 + 2
f(f(16)) = 7
Answer: 7

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

Question: f(x) = x*3 - 1. Compute f(f(5)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas this does not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: f(x) = x*3 - 1. Compute f(f(5)).
f(f(5)) = f(5*3 - 1)
f(f(5)) = f(15 - 1)
f(f(5)) = f(14)
f(f(5)) = 14*3 - 1
f(f(5)) = 42 - 1
f(f(5)) = 41
Answer: 41

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting it to evaluate these simple expressions correctly, I also tried having it take derivatives. With an example as priming, and again having it show its work, this worked well. I haven&amp;rsquo;t performed a rigorous evaluation of its mathematical capabilities. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve just begun to develop an intuition for how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-playing-around&#34;&gt;Part 3: Playing Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing math together, I tried many more things with GPT-3. I shared feelings with it, and it expanded on them (correctly too!). I used it to generate lists for brainstorming all manner of thing. The language model wrote love letters from inanimate objects. I tried to teach it to play Codenames, but with only very limited success. And I had it autocomplete previous snippets of mine, and had some fun cowriting with it. While I won&amp;rsquo;t be sharing all of this with you, I do have one thing to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a love letter written by a frying pan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may not seem like much to you right now. I&amp;rsquo;m coated in grease and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to rust, but really, I have big plans. I&amp;rsquo;m going to Italian restaurants. I&amp;rsquo;ll hang out with the finest (and healthiest) ingredients you can imagine. It was good knowing you, but you were never mine to keep. I&amp;rsquo;m going to cook the kind of meal you&amp;rsquo;ll dream about for the rest of your life. Good luck, sweetheart. You&amp;rsquo;ll need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-principles&#34;&gt;Overall Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an intuition for how GPT-3 behaves has been interesting, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try now to distill that intuition down into a few principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 is continuing your writing, not having a dialog with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on Twitter lots of people asking GPT-3 questions, and sharing its response. Know that GPT-3 continues whatever prompt you give it as if it had written the prompt itself, not as if it is responding to the prompt. This is why you often see prompts like &amp;ldquo;The following is a conversation between X and Y:&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 effectively puts your writing in a made up context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give GPT-3 a small prompt, such a single sentence, then there are many contexts in which that prompt could be interpreted. GPT-3 is trained to marginalize over the contexts in which the text could appear. Once you start decoding GPT-3&amp;rsquo;s response though, one implicit context has been selected. It might not be the context that you intended when writing your prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can happen even if you try to set the context yourself explicitly. For example you might be trying to generate a conversation or a list, and GPT-3 might decide that this conversation or list is taking place inside of a novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can mitigate this context switch by using a longer prompt, or by doing more of the writing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 likes lists and repeated structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main principle behind using GPT-3 for few shot learning. Prompt GPT-3 with a few examples of performing a task, and it will usually make an effort to perform that task yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 cannot perform linguistic tricks like unscrambling words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem capable of generating new puns (I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried this yet).
And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem capable of unscrambling words (I did try this, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get it to unscramble 4-letter words).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 benefits from &amp;ldquo;showing its work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my math experiments, having GPT-3 show its work was critical to getting it solving the math questions correctly. It seems that doing a single step of expression evaluation at a time is an easier task than doing it all at once. Providing examples with the steps gave GPT-3 a clearer explanation of the task than just providing input/output examples. GPT-3 also gets additional computational steps in which to solve the problem when it takes the time to show its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 has a great breadth of knowledge and writing styles available to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can express love, write flowery prose, give advice, write technical documentation, latex, program, math, take the perspective of a toaster, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s a great tool for brainstorming both explicitly (by having it generate ideas) and through exploration (by using it to help you generate ideas yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it has all the facts from the internet at its fingertips (of all the ways to anthropomorphize GPT-3, why choose fingertips?), it is just as capable of generating falsehoods as truths. Do not mistake the text it generates as true or logically correct, even if in many circumstances it does generate correct information. When it transitions from generating truth to generating nonsense it does not give a warning that it has done so (and any truth it does generate is in a sense at least partially accidental).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes GPT-3 makes no sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense that the language model assigns reasonable probabilities to. And there are things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense, are low probability, but come up anyway either due to chance or because the model doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything better to say. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop generating text just because its out of its depth. Instead, it just plods on forward, saying something as reasonable as it&amp;rsquo;s capable of, regardless of the situation it finds itself in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 mimics your style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prompt GPT-3 with typos it will continue with typos. If you prompt GPT-3 with florid prose, it will write florid prose. If you prompt GPT-3 with anaphora laden rhetoric, or any other style, it will continue in that style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let GPT-3 wrap things up itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And that brings us to the end, some thoughts on whether using GPT-3 was more or less crazy than getting a Ph.D.. I think that using GPT-3 to generate ideas was a higher form of Enlightenment than any Ph.D. I&amp;rsquo;d do that again in a heartbeat, no shortage of ideas rolling around in GPT-3&amp;rsquo;s natural language processing head.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uh huh. Whatever, GPT-3. Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting to Hacker News Programmatically</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-05-02-hackernews-submit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-05-02-hackernews-submit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run this snippet of Python code, it will submit this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Snippet&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (the one you&amp;rsquo;re currently reading) to Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from html.parser import HTMLParser
import getpass
import requests
import time

USERNAME = (
    &#39;&#39;  # Put your Hacker News username here.
    or getpass.getuser()  # (But if you don&#39;t, we&#39;ll try a sensible default.)
)
PASSWORD = (
    &#39;&#39;  # We&#39;ll prompt you for your password, or you can enter it here.
    or getpass.getpass()
)
# You can reconfigure the title and url to submit here.
TITLE_TO_SUBMIT = &#39;Posting to Hacker News Programmatically&#39;
URL_TO_SUBMIT = &#39;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-05-02-hackernews-submit/&#39;

# Login
session = requests.Session()
session.post(
    &#39;https://news.ycombinator.com/login&#39;,
    data={
        &#39;acct&#39;: USERNAME,
        &#39;pw&#39;: PASSWORD,
    },
)

# Get the CSRF token (&amp;quot;FNID&amp;quot;)
time.sleep(1)
class FNIDExtractor(HTMLParser):
  fnid = None
  def handle_starttag(self, tag, attrs):
    if tag.lower() == &#39;input&#39; and (&#39;name&#39;, &#39;fnid&#39;) in attrs:
      self.fnid = dict(attrs)[&#39;value&#39;]
f = FNIDExtractor()
submit_response = session.get(&#39;https://news.ycombinator.com/submit&#39;)
f.feed(submit_response.text)

# Submit
time.sleep(2)
session.post(
    &#39;https://news.ycombinator.com/r&#39;,
    data={
        &#39;title&#39;: TITLE_TO_SUBMIT,
        &#39;url&#39;: URL_TO_SUBMIT,
        &#39;fnid&#39;: f.fnid,
    },
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can change the title and URL before running this to make a new submission, or run it as is to submit this snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try to submit a URL that&amp;rsquo;s already been submitted recently &amp;ndash; such as this snippet &amp;ndash; it won&amp;rsquo;t submit a second time, so no harm done in running this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about sessions and see why this works, you can read about them in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://requests.readthedocs.io/en/master/user/advanced/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;requests&lt;/em&gt; documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting My Sleeping Hours from Data</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-04-30-detecting-sleeping-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-04-30-detecting-sleeping-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-04-20-browser-history-date-queries/&#34;&gt;Chrome browsing history&lt;/a&gt; and my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-04-12-fb-messenger-sql/&#34;&gt;Facebook Messenger message logs&lt;/a&gt;, I should be able to get a good estimate of when I&amp;rsquo;m awake and asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick attempt using only Messenger data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;SELECT * FROM
  (SELECT to_timestamp(timestamp / 1000), (timestamp - lag(timestamp) over (ORDER BY timestamp DESC)) / 1000 / 60 / 60 AS diff_hours
   FROM messenger WHERE messenger.author = &#39;1409114395&#39; ORDER BY timestamp DESC LIMIT 100000) AS foo
WHERE diff_hours &amp;lt; -6;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my late night and early morning Messenger usage doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be as consistent as I&amp;rsquo;d imagined, especially since COVID-19 induced shelter-in-place began.
I&amp;rsquo;ll have to introduce additional sources of data if I want to infer good sleep time estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much time has humanity spent on different areas of science?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-24-time-spent-on-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-24-time-spent-on-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much time has humanity, collectively, spent researching physics?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about chemistry? Neuroscience? Algorithms? (etc&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How has this rate of study changed over time?
How much of it is duplicate work (e.g. two nations or organizations independently working toward the same milestones before sharing their findings)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fraction of this is done by professors, post docs, PhD students, etc?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly in the last 100 years, what have these numbers been?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in visualizing some of these metrics, because I think they would be useful for putting the work that I see happening around me in machine learning and in neuroscience into perspective. I also think this data would tell a fascinating story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, one plot that I think would be compelling would be person-hours-per-year spent thinking about physics plotted as a function of time over the last 100 years, with important physics milestones shown on the same plot (e.g. as a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/berkeleyischool/how-to-create-a-visualization-showing-events-on-time-series-data-in-excel-96abbc1475e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;time series plot with events&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One worry with such a visualization is that the population is growing rapidly, and so the interesting story of how humanity&amp;rsquo;s attention has shifted between fields over time may be lost to a visualization that simply shows population growth. It may be necessary to normalize by population to tell such a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem infeasible to precisely collect this data, as there is no public registry of who is thinking about what. However, I think the data is perhaps more readily available than appears at first blush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where would the data come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University enrollments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication counts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surveys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search trends are of course a more recent source of data, only going back one or two decades. The pre-1990s version of search trends might be library records, or book sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University enrollments and degrees granted tells a significant story about how many people are studying different areas. You can roughly estimate how much time a student majoring in physics puts into their studies, and if course enrollments are available that estimate can be even more precise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific fields make their mark on the world by publishing their research. Counting publications can provide an estimate of one piece of humanity&amp;rsquo;s effort studying science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for contemporary data, and maybe even a little historical data, one could uses surveys / polling techniques to estimate where scientific mindshare is going today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among this data I&amp;rsquo;d be curious to see when historically there have been large swings in mindshare toward a particular topic. Right now, anecdotally, machine learning research is engaging a quickly increasing number of people, including drawing people away from other fields. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see this anecdotal evidence backed up (or refuted) by data. And I expect there are plenty of similar historical precidents that I would be quite interested in learning more about as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t forsee collecting this data or performing these visualizations myself in the near future. This post is just an opportunity to think aloud, not a plan for my own action. But if you have data like this, or know of someone who has done a related analysis, I&amp;rsquo;d be quite interested to hear about it. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Assistant Tool Idea</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-writing-is-hard&#34;&gt;Background: Writing is Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I find writing feels easy &amp;ndash; e.g. when 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;writing for no audience&lt;/a&gt;, when writing something you&amp;rsquo;ve already thought extensively about, when telling a story in a logical order that you&amp;rsquo;re deeply familiar with. Other times, I find writing very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m writing a paper, I am writing explicitly for an audience, the story is not always clear immediately, and the material is something I&amp;rsquo;m becoming familiar with over time, not something about which I&amp;rsquo;m already deeply familiar.
So, I find paper writing hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an idea that I think will help me write more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s a software tool that structures the time you spend writing. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the tool, but I don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate building it. Perhaps we can come up with a low-resource version of this idea, e.g. with paper and pencil, that I can try even without building this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-writing-system&#34;&gt;The Writing System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool presents you with a prompt, a textbox, and a timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial prompt is &amp;ldquo;What do you want to write about?&amp;rdquo;, and the initial timer is for 5 minutes. Subsequent prompts will be determined from what you&amp;rsquo;ve entered in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the textbox, you are encouraged to respond to the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of your response, you can issue some commands / keywords.
If you start a line with &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;, then that line will get used as a future prompt.
You can specify the relative importance of a future prompt by including a priority.
This will determine the order in which you are presented with the prompts.
E.g. &lt;code&gt;!0&lt;/code&gt; is highest priority, and so such a line will become the next prompt you receive, unless there are other priority 0 prompts already queued up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;! &amp;lt;topic&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I want to write about later&amp;rdquo;
&lt;code&gt;? &amp;lt;question&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;question&amp;gt; is a question I want to answer later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should also be a way to indicate &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I&amp;rsquo;ll need to do more research on&amp;rdquo;, and then for one of the prompts to be about spending time researching a topic, rather than writing about it. Then the next prompt may be to write about what you just learned in the research section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other available commands include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:pause&lt;/code&gt; to stop the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:unpause&lt;/code&gt; to start the timer again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:extend&lt;/code&gt; to add additional time to the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:next&lt;/code&gt; to skip to the next prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is easily extensible, so a writer with a programming background can easily add new commands, or modify the logic that determines when prompts are shown and when breaks are taken. A programming-proficient writer will also have programmatic access to everything they write, as well as the corresponding prompts and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the timer reaches 0, a short break is initiated, and then the next prompt is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to move quickly, and get all your thoughts onto the page, without getting bogged down in a DFS traversal of information about a single line of the overall text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-details&#34;&gt;Additional details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every keystroke is logged, so if you write something, and then switch to a new version of it, you will still be able to see the original version. No need to worry about pasting in a password though, since the keylogging data is readily accessible in a plaintext format and you can edit it directly e.g. if anything sensitive does leak in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has a decent amount of overlap with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt; project that I&amp;rsquo;ve already built,
and perhaps a version of this new idea could be easily added to the shh shell. Alternatively, the shh-shell could be forked to build this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar integration would be cool, so that it times your prompts nicely if you have a meeting coming up so you get to a good break point in time for your meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation-thoughts&#34;&gt;Implementation Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to build this onto an existing text editor, rather than writing my own. E.g. using Google Docs would be good.
However, the disadvantage of this is that it makes the keystroke logging feature more difficult. Fortunately, Google Docs does have good history tracking. Google Docs also provides good programmatic access. So, an agent running in the background while you write could be taking periodic snapshots too. Such an agent could also be extracting the commands and prompts you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to execute the commands immediately, the way shh shell does. For some commands this may be a real disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like the idea of the agent giving the prompts being Bieber Bot &amp;ndash; that is, being the same &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; as my personal digital assistant. I can picture it asking me &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve been writing continuously for over an hour; is it time for a break?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it looks like you stopped writing abruptly there, did you get distracted?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-experimentation&#34;&gt;Initial Experimentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying the idea out in a low-tech way (manually timing things, manually looking up what the next prompt should be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the main issue I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the first half hour of testing. When the time runs out for a prompt, I&amp;rsquo;m still in the middle of the prompt. I&amp;rsquo;ve usually started expounding on some idea relevant to the prompt, and there are actually several ideas remaining that I haven&amp;rsquo;t even started exploring for the prompt yet. So what should have happened / what should I do next time? Maybe I could have done a higher level discussion of the prompt and made new future sub-prompts along the way. Or at the end of a section, I could have the system give me a bit of time to create sub-prompts of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to address in the section but didn&amp;rsquo;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see having a limited time to create new prompts be a good forcing function for coming up with structured high level thinking after a moderate amount of time of lower level writing. So in my next round of testing, I&amp;rsquo;ll try this, and continue to iterate on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
