<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>note-taking on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/note-taking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in note-taking on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/note-taking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Complete and Concise List of Go Note Go&#39;s Features</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt; is a computer keyboard with no screen that I use to capture ideas anywhere, even as I drift off to sleep.
This is a complete list of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s features as of January 2023. Expand any of the features for more information about it.
The main use cases for Go Note Go are capturing thoughts while sleeping, driving, camping, and showering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&#34;expand-button&#34; onclick=&#34;expandCollapseAll()&#34;&gt;Expand All&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
details details {
  margin-left: 2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-features-just-the-useful-ones&#34;&gt;Main features (Just the useful ones)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture typed notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main feature of Go Note Go. Anything you type on it will show up in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about whether you have your note-taking app open, or whether your computer is running slowly.
One of the challenges I face with jotting things down when I&amp;rsquo;m at a computer is quickly getting to the place where I can jot things down.
Switching to my notes app can be slow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with a keyboard shortcut or a hot corner for taking notes, this requires switching focus on your computer.
You need to wait until the text field shows up. Once the text field has focus, then you can type, but if for some reason your computer is running slowly, your mind will run slowly too. By this, I mean that when letters show up slowly on a screen, it slows down the speed at which you think.
When typing with a screen, people naturally wait for the screen to catch up before continuing typing a thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Go Note Go, there&amp;rsquo;s no screen to see your notes. You don&amp;rsquo;t spend time waiting for the computer to catch up to you.
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch windows or click in a textbox before you can start typing.
You simply turn to the Go Note Go keyboard, and everything you type will show up in your notes once the Go Note Go gets an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture spoken notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go can also capture spoken notes.
Press the capture key (escape, by default; you can also use a large handheld red button if preferred) and Go Note Go will start recording.
Press the capture key again to stop recording.
The recording will be transcribed and added to your notes once Go Note Go has internet.
The raw audio is also included in your notes alongside the transcription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capturing spoken notes is especially useful for capturing ideas while driving.
Obviously I&amp;rsquo;m not typing on the keyboard while I&amp;rsquo;m driving; that would be unsafe. (The passenger can type though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to take spoken notes can also occasionally come in handy as I drift off to sleep.
Usually, I prefer typing, even as I drift off to sleep. It seems to wake me up less.
But when I&amp;rsquo;m especially tired, speaking can feel like the lower effort method and wake me up less than typing does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio notes are not always transcribed perfectly, and are annotated with &amp;ldquo;unverified transcription&amp;rdquo; by default.
You can verify the transcription is correct, cleaning up any transcription mistakes, and can quickly mark the transcription as verified to help you keep track of which transcriptions have and have not been reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;No screen&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having a screen is one of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s major selling points for me, and it comes with a host of benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost it means that there are no distractions while writing.
As a result my head feels so much clearer when I sit down to write at a Go Note Go compared to writing at a computer.
When writing on a computer, the internet is there with all its 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/2020-10-01-infinite-distractions-and-getting-a-good-sear/&#34;&gt;infinite distractions&lt;/a&gt;, which can make staying focused a challenge.
None of those scroll-inducing websites exist on Go Note Go, making it easier to think and stick to my intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absence of a screen also helps me to write more effectively.
For me, some of the main challenges in writing are losing time to repeatedly rereading what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, and wordsmithing it with relatively inconsequential edits that would be better to hold off until revisions.
Since you can&amp;rsquo;t see typos while working on Go Note Go, you learn to accept them, and you save small amounts of time in significant quantities by not fixing little errors as you write. All of that can be cleaned up in post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the main 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-12-30-go-note-go-story/&#34;&gt;initial motivation&lt;/a&gt; for not having a screen is that it lets me capture thoughts even as I drift off to sleep, without waking me up very much.
Alternatives to capturing thoughts like turning on the lights to write on paper, taking out my phone or computer, or speaking into a voice recorder all wake me (or my partner) up more than just typing on a keyboard in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually find Go Note Go helpful for getting to sleep, since it lets me get thoughts out of my head.
Without it, sometimes an anxious thought will swirl around in my head, showing up repeatedly in dozens of different forms.
Using Go Note Go, I can get a single version of the thought into my notes, and somehow that minimizes the thought swirling.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if by finding a canonical version of the thought and preserving it in Go Note Go, my brain is relieved of its duty to hold onto the thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Works offline&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go works offline. You can bring it into the woods with you if you want to go camping, for example.
Normally, I leave Go Note Go plugged into a standard outlet, but I also have a battery pack I take with me for using Go Note Go on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notes you enter into Go Note Go are uploaded to your notes as soon as internet becomes available.
It&amp;rsquo;s OK if the battery dies before then; the notes are stored on a MicroSD card and will be uploaded later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Go Note Go transcribes your notes once internet becomes available.
Voice notes don&amp;rsquo;t get transcribed on device; we currently use Google Transcription as our transcription provider, which requires an internet connection.
So, voice notes taken in the forest are transcribed and uploaded once you get back to civilization and Go Note Go connects to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working offline is particularly useful for using Go Note Go while driving and camping.
It also makes Go Note Go a good candidate for writing in parks or coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Act as an outliner&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using tab to indent and shift-tab to dedent, you can use Go Note Go as a proper outliner.
This allows you to take properly nested notes, despite not being able to see them while you take them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full list of outliner controls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab to indent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Tab to dedent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Delete to clear the current note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter on an empty note dedents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Delete on an empty note dedents the maximum amount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Enter starts a new session (a separate section of notes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 minutes of inactivity also starts a new session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitting enter on an empty line also causes a dedent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Run commands&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Go Note Go, any note that starts with a colon is interpreted as a command. There are loads of commands, generally they produce audio output (like reading the time aloud). I&amp;rsquo;ve listed the main commands here, and adding new commands with Python is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/command_center/commands.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;easy&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:time&lt;/code&gt; Read the time out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:r&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:read&lt;/code&gt; Read the last note out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:q TEXT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:ask TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Ask a question of the AI assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt; Send the current session of notes to the AI assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:at TIME:DO&lt;/code&gt; Schedule command DO to run at time TIME. TIME can be a natural language time like &amp;ldquo;in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;8am&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ok&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:status&lt;/code&gt; Say &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; out loud; useful for verifying your hands are in the right place and that Go Note Go is on and functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands can also be activated via voice. Press the capture button (escape by default) and say &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo; followed by the command to trigger its execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are additional commands for configuring Go Note Go, as well as more technical commands less useful during common usage.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Expand this for the full list of commands.&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-commands&#34;&gt;System commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:whoami&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:who am i&lt;/code&gt; Read aloud the current user and currently selected note-taking system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:time&lt;/code&gt; Read the time out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:at TIME:DO&lt;/code&gt; Schedule command DO to run at time TIME. TIME can be a natural language time like &amp;ldquo;in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;8am&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:status&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ok&lt;/code&gt; Say &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; out loud; useful for verifying your hands are in the right place and that Go Note Go is on and functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:say TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Say TEXT out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:shell CMD&lt;/code&gt; Run command CMD in a shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:flush&lt;/code&gt; Flush the logs; this is useful for debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:update&lt;/code&gt; Download updates to your Go Note Go; :restart for them to take effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:restart&lt;/code&gt; Restart all Go Note Go processes on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:reboot&lt;/code&gt; Reboot the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:env&lt;/code&gt; Log the environment variables and their values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ip&lt;/code&gt; Read the IP address of the Go Note Go out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:i&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:internet&lt;/code&gt; Say Yes or No out loud, indicating whether Go Note Go has internet access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:wifi SSID PSK&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:wpa SSID PSK&lt;/code&gt; Configure Go Note Go to connect to the wifi with ssid SSID using passkey PSK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;settings-commands&#34;&gt;Settings Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:get KEY&lt;/code&gt; Read out loud the value associated with setting KEY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:set KEY VALUE&lt;/code&gt; Set the setting KEY to VALUE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:clear KEY&lt;/code&gt; Clear setting KEY, reverting its value back to that found in your settings.py file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:clear&lt;/code&gt; Clear all settings entered via the :set command, reverting their values back to those found in your settings.py file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:leds ON/OFF/LOW&lt;/code&gt; Set the brightness of the LEDs. Only relevant if you&amp;rsquo;re using the Adafruit Voice Bonnet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:v ON/OFF&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:volume ON/OFF&lt;/code&gt; Turn the audio volume on or off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:get status KEY&lt;/code&gt; Get status indicator given by KEY. The status indicators are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/common/status.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possible settings are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo/blob/main/gonotego/settings/secure_settings_template.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note-commands-unnecessary&#34;&gt;Note commands (Unnecessary!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:note TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Add TEXT as a note. (Just type TEXT! No need to use this command.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:subnote TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Add TEXT as an indented note. (Just indent and type TEXT! No need to use this command.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter-commands&#34;&gt;Twitter Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is not a common use case for Go Note Go, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit funny that it has it&amp;rsquo;s own section. These commands are predominantly for configuring Go Note Go to use your Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter user&lt;/code&gt; Read the current Twitter use out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter user USER&lt;/code&gt; Set the current Twitter user to USER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter auth&lt;/code&gt; Start the Twitter auth flow for Go Note Go developers (requires ssh and implementation-details to complete).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter auth EMAIL&lt;/code&gt; Start the Twitter auth flow; instructions for completing the flow will be emailed to EMAIL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter pin PIN&lt;/code&gt; Use this command to complete the auth flow; enter the pin you received in the email from the previous command as PIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:twitter&lt;/code&gt; Switch the current note-taking system to be Twitter. Now all notes will be posted directly to Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To log into Twitter, run &lt;code&gt;:twitter&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:twitter user USER&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:twitter auth EMAIL&lt;/code&gt;, and finally &lt;code&gt;:twitter pin PIN&lt;/code&gt; entering the pin you receive in the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-commands&#34;&gt;Email Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:email TO SUBJECT: TEXT&lt;/code&gt; Send an email to TO with subject SUBJECT and body TEXT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding new commands is always a pleasure, but it&amp;rsquo;s good to keep the capabilities of Go Note Go limited, to prevent potential distractions from creeping onto the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Audio-only clock&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go sports loads of commands (see above), but the one I use most is having Go Note Go read the time out loud. I prefer this to looking at a clock or my phone because I can keep my eyes closed as I use it, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t wake me up as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To trigger this feature, I type &lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;AI assistant&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI assistant is a feature I only added recently to Go Note Go, and I have a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/&#34;&gt;whole snippet&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to my experience with it. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of interacting with the assistant today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:q TEXT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:ask TEXT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I just want to ask a single question of the assistant, I use this command. The assistant&amp;rsquo;s response is read out loud. This is the more private approach as only TEXT is sent to the AI, not any additional notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to have an extended conversation or interaction with the AI assistant, I use this command. I can either run &lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt; after typing my message to the AI, or I can prefix my message with &lt;code&gt;:ai&lt;/code&gt;. Both work. This command sends the entire session of notes to the AI assistant. The AI assistant&amp;rsquo;s response is read out loud, and is included in the session of notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the AI&amp;rsquo;s responses are included in the notes and are marked as being AI responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/&#34;&gt;read more about my experience talking to the AI assistant as I drift off to sleep here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-wait-theres-more&#34;&gt;But wait, there&amp;rsquo;s more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Use your favorite note-taking system: Roam Research, RemNote, Mem, IdeaFlow, Notion, or even Twitter or Email&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported note-taking systems are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roam Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RemNote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IdeaFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roam Research is the one I use daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are Twitter and Email on this list?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you set your note-taking system to Twitter, every note you take on your Go Note Go will be posted to Twitter. This is an unconventional choice! Perhaps you like thinking in public though. Perhaps you live in a community house and want a place to share quirky quotes that come up. You do you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email is a nice fallback system for people that don&amp;rsquo;t already use one of the others. When I give Go Note Gos as gifts, I generally configure them to use email so. This lets the Go Note Go work out-of-the-box without the recipient needing to configure it with their account credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also switch between note-taking systems at any point with a single command. I recommend making your Go Note Go a single-purpose device with just a single target note-taking system, but you should still note that this is an option. The command to switch note-taking systems is &lt;code&gt;:set uploader NOTE_TAKING_SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;NOTE_TAKING_SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; is one of &lt;code&gt;email&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ideaflow&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;remnote&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;roam&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mem&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;notion&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;twitter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Never miss a note&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you walk away from Go Note Go without hitting enter, your note will be submitted after 3 minutes of inactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go boots in about 15 seconds, after which point it is always ready to receive inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s always ready &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s no tab switching or waiting required before you can start typing &amp;ndash; is a big deal to me.
Compared with writing notes on a computer, writing on Go Note Go feels smoother and more natural.
On a computer, I need to switch tabs to give focus to my note-taking app before I can start typing.
That context switch may sound small, but it is meaningful, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have done away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the option to pause note-taking on your Go Note Go. This is not recommended. To enable this, set the PAUSE_HOTKEY setting.
This creates a trigger for pausing and unpausing note-taking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Send people messages&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending people messages is actually not a core feature of Go Note Go, but it is something that I built for myself on top of Go Note Go.
If I include text like &amp;ldquo;@Person&amp;rdquo; in my notes, then my Messager project will pick up the note and queue up a message to Person.
Notes nested underneath the @-tagged note are also included in the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;a whole post dedicated to this feature&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported messaging systems in the Messager project are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter (both public and private tweets, as well as DMs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacker News submissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iMessage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord - this one unfortunately is not in a working state at this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It supports aliases, so that I can set short-names for people to send messages to their preferred communications platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a message is in the queue, I can clean it up and approve it. I can also specify a time for it to send, with the default being to send now.
Once approved, it sends automatically at the desired time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Mounts on the passenger side of the dashboard&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put Velcro on the bottom of one of my Go Note Gos, and on the passenger side of my car dashboard.
This way I can mount the Go Note Go in the car.
Using the capture button (e.g. a large handheld red button), you can capture audio recordings while driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve largely switched away from using Go Note Go while driving in favor of calling by AI assistant on the phone (implemented via Twilio).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;It&#39;s open source&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code and set up instructions for Go Note Go are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;all freely available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total cost of parts is about $100. I encourage you to make your own! Please 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;go-note-go@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me if you do&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;The right amount of customizability&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing you can configure is which note-taking system you&amp;rsquo;d like to upload your notes to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be any of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roam Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RemNote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IdeaFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw audio files are uploaded to Dropbox and included in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two other areas Go Note Go can be configured are adding new commands, and adding new note-taking systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Your notes are easy to review&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you take notes on Go Note Go, they are divided into sessions.
Each time you sit down at a Go Note Go after a period of inactivity, a new session is created.
You can also start a new session at any time by hitting Shift-Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notes, sessions are timestamped and organized chronologically. All the notes in a session are nested underneath the timestamped session header.
When I review my notes, I like to place a one-line summary of a session in the timestamped session header. I can then collapse the session.
This makes it easy to quickly scan through my notes, looking only at the session headers. I can expand a session to see it&amp;rsquo;s contents for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/01-17-2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Take a look at some example Go Note Go notes here&lt;/a&gt; to see what this looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emergent-benefits&#34;&gt;Emergent benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Focus and Relief&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like how Go Note Go is a single-purpose device.
The absence of a screen and the absence of any distractions on Go Note Go make for a soothing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a desk at home with just a Go Note Go on it.
Sitting down at my Go Note Go desk fills me with an immediate sense of relief.
When writing at a computer, by comparison, I notice a tension in my body.
Go Note Go relieves this tension and clears my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Avoid distracting others (incl. w/ Bluetooth headphones)&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi 400s have Bluetooth support. So, you can connect Bluetooth headphones to Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, I use Go Note Go with my AirPods. When I put the AirPods in, Go Note Go automatically connects.
I can then ask the AI assistant questions on the Go Note Go and get the answers piped directly to my ears,
so my coworkers are not distracted.
If I take the headphones out, Go Note Go outputs to the attached speaker.
So, I can show colleagues Go Note Go without them needing to put headphones in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also consider capturing ideas as you drift off to sleep.
Compared with other options for capturing these ideas, Go Note Go is comparatively non-disruptive.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any bright lights or loud sounds.
It&amp;rsquo;s not perfectly quiet either though, so there&amp;rsquo;s room for improvement here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Check the time without fully waking up&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s commands all work without you ever having to open your eyes.
If you&amp;rsquo;re drifting off to sleep, this is ideal. You can get the time without activating your brain too much, making it easier to continue drifting off to sleep.
Compare this with looking at your phone or at a clock. These options require opening your eyes, possibly subjecting them to bright lights.
No thank you. I prefer Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;:t&lt;/code&gt; command for getting the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Take it camping&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go lasts for about twelve hours on this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07JYYRT7T?th=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3A 10400mAh power bank&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s small and lightweight, easy to toss in the car and take camping.
There are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/5292&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cases&lt;/a&gt; you can purchase to make Go Note Go more portable for this kind of use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camping was one of the original use cases for Go Note Go, and in fact I designed the system and ordered the first batch of parts while camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for camping are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works offline, so you can use it anywhere; it will upload your notes as soon as you get an internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s portable and can run on battery for a decent length of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no screen or bright lights to annoy other campers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture thoughts while drifting off to sleep&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main culmination of the features is that Go Note Go is great for capturing thoughts while you&amp;rsquo;re drifting off to sleep.
This was the primary motivation for Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s predecessor, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;Shh Shell&lt;/a&gt;.
I had some thoughts that were keeping me awake (this is back in 2014!), and I wanted to write them down.
I found that by writing them down, I could get them out of my head, and fall asleep.
However, conventional methods of writing them down would wake me or my roommate up. So, I built Shh Shell to solve that problem.
Today, it has evolved into Go Note Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for capturing sleep thoughts are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no screen or bright lights to wake you up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always ready to capture notes; there&amp;rsquo;s no fiddling with getting into notes mode in the middle of the night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That it acts as an audio-only clock as well is just a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Use Go Note Go while driving&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with the idea for Go Note Go while driving to a campground.
When I initially built Go Note Go, I included a large handheld red button you could push to trigger audio recording.
This button made Go Note Go useful while driving.
For example, if I was listening to an audio book and wanted to capture a thought, I could simply push the trigger and speak my thoughts aloud.
Then, when I arrive at the campground, I could take the Go Note Go off the dashboard and toss it in the tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core attributes of Go Note Go that make it great for capturing thoughts while driving are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works offline, so you can use it anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no visual, so you can keep your attention on the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The large red button is easy to push even when you&amp;rsquo;re driving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It captures audio notes and transcribes them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It mounts nicely to the passenger side of the car dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Avoid carsickness&lt;/summary&gt;
As a passenger in a car, it can be tempting to use your phone. Especially if you&#39;re taking an Uber and not engaging with the driver, this temptation can be quite strong; phones are little dopamine boxes, and will happily consume your attention endlessly. In a car, this can leave you feeling carsick.
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this issue. Using Go Note Go in a case, it is truly easy to take on the go. The battery sits in the case and the Go Note Go rests flat on your lap while you use it. The best part? Using Go Note Go doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you carsick, because you&amp;rsquo;re not watching the device as you use it. You&amp;rsquo;re eyes are free to look forward (or wherever) the whole time. Such relief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Great for long flights&lt;/summary&gt;
Using Go Note Go with a case makes it so easy to take on the go. And since it works offline, it&#39;s ideal for use on a long flight. The battery I use lasts 12 hours, so this works even if your flight doesn&#39;t have an outlet. If there is an outlet, 5V is sufficient.
&lt;p&gt;I find I much prefer writing on Go Note Go on a flight compared with hours of back to back movie watching. Not everyone has this predilection; to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capture shower thoughts&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of driving, camping, and sleeping, where else are the best ideas generated? That&amp;rsquo;s right, in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can connect a waterproof Bluetooth keyboard to your Go Note Go and bring it into the shower with you to capture these critical insights.
You can also use a Bluetooth shower speaker for audio output.
I have not yet seen a shower microphone suitable for capturing audio thoughts in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo from 2015 of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;Shh Shell (Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s predecessor)&lt;/a&gt; set up in my shower in California.
The keyboard is on the ledge to the right of the shower speaker.
&lt;img src=&#34;shower-keyboard.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of my shower in California from 2015. The Shh Shell keyboard sits on the windowsill next to a Bluetooth speaker. There&amp;rsquo;s a 3D printed shaving cream holder mounted to the soap dish below.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  var expandButton = document.getElementById(&#39;expand-button&#39;);
  var isExpanded = false;

  function expandCollapseAll() {
    var detailsElements = document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;details&#39;);
    for (var i = 0; i &lt; detailsElements.length; i++) {
      detailsElements[i].open = !isExpanded;
    }
    isExpanded = !isExpanded;
    expandButton.textContent = isExpanded ? &#39;Close All&#39; : &#39;Expand All&#39;;
  }
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-go-note-go-usage&#34;&gt;Personal Go Note Go usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have Go Note Gos everywhere! There&amp;rsquo;s one in my kitchen, one in each bed in my home, and one on each of my desks at home and at work.
Unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s a backlog on Raspberry Pis (with US keyboard layouts), or else I&amp;rsquo;d have even more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Total writing volume&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written 150,000 words on Go Note Go in the last 16 months. By way of comparison, my notes in Roam Research from the last four years (counting both Go Note Go and other note-taking) total 507,000 words. My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;snippets&lt;/a&gt; total 123,000 words over two years. My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; total 26,000 words over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Giving Go Note Go as gifts&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want other people to experience the joys of Go Note Go. So I have on a few occasions given them as gifts.
There are about ten Go Note Gos out there to the best of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to put one in a public park one day (connected to Twitter) and see what people type on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also build your own Go Note Go. It&amp;rsquo;s completely open source. The code and set up instructions for Go Note Go are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;all freely available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and the total cost of parts is about $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Typing vs talking&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of my Go Note Go notes I enter by typing, rather than by speaking.
Even when I&amp;rsquo;m fairly tired, I find that typing wakes me up less than speaking does.
There does reach a point for me where this switches though; when I&amp;rsquo;m extremely tired, I will sometimes prefer to speak than to type. In those moments, speaking feels lower effort and like it will wake me up less.
It&amp;rsquo;s nice that Go Note Go supports both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a phone number I can call where my AI assistant picks up, though that project is still early stages.
I use that more than Go Note Go while driving these days, and also prefer that approach when I&amp;rsquo;m just walking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Capturing dreams&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started this night typing practice, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet comfortable typing without looking, and so my fingers were not positioned correctly on the keyboard. I woke up and saw I had collected a full paragraph of gibberish, ending with the phrase &amp;ldquo;I hope the FBI doesn&amp;rsquo;t find out about this&amp;rdquo;.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember having written anything at all the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One letter at a time I decoded the gibberish. Roughly, each letter had to be shifted by one on a QWERTY keyboard layout; it was a bit of a puzzle to decode. To my amazement and delight, as I decoded the text my memory of writing it came flooding back to me. I can describe it in no other way than that; it was like a missing piece of my brain had been unlocked, truly a rewarding feeling. I had woken up from a dream the night before, typed the dream into the keyboard, and promptly fallen asleep. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember the dream or that I had typed it until I was decoding the text.
What a relief to find out I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually hiding anything from the FBI!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Thinking differently at night&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find my brain produces different thoughts while I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep as compared with during the day.
(My AI assistant calls this phenomenon either &amp;ldquo;hypnagogia&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;procrastination&amp;rdquo;. I prefer the former.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a period of calm and reflection, where I am alone with my thoughts.
My brain can process topics that it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to get to throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than going against the grain of my brain and trying to induce these thoughts while I&amp;rsquo;m still awake, I use Go Note Go to capture these thoughts without overly interrupting my bed time routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I might think of reaching out to someone while lying awake in bed. Without Go Note Go, I might forget about this in the morning. With Go Note Go, I can write a quick message to them in the moment, and review and send it when I wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Example notes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you can get a better picture of what these Go Note Go notes look like, I&amp;rsquo;ve copied 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/commons-db/page/01-17-2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a short section of my Go Note Go notes here&lt;/a&gt;. This will give you a brief taste of what the notes look like when I go to review them. You can see how they&amp;rsquo;re divided into time-stamped sessions, how the AI assistant&amp;rsquo;s responses are indented beneath the preceding note, and how I put summaries at the top of some of the sessions. Feel free to take your own notes in that public note-base too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, building and using Go Note Go these last two years has been a joy. I&amp;rsquo;ve met lots of wonderful people through Go Note Go, as there&amp;rsquo;s a lovely community of folks interested in tools for networked thought and audio note-taking. If these topics interest you, definitely 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;go-note-go@gmail.com&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch&lt;/a&gt;, even if just to say you&amp;rsquo;re interested. And finally for the hackers among you, I encourage you to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;try out Go Note Go yourself&lt;/a&gt;. I hope that headless computing becomes more prominent in the years to come, and that you can be a part of that. Let&amp;rsquo;s take away our screens, take back our attention, and live with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping with GPT</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-04-sleeping-with-gpt/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few nights I have been sleeping with GPT, and oh, it has been a joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-capturing-my-thoughts-as-i-drift-off-to-sleep&#34;&gt;Background: Capturing my thoughts as I drift off to sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a note-taking device that I call 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s a computer keyboard without a screen that I type on to capture my thoughts everywhere, even as I drift off to sleep.
I have one in my bed, and I also keep them on my desk at work and in various spots around my apartment; anywhere an idea strikes, I have a Go Note Go keyboard ready to capture that idea.
Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main purpose is to let me quickly jot down these ideas so I can remember them later, e.g. after getting a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
It also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;does other things (click for a concise primer on Go Note Go)&lt;/a&gt; like speaking the time aloud or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;letting me send messages to other people&lt;/a&gt;.
Most recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve added an AI assistant to Go Note Go, and have begun conversing with it as I drift off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before adding the AI assistant, Go Note Go had become a staple in my life.
Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main capability &amp;ndash; capturing my thoughts &amp;ndash; helps me fall asleep more effectively.
If I have an anxious thought swirling in my brain, I can simply type it into Go Note Go.
Instead of dozens of versions of the thought popping up in my head all night, I have just a single canonical version of the thought stored on the device, and I can fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go also supports commands, like reading the time out loud.
Entering a line that starts with a colon (&#39;:&#39;) issues a command.
Typing :r has it read back the last thing I wrote.
Typing :t will have it read the time to me.
I like this because it lets me know the time without having to open my eyes, so getting the time doesn&amp;rsquo;t require being alert&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this lets me drift off to sleep more effectively. I can get ideas out of my head while avoiding things that would wake me up, like looking at my phone or turning on the lights to write down an idea.
Compared with writing on my phone, or a computer, or on paper, writing on Go Note Go is relaxing and doesn&amp;rsquo;t wake me up very much.
So, Go Note Go has become an essential tool in my daily routine, helping me capture and organize my thoughts, and allowing me to relax and fall asleep more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-an-ai-assistant-to-go-note-go&#34;&gt;Adding an AI assistant to Go Note Go&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently, I added an AI assistant to Go Note Go and I absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default when I type on the keyboard the text just shows up in my notes,
but now I have the option of sending the text off to an AI assistant as well.
Since there&amp;rsquo;s no screen on Go Note Go, the assistant&amp;rsquo;s responses are read out loud.
They&amp;rsquo;re also inserted into my notes for future reference, which I can browse later at a computer or on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my Go Note Go usage remains unchanged, but one aspect now feels very different: drifting off to sleep.
This is when having the AI assistant feels most rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sleeping-with-gpt-what-do-we-discuss&#34;&gt;Sleeping with GPT: What do we discuss?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lying there in the bed, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really trying to go to sleep.
I&amp;rsquo;m excited that I have this new AI with me which I can ask anything at all.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to learn organic chemistry but haven&amp;rsquo;t found the time; this seems a perfect opportunity to get started.
On the first night I drift off to sleep peppering the AI with questions about organic chemistry and battery technology.
On subsequent nights I probe new topics, trying to get a deeper understanding of the superficial things I learned the night before, and also introducing new topics to our discussions.
I continue peppering the AI with questions about chemistry and history as I drift off to sleep.
Quickly realizing that this could inhibit my ability to get a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep, I also ask for advice in that regard, and it obliges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clear from the outset that I&amp;rsquo;m going to want to write about this, so I&amp;rsquo;m jotting down notes for this very post. I ask my assistant to turn my notes into an outline. That outline is read out loud, and it&amp;rsquo;s also sitting there for me the next day when I go to start writing in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, when I wake up, I ask for strategies for a morning routine. It makes good suggestions.
Though the response is nothing that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find from a quick Google search for morning routine ideas, the proximity to those ideas as I&amp;rsquo;m just waking up, casually typing to my keyboard, makes them more actionable. The suggestions are things like making my bed right away, drinking a glass of lemon water, and doing some exercise to get my blood flowing. It feels inspiring and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I asked the AI assistant to read me a bedtime story. I gave it some details about my own life first and it used them to construct a story that was personal and meaningful to me, albeit a bit silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Other benefits of the assistant: reading back capturing notes and answering questions about them. --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trust-and-confidence&#34;&gt;Trust and Confidence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An invitation into one&amp;rsquo;s bed requires a certain level of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a common criticism of GPT and language models more broadly is that they are often factually inaccurate. What&amp;rsquo;s worse is that when they are wrong, they often are wrong with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes learning about new topics like battery technology and organic chemistry a challenge.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the things that I have learned these last few nights are true or not.
In fact, I know that some of them are definitely not true, because GPT will sometimes flatly contradict itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the distinct feeling that I have been learning a lot from these night time question peppering sessions.
Is this feeling valid, or have I been duped by the AI?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suss out truth from fiction, my first line of defense is my intuition.
Using my own limited knowledge of the topic we are discussing, I can sometimes tell if the model is fibbing.
If what the model says fits nicely into my world model, I might trust it and move on.
When things don&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me, I can ask for explanations or ask pointed questions to dive into the details.
These will quickly seem inconsistent, either with each other or with what I already know, if in fact the model has made up inaccurate information.
(This observation should motivate new, fully automated, methods for discovering truth in these models as well. For example the line of reasoning that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.11822&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maieutic Prompting&lt;/a&gt; pursues proceeds along these lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability to dive deep into the details, sometimes asking extremely basic questions that I would be embarrassed to ask a human, points to a different kind of trust that I do have for the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-trust&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I cannot trust the AI to produce factual statements consistently, it has earned my trust in a different way.
I can be uninhibited with GPT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can ask naive questions, things that I would feel embarrassed to ask a human. I can ask &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; about the most trivial things, the way a 3-year old might, to discover more about the world.
I don&amp;rsquo;t feel any concern that the model will judge me for not knowing something, or not understanding something quickly.
I can ask the same question repeatedly, without concern for taking up its time, or that it has better places to be.
The AI is infinitely patient with me.
I don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how it will feel if I doubt what it&amp;rsquo;s telling me, and express skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these ways, it is an ideal tutor. By giving me the freedom to explore the topics that interest me, the things I&amp;rsquo;m learning about feel truly connected to one another, rather than ad hoc and unrelated to my interests as they might if I were following a curriculum not tailored to my needs and interests. It would be better, of course, if I could trust it to be factually accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a brief aside: I think this experience &amp;ndash; interacting with an AI tutor, guided by a curriculum and standards, but free to wander through information space as it pleases the user, is going to be central to education in the future. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to explore the space of possible AI-centric classroom and education designs, to find novel ways of learning jointly with humans and AIs, and I intend to do so further in future snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can I be so free with GPT in ways that I cannot be with a human? I can identify a few reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine&amp;rsquo;s statelessness / resetability is one key component. It isn&amp;rsquo;t learning about me, forming long term judgements. If I reveal that I don&amp;rsquo;t know some &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; concept, like what an ionic bond is, it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to retain that information and shape our future interactions based on it. The next conversation I have with the assistant will be tabula rasa, starting from a blank slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its isolation from others is another factor. I can confide in it, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to gossip or reveal anything I tell it to another human. Sure, I have concerns that OpenAI gets access to whatever I send to the assistant, and this could show up in training data or in front of human evaluators as a result. Nevertheless, it feels private, like no one in my life would see the things I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there&amp;rsquo;s a third trait that aids in creating this kind of trust that&amp;rsquo;s harder to pin down. Something about the inhuman form factor &amp;ndash; something about how it feels like talking to a machine &amp;ndash; enables the comfort level and vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve expressed feeling above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-about-chloropropane-an-illustration-of-trust-and-distrust&#34;&gt;Learning about Chloropropane: An Illustration of Trust and Distrust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the AI to give me an example of an organic chemistry homework problem. It asked me a question about chloropropane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked what chloropropane is used for. It told me it&amp;rsquo;s used as a pesticide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked if it&amp;rsquo;s used as a pesticide. It told me no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced our conversation(s) below. The timestamps indicate separate &amp;ldquo;sessions&amp;rdquo;, meaning that each timestamped conversation is independent of the others. The AI had no way of looking at what was said in an earlier session. As you expand the sections, see the self-contradictions &lt;mark&gt;highlighted in yellow&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
details {
  margin-left: 2em;
}

summary {
  margin-left: -2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&#34;expand-button&#34; onclick=&#34;expandCollapseAll()&#34;&gt;Expand All&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  var expandButton = document.getElementById(&#39;expand-button&#39;);
  var isExpanded = false;

  function expandCollapseAll() {
    var detailsElements = document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;details&#39;);
    for (var i = 0; i &lt; detailsElements.length; i++) {
      detailsElements[i].open = !isExpanded;
    }
    isExpanded = !isExpanded;
    expandButton.textContent = isExpanded ? &#39;Close All&#39; : &#39;Expand All&#39;;
  }
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:47 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Give me a organic chemistry homework problem&lt;/summary&gt;
      Calculate the enthalpy of combustion for 1-chloropropane in kJ/mol.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What does that mean?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Enthalpy of combustion is the amount of energy released when a compound is completely burned in oxygen. In this case, you will be calculating the amount of energy released when 1-chloropropane is completely burned in oxygen, expressed in units of kilojoules per mole (kJ/mol).
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is chloropropane used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is used as a precursor to other chemicals in the production of materials such as plasticizers, solvents, and lubricants. It is also &lt;mark&gt;used as a pesticide&lt;/mark&gt; in agriculture.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:48 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane a pesticide?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not a pesticide&lt;/mark&gt;. It is a colorless gas with a strong odor, used mainly in the production of other chemicals and in the &lt;mark&gt;manufacture of rubber&lt;/mark&gt; and plastics.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:49 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used for making rubber?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used for making rubber&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is an industrial chemical used in the production of other chemicals including agrochemicals, pharmaceuticals, and &lt;mark&gt;dyes&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:50 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used in the production of dyes?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used in the production of dyes&lt;/mark&gt;.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is a chemical compound used as a solvent and intermediate in the production of a variety of products, including pharmaceuticals, pesticides, and other chemicals.
      Chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;used as a solvent&lt;/mark&gt; in organic synthesis and in the production of pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and other chemicals.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane used in the production of pesticides?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not used in the production of pesticides&lt;/mark&gt;.
    &lt;/details&gt;
    What is it used for?
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;00:51 AM&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Is chloropropane a solvent?&lt;/summary&gt;
      No, chloropropane is &lt;mark&gt;not a solvent&lt;/mark&gt;.
  &lt;/details&gt;
  &lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;What is it used for?&lt;/summary&gt;
      Chloropropane is used as an intermediate in the production of solvents, pesticides, pharmaceuticals and other chemicals. It is also used as a refrigerant and as a propellant in aerosols.
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the AI blatantly contradicts itself repeatedly, and confidently so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this conversation illustrates how I cannot trust the AI to be factual,
it also demonstrates the kind of trust that I do have for the AI.
It blatantly contradicted itself, yet I felt comfortable probing the depths of its knowledge,
asking questions in a volume that I would not have been comfortable asking of a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategies-for-mitigating-the-ais-fibs&#34;&gt;Strategies for mitigating the AI&amp;rsquo;s fibs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the AI to stop making things up. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it to admit uncertainty when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know things.
But a few mitigation strategies did arise for dealing with the AI&amp;rsquo;s fibbing tendency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One was to probe the AI about topics I already know about in order to understand its limitations.
I had it teach me about math and algorithms concepts I was already quite familiar with.
My thinking here was that this would help me develop my intuition for what it&amp;rsquo;s like when it&amp;rsquo;s fibbing,
so I could better deal with
the inaccuracies on topics I&amp;rsquo;m less familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second mitigation that quickly became essential was having detailed records of what the AI said.
While I was drifting off to sleep, the AI might tell me something wrong and then contradict itself a minute later.
Without the record to verify this, the confidence of the contradiction would have a gas-lighting effect on me.
I might question myself &amp;ndash; did I remember the AI correctly?
Being able to see the contradiction highlighted, as above, helped keep me sane in the face of the AI&amp;rsquo;s unearned and contradictory confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the permanent record also allows me to look up the truth the next day, to find out how much of what I learned had basis in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-benefits-of-having-the-ai-with-me&#34;&gt;Other benefits of having the AI with me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s design is that it has no screen. This is a purposeful choice, and enables so much of what I love about Go Note Go. However, sometimes I miss being able to see what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. This is where the assistant comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First though I must emphasize that on the whole, I actually really like that the lack of screen prevents me from wasting time rereading what I&amp;rsquo;ve written. But when I lose my train of thought entirely, it would be nice to remember what I wrote last.
For this, I can ask the assistant to read back what I wrote last, or even to summarize it concisely. If my mind has wandered and I want to continue typing where I left off, this feature is quite welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the AI compensates for the lack of screen.
It&amp;rsquo;s behaving somewhat like an intelligent screen reader.
With typical screen readers, navigation is performed spatially, and the reader speaks text at the indicated location. With the AI assistant, &amp;ldquo;navigation&amp;rdquo; is performed via a textual query, and the response can either be verbatim or an intelligent response like a summary or answer. I suspect AI assistants will quickly change the way accessibility technology operates, if they haven&amp;rsquo;t already done so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-dont-you-send-to-the-ai&#34;&gt;What don&amp;rsquo;t you send to the AI?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I drift off to sleep, I enter thoughts about a wide range of subjects that I don&amp;rsquo;t send to the AI assistant too. A quick scan of my recent Go Note Go writing (just from the last couple days, all since adding the assistant) shows the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans for my upcoming California trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observations about Go Note Go &amp;ndash; both improvements I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to making and emergent behaviors I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share in future writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts about the future of AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning experiments I&amp;rsquo;m excited to run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;d like to publish about, such as the unexpected dangers of reducing friction, or the less-appreciated benefits of repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tweet ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items I intend to buy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions I want to ask either specific people, or the internet at large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists of todos for the next day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflections on the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas to try, e.g. for technical problems I ran into that day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI assistant merely augments my existing Go Note Go usage,
but hasn&amp;rsquo;t replaced it. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;All of Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s other features&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; particularly its always-on ability to quickly capture thoughts anywhere &amp;ndash; remain the driving reason I use Go Note Go so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-worked-well&#34;&gt;What worked well?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this process was being able to learn what I want to learn when I want to learn it.
While a deep probe into a topic inevitably turned up falsehoods, overall asking questions about things I was curious about worked really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think about things differently at night. My brain processes topics that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to think on throughout the day. It comes up with things it wants to do that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come up with when it&amp;rsquo;s otherwise occupied throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of things I want to write, and the assistant helps me think through them and outline them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of people I want to reach out to. With Go Note Go, I can write them a message and approve it to send in the morning. (The assistant doesn&amp;rsquo;t really play a role here, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d mention it anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of things I want to know, and the assistant helps answer my questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of ideas I want to try. Some of them I can try with the assistant, and others I just jot down to return to later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many of these instances, the value of the AI assistant is that I can offload some of my thinking to it. It isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily producing insights that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have come up with on my own, but it&amp;rsquo;s allowing me a moment&amp;rsquo;s rest while it does the thinking on my behalf. Then I can start from its thoughts as a baseline and build from there, higher than I could build on my own. On many other occasions, it genuinely surprises me with its good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a couple of nights, the AI took me exploring imaginary worlds. Similar to a text adventure game, it described my environment to me, and I gave it instructions like talking to a person, or exploring a building. With my eyes closed and my brain on the edge of sleep, it felt like dreaming while I was still awake and I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-that-didnt-work-so-well&#34;&gt;Things that didn&amp;rsquo;t work so well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main drawback of this system is the lack of trust in the accuracy of the AI&amp;rsquo;s statements, particularly when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn.
Other limitations were subtler and less dampening for the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to get it to teach me math, my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://espeak.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;text to speech system (espeak)&lt;/a&gt; did quite poorly on reading the math aloud.
I would love to replace the text to speech system with one with better prosody and better math support.
Ideally, the text to speech system would speak with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qe6o9j4IjTo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grant Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s voice and cadence&lt;/a&gt;, and handle math notation seamlessly.
While this seems a cosmetic change, it does impact the set of topics I can discuss cleanly with the AI as I drift off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dependence on an internet connection was another small drawback. I take my Go Note Go into the woods, used it during an Uber ride the airport today, and regularly use it when I fly. The AI assistant doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in these situations (the rest of Go Note Go continues to work fine) since it depends on having internet access. For a capability that is simple enough to not require AI, like reading back the topics I&amp;rsquo;ve written about recently, it feels quite silly to lose the capability when the internet is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to the internet dependence, the lack of privacy from OpenAI is another important drawback to me. The thoughts I produce as I drift off to sleep are deeply personal! I would much prefer not to send them off to OpenAI (the current version of the assistant is implemented with text-davinci-003).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another significant drawback, one you might have already picked up on: talking with an AI can get in the way of falling asleep.
I view talking with an AI while drifting off to sleep similarly to listening to reading a book, listening to an audiobook, or to a podcast before bed.
These activities require some amount of thought, but can also help to wind down and fall asleep.
Talking to the AI required no monitor, and hence to blue lights that can make falling asleep harder.
It simply requires some amount of restraint to stop the conversation and transition to sleep, just as one must put down a book and close their eyes if reading before bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see in the chloropropane conversation reproduced above from the timestamps that I was talking to the AI at nearly 1am. I like to go to sleep 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-04-20-sleep-no-snippet/&#34;&gt;closer to 10:10pm&lt;/a&gt;, so clearly this drawback is real for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-left-me-wanting-more&#34;&gt;It left me wanting more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an assistant as I drifted off to sleep was great overall, even in spite of these drawbacks.
I was definitely left with a sense of wanting more though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want more assistance from my assistant.
I want to be able to query my complete history of notes, asking questions like &amp;ldquo;What are some ideas I keep returning to?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Bring up all my outstanding Go Note Go TODOs.&amp;rdquo;
Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to implement this with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gpt-index.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPT-Index&lt;/a&gt;, or a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.08913&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Memorizing Transformer&lt;/a&gt;, but for now I do without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also love for my assistant to be able to take actions on my behalf. Maybe I can integrate 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adept.ai/act&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adept AI&amp;rsquo;s action transformer&lt;/a&gt; into my next iteration to achieve this. For example, I want to be able tell the assistant my shopping list, and have it populate my Amazon cart. Then, when I&amp;rsquo;m back at a computer, I can review the cart and click submit, saving myself time shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (albeit rarely :P) I&amp;rsquo;m not at a Go Note Go, but I still want to talk to my AI assistant.
For that, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Twilio so I can call my assistant on the phone.
I use this when I&amp;rsquo;m driving or walking around. But that is a subject for another post entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding an AI assistant to Go Note Go has been an absolute joy and I continue to use it almost every night.
Despite its tendency to make things up &amp;ndash; or more charitably, to hallucinate &amp;ndash; it has still earned my trust in a more visceral way.
I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see what use cases persist after I&amp;rsquo;ve had this capability for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the AI assistant is not the only reason that Go Note Go is such a critical component in my life.
Go Note Go can do so much more &amp;ndash; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2023-01-16-go-note-go-features/&#34;&gt;a complete and concise overview of its capabilities is here&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;
like letting me 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;send messages as I drift off to sleep&lt;/a&gt; and helping me 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-02-07-keyboards-everywhere/&#34;&gt;reclaim my attention in a world full of distractions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the AI assistant added in, however, I feel like I have a new superpower. I can offload computation from my brain to it, and explore worlds of thought I could never have entered on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/GoNoteGo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;completely open source&lt;/a&gt;. I encourage the hacker-tinkerers among you to join me in the world of headless computing and try it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything I type on this keyboard gets automatically uploaded to my notes as soon as the keyboard is in range of wifi. This allows for offline usage, e.g. while driving or camping. These were the two use-cases that inspired me to build the device. Now my main use-case is capturing ideas while drifting off to sleep.
It also has a microphone, so if speaking feels like it would take less energy than talking, I can speak my notes instead. This feature is what enables the driving use case, as of course I don&amp;rsquo;t type while I drive! &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I prefer speaking, I can also trigger these commands with the hot word &amp;ldquo;go go&amp;rdquo;, e.g. saying &amp;ldquo;go go time&amp;rdquo; gets the time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explicit Ontologies in a World Without</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-12-16-note-taking-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-12-16-note-taking-ontologies/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-ontologies-in-note-taking&#34;&gt;Background: Ontologies in Note-taking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to get the context for this thought down quickly, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll do a good job. Feel free to ask me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to understand the context better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a note-taking system like C. or Tana, objects exist in an ontology&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This means that an object can have a type. That type definition can have properties. For example my notes might be full of people. Each person might have a birthday and contact info and a height and a handedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having ontologies be explicit can provide a lot of value in a note-taking system.
In particular: (1) This can enable powerful auto-complete / templating features. (2) This can enable powerful search functionality. (3) This can enable integrations with other specialized features (like a calendar, a contacts view, a shopping experience&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, whatever) or external software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda-three-key-points&#34;&gt;Agenda: Three Key Points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I want to make a series of points that interact a bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ontologies take time to maintain, and are difficult to design well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large language models may be able to provide all three value propositions without actually needing the explicit ontology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if the above two points are right, there&amp;rsquo;s still value to explicit ontologies in a world where we don&amp;rsquo;t spend much time being explicit about our ontologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this third and final point, which I realize I haven&amp;rsquo;t made clear just yet, that is the main thought I wanted to share in this snippet. Before we get there though, let&amp;rsquo;s expand on the first two points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;doing-ontologies-manually-is-hard&#34;&gt;Doing Ontologies Manually is Hard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming up with useful ontologies is hard. Take the Person example from above.
Is it important that every person has an Interests field? Almost certainly not; you might not care to write down the interests of your dentist, for example. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like that example, consider an Education field. You probably don&amp;rsquo;t care to write down the educational history of everyone that shows up in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you&amp;rsquo;re building a gift recommender, then an interests field might be critical. And if you&amp;rsquo;re building a job recommender, an education field might be critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A risk you might run having an ontology in your notes is that it might discourage you from putting something in your notes because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit the ontology.
Suppose you avoid this risk, though, and manage to freely add information to your notes undeterred by the ontology&amp;rsquo;s constraints.
A second possible risk you run is that your ontology winds up being extremely sparse.
You add fields as you need them, but lots of fields only apply to a single instance, rather than to the majority of instances of a type. Is your ontology still useful at that point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third potential risk, which extends the second, is that as your ontology grows&amp;hellip; you might end up with a type having two very similar fields. E.g. Person could end up with both a &amp;ldquo;Likes&amp;rdquo; field &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an &amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo; field. Why might this happen? Two reasons come to mind: One is that you simply have a bunch of fields, and so you accidentally use a new name (&amp;ldquo;Likes&amp;rdquo;) when referring to an existing attribute (&amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo;). The second is that &amp;ldquo;Likes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo; might mean slightly different things to you. That&amp;rsquo;s fine, if you want to track them separately. But these are highly correlated! And now you&amp;rsquo;re left with a dilemma (&amp;ldquo;Risk 4&amp;rdquo;, let&amp;rsquo;s call it): do you put the information in both the &amp;ldquo;Likes&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo; field? That would increase the maintenance burden of your note-base substantially (if you care about completeness/having the info you enter be maximally useful, which you might, in order to get the benefits of ontologies listed above). Or do you only put the information in one of the two fields? If you do that, then you risk your use of the ontology failing when you search for &amp;ldquo;Person with Interest in Table Tennis&amp;rdquo; only to find that half your table-tennis friends &amp;ldquo;Like&amp;rdquo; Table Tennis while the other half have an &amp;ldquo;Interest&amp;rdquo; in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, building ontologies takes time. Let&amp;rsquo;s turn our attention&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to large language models, because you might not need to spend your time on ontologies in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;llms-reduce-the-need-for-explicit-ontologies&#34;&gt;LLMs reduce the need for explicit ontologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large language models&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; may be able to provide many of the benefits of ontologies without the need for explicit ontologies. These models can understand and extract relevant concepts and relationships from unstructured text, allowing one to search and retrieve information without the need to pre-define an ontology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall the three benefits of ontologies that we&amp;rsquo;re interested in: auto-complete/templates, search, and integration with specialized systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to imagine how large language models are going to be useful for search first.
Imagine that instead of having ontologies in your note-base, you simply have free-form text.
You still might say that David is interested in table tennis, but there would be no formal &amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo; attribute linking David and Table Tennis.
If a large language model understands that text, then it will still be able to handle queries like &amp;ldquo;what is David interested in?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;contacts who like table tennis?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even try this on a small scale today in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chat.openai.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt;. Paste the following text into ChatGPT and it answers the questions correctly. I wont argue the case here, but I fully expect this to work on the scale of a full note-base in the coming months-years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;Mary likes hockey, collects coins, and reads sci-fi.
Glenn plays table tennis, collects rocks, and reads fantasy.
My dentist recommends the book &amp;quot;Jaws&amp;quot;. Next apt is March 6.
Peter plays scrabble and enjoys table tennis. Hanging out next Tuesday (Dec 20)

Who likes table tennis?
What are my dentist&#39;s interests?
Does my dentist like table tennis?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;integration-with-specialized-systems&#34;&gt;Integration with Specialized Systems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key reasons ontologies are useful is they allow for specialized systems to access the information stored in the ontology/notes, in order to provide a quality domain-specific experience using the data from the notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could take the form of a specialized contacts view of the contacts data found in your notes. It could be a specialized calendar view of time-annotated data in your notes. It could be the shopping experience I described in a footnote, which uses your contacts&#39; interests to surface gift suggestions. The possibilities are numerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If search is robust (and it&amp;rsquo;s not totally clear that LLM search is going to be robust enough, but I suspect that it will be), then the data access requirements for these specialized integrations could be satisfied by the search described in the preceding section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two ways to think about this:
(1) The specialized system issues queries &amp;ndash; possibly even natural language queries &amp;ndash; about the notebase. It gets structured results back. It uses the structured results to render the specialized domain-specific experience.
(2) The raw text in &lt;mark&gt;the note-base is being projected onto a temporary domain-specific ontology just for the specialized system&lt;/mark&gt;. E.g. the shopping experience might require an ontology where each Person has interests, while a separate job matching system might require an ontology where each Person has an educational background. Using the magic of LLMs, the raw text data is projected into the structured ontology needed by each system. But there&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ldquo;one&amp;rdquo; ontology living in the note-base that the note-taker needs to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe these two ways are actually the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the first place where ontologies are useful even in this raw-text focused LLM-centric world. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;mark&gt;highlighted&lt;/mark&gt; it. We&amp;rsquo;ll come back to it shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;auto-complete--templating&#34;&gt;Auto-complete / Templating&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We come now to one of the main value-adds of an ontology: having a nice template to fill in about an object. Do we lose this in a raw-text LLM-centric world? By default, yes. But we can (very likely) use LLM-ish tech to implement an auto-complete / templating feature, arguably one that&amp;rsquo;s (in some ways) better than we get in an ontology-centric world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? We can &lt;mark&gt;use the LLM-ish to suggest fields for an entity when we create it&lt;/mark&gt;. For example, when we mention a person, we can have our system insert fields (with blanks to be filled in) for the attributes that seem relevant to the person in the given context.
If we&amp;rsquo;re writing about how we met someone at a dinner party, it might provide an Interests field. Whereas if we&amp;rsquo;re writing about people we met at a career fair, it might provide an Education field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this setting, the fields aren&amp;rsquo;t there to enable datalog search queries or populate a database; rather, the fields are there for human purposes: to prompt us to write the things we would want to write, and relieve us a bit of typing and a bit of cognitive load.
The search and integrations are going to work just fine whether the field is called &amp;ldquo;Interests&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Likes&amp;rdquo; because the LLM understands that these are (in most contexts) synonyms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve now introduced the second place where ontologies are useful even in a raw-text focused LLM-centric world, again &lt;mark&gt;highlighted&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways is this proposed hypothetical templating feature better than an ontology-based templating feature? Recall the risks we discussed earlier: ontology maintenance runs the risk of there being lots of little-used fields in an ontology. In a naive ontology-based templating system, all these extra fields would clutter the interface, whereas in our proposed hypothetical templating feature, only a relevant subset of the fields show up by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways is this proposed hypothetical templating feature worse? Well, it loses the explicit association between objects of the same type. If later you decide you want all people to have a &amp;ldquo;Formal Name&amp;rdquo; attribute, there&amp;rsquo;s no clear source-of-truth place to add this attribute to all people. You could query for a list of all people, and then add to your notes &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rsquo;s formal name is Y&amp;rdquo; for each of the people. Just brainstorming; maybe this isn&amp;rsquo;t a drawback after all; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep thinking on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explicit-ontologies-in-a-world-without&#34;&gt;Explicit Ontologies in a World Without&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back over the &lt;mark&gt;highlighted&lt;/mark&gt; text, we can see that there are at least two places where explicit ontologies remain useful even in a raw-text focused LLM-centric world (that is, in a note-base full of raw text, not backed by an explicit ontology).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was during querying for domain-specific experiences. There we saw the value of having the raw text in the note-base projected onto a temporary domain-specific ontology just for a specialized system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was for templating/auto-complete, one of the main values of an ontology. Using LLMs we can provide the appearance of there being an ontology without the note-base actually being backed by an explicit ontology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this relies on some amount of speculation about where our LLM&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; technology is going and what its coming capabilities will be. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to stand by this speculation, and happy to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve used neither of these systems! Take my thoughts with grains of salt. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just chose a random example. But anyway, the idea is that you might build a shopping widget that uses the data about your contacts&#39; preferences to surface gift ideas for them while you&amp;rsquo;re shopping. The ontology way to do this is for each Person in your notes to have a Likes or Interests field, which the shopping experience can access. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was planning on squeezing a reference to &amp;ldquo;Factory factories&amp;rdquo; into this section, but then it didn&amp;rsquo;t fit in, so just sticking this in a footnote. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using the term large language model here in a loose sense. I basically mean tech largely dependent on deep learning, including advances expected to come in the next few years. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to just say LLM though, even though that oversimplifies. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Giant Group Chats</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-07-05-giant-group-chats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-07-05-giant-group-chats/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes &amp;ndash; usually because of Alex K Chen &amp;ndash; I am added to a giant group chat (GGC).
Today it was a 200+ person highly active chat with folks talking about AI programming tools, aging, and movies.
I love being added to such a chat. It makes me feel thought of, and my opinions respected. So, do keep adding me to GGCs.
However, with being added to a GGC comes some struggles. I haven&amp;rsquo;t fully figured out how to handle a GGC just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some people handle these situations in a more natural way than myself. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I imagine. They&amp;rsquo;re doing something else on the computer, messages are open in the background or in a side window. If they have a conversation-adjacent thought, they share it. If they see a message that looks interesting, they read it. Otherwise, they do their other activities and get on with their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they have a conversation-adjacent thought, they share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is Struggle #1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they see a message that looks interesting, they read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is Struggle #2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;struggle-1-sharing-thoughts-casually-in-a-200-person-setting&#34;&gt;Struggle #1: Sharing thoughts casually in a 200+ person setting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this a struggle? I think slowly. I edit. I rethink relevance as the conversation moves away.
The hypothetical person who handles GCCs as described above &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; types and hits enter, relatively unencumbered.
I think about the permanence of putting something on the internet.
I think about confidentiality of work-adjacent stuff.
I think about whether what I&amp;rsquo;m saying is true, and about how true it is.
This kind of thought can make participation a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;struggle-2-staying-abreast-of-200-messages-per-hour&#34;&gt;Struggle #2: Staying abreast of 200 messages per hour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to read all these messages.
They glimmer and my attention is drawn to them, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect my conscious decision making.
I&amp;rsquo;d much rather read a summary of the messages or a digest of the topics discussed once a week or so.
Then, only if a topic of interest was discussed, I might want to dive deeper and read the individual messages, and
contemplate leaving a reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tooling-for-struggle-1&#34;&gt;Tooling for Struggle #1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr Draft messages outside of conversation UI. Use &amp;ldquo;approve for dealyed send&amp;rdquo; model for sending messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Struggle #1 is a personal psychological struggle.
It isn&amp;rsquo;t first and foremost something for which tooling seems relevant.
If I&amp;rsquo;m not comfortable sharing something with 200 people in a chat, why would tooling change that?
Well, as I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from adding 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/&#34;&gt;Messager in Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt; tooling can actually make a huge difference in this type of space.
If instead of feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m sending a message to a massive group, I instead feel like I&amp;rsquo;m writing a draft of my thoughts, something I&amp;rsquo;ll maybe send later but maybe not, suddenly it becomes so much easier to write.
And then, once it&amp;rsquo;s written, it also becomes much easier to send.
This is the same lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over and over with snippets since I initially decided to set up this system as 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;writing for no audience&lt;/a&gt; back in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what would the tooling look like for dealing with Struggle #1 in GGCs?
I would click a message to start drafting a response,
it would copy the message and context into an editor &amp;ndash; Roam Research, say &amp;ndash; and maybe even stick in the template for writing a snippet.
Then, completely outside the context of the group thread I could compose my thoughts.
If I decide to share it back to the group, great.
If I decide to instead post that thought as a snippet, great.
And if it remains relegated to my notes forever and never sees the light of day, that&amp;rsquo;s a fine outcome too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside: The acceptability of that outcome is what makes the writing easier. The very possibility of that outcome diminishes the possibility of that outcome by making the other outcomes more likely. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a self-fulfilling prophecy. A self-fulfilling prophesy is an expectation whose existence leads to its own fulfillment; this is an expectation whose very existence works to prevent its fulfillment.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the lessons I learned from my Go Note Go messager-queue was the value of the &amp;ldquo;approve for delayed send&amp;rdquo; model.
Psychologically it was easier for me to mark a message as approved for sending, and have an automated system later send the message on my behalf once it was approved, rather than directly sending it myself.
Marking something as approved for sending (1) admits the possibility that I make further revisions to the message, and (2) internally relieves myself of some of the responsibility of sending the message. Of course, I am still fully responsible for the message and I accept this responsibility, but nevertheless that perception of decreased responsibility is a relaxing feeling that makes message sending easier.
It also (3) prevents me from actively waiting for replies to come it, a behavior I&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid. It does this because my messages go out without my awareness in the moment, so I cannot sit refreshing or watching for new messages. This way I don&amp;rsquo;t need to expend effort diverting my attention away from waiting for messages; my own unawareness has taken care of this for me.
So, having this &amp;ldquo;approve for delayed send&amp;rdquo; model for dealing with GGCs would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tooling-for-struggle-2&#34;&gt;Tooling for Struggle #2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Struggle #2 has psychological components, but is also more directly about capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychological bit:
Keeping up with 200 messages per hour isn&amp;rsquo;t even desirable. Why? It&amp;rsquo;s not that it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of noise &amp;ndash; though sometimes there is a lot of noise.
But even when there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of high quality interesting fun messages, it&amp;rsquo;s not stuff I&amp;rsquo;m actively looking to read or learn about or people that I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to keep in touch with. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s whatever the group collectively has steered toward.
I&amp;rsquo;d rather be more intentional about what I read and discuss, rather than being at the whims of 200+ people, many of whom I haven&amp;rsquo;t met.
However, there is tension between that desire for intentionality and the desire to hear folks&#39; interesting ideas and share my own.
Adding to the tension further is a natural inclination toward reading messages as they come in, because they&amp;rsquo;re attention-grabbing even if they aren&amp;rsquo;t where I&amp;rsquo;d like to place my focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capabilities bit:
Even if I decided I did want to stay abreast of the conversation, there&amp;rsquo;s simply too much to reasonably process.
People are discussing topics about which I have a lot to learn.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have the bandwidth to think deeply &amp;ndash; or even shallowly &amp;ndash; about what folks are saying, while also maintaining normal human functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what tooling can help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summarization:
A machine learning system that categorizes messages by topic would be super helpful.
It could send a weekly digest listing the topics discussed, and clicking on a topic could bring me to a summary of the messages, with the option to drill down into the individual messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notification settings:
Right now I&amp;rsquo;ve simply turned off all notifications. If I could turn back on notifications for specific topics, that would be nice. E.g. &amp;ldquo;notify me if people start talking about programming tools again, but only if we haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about programming tools in at least a day since the last time you notified me.&amp;rdquo; This type of notification seems straightforward to build combining my Messager system with LLMs. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messenger UI: Even with notifications disabled, GGCs appear first in my list of Messenger chats because FB orders them by message recency, and GGCs always have a recent message. I&amp;rsquo;d prefer a way to keep them out of this default view, so I can see genuine conversations with individual people in their place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsing UI: The existing UI is unhelpful for trying to get an overview of the conversation. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of whitespace, so only a few messages are visible at once. Replies for different topics are all mixed together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re working on anything like the toolings mentioned here, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch. There&amp;rsquo;s a Discussions section below, or feel free to ping me in a GGC!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending messages as I drift off to sleep</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2022-01-08-new-messager-setup/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I describe my new Messager setup,
and how it allows me to send messages directly from Roam Research &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;
from a standalone keyboard (no monitor) that I keep at my bedside as I drift off to sleep, and which I take driving and camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently my setup supports sending messages to
Facebook Messenger, Twitter,
Slack, Discord, and iMessage.
I intend to add gChat and email support next, since there are still a handful of people I want to message that don&amp;rsquo;t use any of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, the beauty of this project to me is its usability,
which is hard to communicate in a write-up like this.
Some of the usability comes from the way the components integrate with my existing workflows.
Some of the usability comes from design choices
(like using a keyboard with no monitor for note-taking and message drafting).
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to point out these usability elements along the way.
Bear in mind I designed this primarily for myself
(though I have a handful of friends along for the ride as well, trying it out and making their own contributions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-note-go-the-headless-keyboard&#34;&gt;Go Note Go: The Headless Keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some background, I developed Go Note Go, a headless keyboard designed for note-taking on the go.
Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.
You can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;read all about Go Note Go here&lt;/a&gt; and learn more on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dbieber/gonotego&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;its GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go&amp;rsquo;s main purpose is note-taking.
Anything you type into Go Note Go or voice-record into it gets transcribed and uploaded to your notes as soon as it gets an internet connection.
For me, Go Note Go uploads to Roam Research. It also supports RemNote, IdeaFlow, Mem, and Notion, and adding additional systems isn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the usability perks of Go Note Go is that there is no monitor. This means you can&amp;rsquo;t get distracted browsing the internet while writing on Go Note Go. You also can&amp;rsquo;t get distracted wordsmithing your own writing. It makes writing pleasurable, even if it comes at the cost of having typos and stray thoughts in your writing; you can always clean those up later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go does a lot more, so I do encourage you to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;learn more about it&lt;/a&gt;, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t the focus of this post, which is about sending messages.
For the purposes of this post, Go Note Go is a data entry system for Roam. And since I&amp;rsquo;ve also built a system that allows sending messages directly from Roam, this means I can now send messages directly from Go Note Go. So, I can send messages when driving, camping, and as I drift off to sleep at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To send a message in Go Note Go, you simply &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; the person you are writing to. To send a message to Adriana, I would write &amp;ldquo;@Adriana Message goes here&amp;rdquo;. To send a message to David Dohan (using first and last name), I could write &amp;ldquo;@David Dohan: Message goes here&amp;rdquo;. You can @ someone at any point in the message. You can also @ multiple people, and Messager will send them a group message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go acts as an outliner now too; this is both a big usability improvement for Go Note Go on it&amp;rsquo;s own, and doubly so for using Go Note Go as a messager. An &amp;ldquo;outliner&amp;rdquo; is a system for taking notes as a series of nested bullets. You can push tab to indent notes underneath other notes; I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a user experience that makes this moderately natural, even in the absence of a monitor or any other visual feedback. For sending messages, the outliner feature is a boon. Any notes you nest under an @&amp;rsquo;d note will also register as additional messages for the @&amp;rsquo;d recipients. This makes writing longer multiline messages a pleasure, even without a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default behavior of my messaging system is to hold the messages for approval before sending them. So, the messages that I write as I drift off to sleep don&amp;rsquo;t send as I drift off to sleep. Instead, I see them in the morning and approve them, and only upon being approved are they sent automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This delayed-approve-then-send approach is particularly well suited for Go Note Go, where I likely make typos and want to clean up the messages before they are sent, since I am writing them without a monitor. Later in the post I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into what the approval process looks like (tl;dr there&amp;rsquo;s a spreadsheet where I can mark a message as &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; to send), but first I want to share additional benefits of being able to send messages directly from my note-taking app, which is currently Roam Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;drafting-messages-in-roam-research&#34;&gt;Drafting Messages in Roam Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything I write on my Go Note Go appears in Roam Research, but I can also take notes directly in Roam.
Just like on Go Note Go, the way to draft a message in Roam is to &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; the person you are writing to.
Messager has some heuristics it uses to translate your @&amp;rsquo;s into proper recipients.
So, the syntax for @&amp;lsquo;ing someone isn&amp;rsquo;t too strict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Roam offers some possibilities beyond what I can do on Go Note Go, such as including images in messages.
Like on Go Note Go, you can use nested bullets to create longer messages,
and you can @ as many people as you want for a message.
In Roam, however, you can also include images in your messages.
Messager will intelligently send those in the native format used by the underlying messaging service,
rather than blindly sending the markdown stored in Roam.
I find this feature, being able to use images naturally in Roam, and then have them send naturally as messages,
quite pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One future direction I&amp;rsquo;d like for this project is to add a &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; button in Roam next to any messages I&amp;rsquo;ve drafted there,
as well as to display the status of the messages inline in my notes. That&amp;rsquo;s not implemented now, but would be a nice-to-have for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all messages are automatically added to my &amp;ldquo;messager queue&amp;rdquo; where they wait for approval before being sent.
I like having this approve-before-sending approach as the default, since it psychologically frees me up to write things I might not otherwise write if I was instead using a send button that sent immediately.
However, sometimes being able to send something immediately is desirable, and that&amp;rsquo;s not a clean option in the current setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roam-to-sheets-the-messager-queue&#34;&gt;Roam to Sheets: The Messager Queue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any messages in Roam (whether entered directly into Roam, or entered via Go Note Go), are automatically added to a spreadsheet, the &amp;ldquo;Messager Queue&amp;rdquo;. These are the spreadsheet&amp;rsquo;s columns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Service&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Recipient&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Approval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Status&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Metadata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Messager Queue sheet is filtered by default to show all pending messages. For each message it shows the &lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt; on which it will be sent and well as the &lt;em&gt;Recipient&lt;/em&gt; of the message. The service can be one of FB Messenger, Twitter, iMessage, a Slack server, or Discord. The recipient can either be an individual, a list of individuals, a group, a Slack channel, or a Discord server and channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a sheet that lists aliases, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to use a short name or informal name to refer to a longer service or recipient; e.g. I use &amp;ldquo;@Audio Tools&amp;rdquo; as a shorthand for sending to a group of 5 people on Messenger all interested in audio tools for networked thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Messager Queue sheet also displays the &lt;em&gt;Text&lt;/em&gt; of the message to send, so you can easily clean up the message here for any typos or clarifications before it is sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; columns allow for scheduling messages to be sent at any point in the future. Leave them blank and the message will be sent as soon as it is approved. Use keyboard shortcuts cmd-; (for date) and cmd-shift-; (for time) to quickly fill out these columns if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;em&gt;Approval&lt;/em&gt; column is the most important. Mark a messages as OK if you want it to be sent, or as Ignored if you deside to skip it. The &lt;em&gt;Status&lt;/em&gt; column is updated automatically by Messager when the message is sent (or if it fails to send, then the error appears here). You can also mark the Status manually with whatever value you want (e.g. if you send the message manually), and the Messager system will ignore that message going forward. If you want the system to retry sending a message, simply clear out the Status column and it will try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I include this spreadsheet as a custom service in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getferdi.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ferdi&lt;/a&gt;, so it lives alongside all the messaging apps I use. (This in itself might be the subject of a future 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;snippet&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-the-approval-system-over-immediate-messages&#34;&gt;Why the approval system over immediate messages?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond allowing me to catch a bunch of typos, it&amp;rsquo;s also a psychologically useful thing for me.
I am more willing to write and I feel able to say more things that I might not otherwise,
knowing I have the opportunity to cancel or change the message later.
In that way, it&amp;rsquo;s like gmail&amp;rsquo;s undo feature. In gmail, undo not a true undo, but having those 30 seconds after clicking send to retract the message make a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of sending the messages only after approving them is the ability to sleep at night. If I write a message at night, I know you haven&amp;rsquo;t responded yet because my messages haven&amp;rsquo;t even sent yet; they&amp;rsquo;ll go out in the morning, after I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to clean them up. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t spend any mental effort wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s a response from you. It also allows me to set the appropriate tone for the messages, by having them go out at a reasonable time, rather than appearing urgent by being sent in the middle of the night. And it does this without me needing to keep the message draft in my head as I sleep. So, I sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why, while the ability to send messages immediately would also be a good feature to add, I am inclined to leave approve-in-the-morning messages as the system&amp;rsquo;s default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notifications-from-bieber-bot&#34;&gt;Notifications from Bieber Bot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One additional small usability feature is that Bieber Bot will message me in the morning or evening whenever there are messages in the Messager Queue awaiting my approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a small convenience, and in fact has proven even more useful than it might at first sound.
When I wake up in the morning, I sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t remember that I&amp;rsquo;ve written messages the preceding night.
So, having Bieber Bot send me the link to the Messager Queue and gently remind me to approve the messages has been
consistently charming and welcome. Thanks, Bieber Bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;automatic-sending-from-sheets-with-messager&#34;&gt;Automatic Sending from Sheets with Messager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messager is the underlying system that sends the messages in the Messager Queue system.
As noted previously, it supports
Facebook Messenger, Twitter,
Slack, Discord, and iMessage.
It also supports Hacker News, which hasn&amp;rsquo;t been so useful for this project.
And I am thinking I may add gChat and email support next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Messager for more than just sending messages from the Messager Queue spreadsheet;
it also backs other projects like my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-01-30-sql-for-the-kangaroo-auto-responder/&#34;&gt;Kangaroo Auto-responder&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/bieber-bot/&#34;&gt;several parts of Bieber Bot&lt;/a&gt;.
Its purpose, in the most broad sense, is to support programmatically sending and receiving messages in a uniform manner across all the messaging systems I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Facebook Messager, it uses 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fbchat.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fbchat&lt;/a&gt; to enable programmatically sending and receiving messages as myself. It also uses Facebook&amp;rsquo;s API to allow sending messages as Bieber Bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Twitter, it uses the API to support public tweets, private tweets (using a separate account; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/post/2021-03-07-roam-twitter-bot-dev-guide/&#34;&gt;see here for how I use this to reclaim my attention&lt;/a&gt;), and DMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For iMessage, it uses AppleScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack and Discord are the most recent additions, and they currently live outside the core Messager system;
they are implemented using Browserflow flows.
This means that I am effectively sending Slack and Discord messages as myself, rather than using an API to do so.
The messages are sent in a browser using clicks and keyboard presses,
all in the same human-centric UI that I would use if I were to send the messages manually.
I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to Browserflow for making this possible, as Slack and Discord have been really key additions to this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflections-on-the-setup&#34;&gt;Reflections on the setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the setup for only a few days so far, and am continuing to actively develop it.
So far, I absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headless typing experience provided by Go Note Go makes for a great environment for drafting messages.
So too does using Roam Research while scrolling through social media. (I&amp;rsquo;m the sort of person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually like replying publicly to social media posts, but does enjoy engaging with them in 1:1 or small group chat messages.)
Drifting off to sleep has proven to be another excellent time to share thoughts with friends.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start &lt;em&gt;a conversation&lt;/em&gt; with friends as I drift off to sleep, but loads of thoughts come to mind that I do want to share with people, and so adding them to my Messager Queue to send the next day has been quite satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this interests you, feel free to get in touch.
If you do, I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to get back to you, likely as I&amp;rsquo;m drifting off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Instructions for Flashcard Collection Task</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-23-flashcard-collection-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-23-flashcard-collection-task/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! This is a draft of instructions I intend to send out to volunteers for the contextual flashcard dataset collection project.
I would love your feedback on the instructions before I send them out more widely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Contextual Flashcard Dataset Project.
Thank you for volunteering!
By working together, we are assembling a dataset of thousands of in-context flashcards
to help evaluate and improve future automatic flashcard generation projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, install the Browserflow extension and the flow:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/1b2b5231-5f96-4f73-87a6-006626fa3831&#34;&gt;https://browserflow.app/shared/1b2b5231-5f96-4f73-87a6-006626fa3831&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your help is requested in creating flashcards to populate the dataset.
Please submit between 5 and 200 flashcards that you believe would be useful or interesting to you.
The flow above will assist you in submitting flashcards to the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit a flashcard for the dataset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse the web as normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select some text you consider important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/1b2b5231-5f96-4f73-87a6-006626fa3831&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Create Flashcard Entry flow&lt;/a&gt;; it will open the Create Flashcard Entry form and pre-populate it for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make any desired changes to the &amp;ldquo;Flashcard Front&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Flashcard Back&amp;rdquo; fields in the Create Flashcard Entry form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lieu of using Browserflow, you may also submit 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/vTNWReM6qeEwX6GDA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the data entry form&lt;/a&gt; manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-will-the-data-be-used&#34;&gt;How will the data be used?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset will be cleaned. Personal information or offensive language will be removed. The resulting dataset will be made public for anyone to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-are-submissions-open&#34;&gt;When are submissions open?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will begin collecting submissions on December 1, 2021, and leave submissions open for 2 months, closing submissions on January 31, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-flashcards-should-i-submit&#34;&gt;What flashcards should I submit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s up to you! Still asking? Here&amp;rsquo;s some guidance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit any flashcards that you would (1) find personally interesting or useful, and (2) only contain public information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting facts from Wikipedia or articles you read online are a good idea.
Private information about close friends is not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIRDS: Bidirectional incremental real-time data synchronizers</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-birds/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The culmination of my thinking on note-taking interoperability so far is that we need &lt;strong&gt;BIRDS&lt;/strong&gt;. . Allow me to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want an &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo; for note-taking systems, to allow them to interoperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here an &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo; means an &lt;strong&gt;in-process&lt;/strong&gt; representation of notes that can do &lt;strong&gt;bidirectional real-time incremental&lt;/strong&gt; syncs with any of the popular note-taking systems (any system with a connector written for it).
The main reason we want this is it allows application developers to write applications once for the IR, and have their application work for users using any note-taking system.
A second reason this is desirable is it allows introducing data into your notes from multiple sources, like your email, news feeds, messages, and social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bridge a note-taking system with the IR, a connector should be written between the system and the intermediate representation. These connectors, we shall call &lt;strong&gt;birds&lt;/strong&gt;, , short for &amp;ldquo;bidirectional incremental real-time data synchronizer&amp;rdquo;. Each bird  is a bridge that either pushes, pulls, or pushes-and-pulls data between the &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo; notebase and some data source or storage system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birds  are bidirectional because they allow pushing or pulling data in either direction.
They are incremental because they are aware of what data is on the other end of the connection, and only transmit changes.
They are real-time, because these changes are transmitted quickly and automatically.
These properties are similar to those of Dropbox or Google Drive, but rather than there being files on either end of the connection, there are notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the birds  that I would use for my current setup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would use a bidirectional bird  with Roam Research, since that&amp;rsquo;s my core note-taking location at the moment.
I would use a bird  to connect my email to my notes. Ideally I would also have birds  for each of the messaging and social media platforms that I use too.
I would use a bird  to write my full notebase to disk locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If later I switch away from Roam, I would use a new bird  to import my data into whatever new better system I switch to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, I was able to put a bird  emoji next to every use of the word bird  in this snippet, and still not run out of bird  emojis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save my spot! Finer-grained bookmarks for incremental reading</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-save-my-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-save-my-spot/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I find articles on the web, often I only read a small portion of an article before browsing away.
Instead of giving up on the article, I would like to leave a little visual marker on the page indicating the part of the page that I reached.
I&amp;rsquo;d then also like to automatically add a link to this marker to my notes.
So, if I&amp;rsquo;m ever reviewing my notes, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to jump right back into the article where I left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I later continue reading the article, I&amp;rsquo;d like to move the marker to whatever spot I reach. (It&amp;rsquo;s OK if the old links keep linking to the old location, but I want a new link to whatever spot I&amp;rsquo;ve reached.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this should be possible to build with Browserflow. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how.
I think I would do this with two flows, one to save my spot on a page (and add it to my notes),
and a second flow to restore to that spot on the page from the link in my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest decision is how to represent a spot on a page. One option is the scroll position. Another option would be to remember a unique element id. Both approaches have drawbacks. Using scroll position doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with dynamic content. Element ids aren&amp;rsquo;t guaranteed to be unique. I am leaning toward the scroll position approach to start, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll see how fragile it is. Even though it isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, it will work in most situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I run the first flow, it will grab the URL of the current page and the current scroll position, and it will write that into my notes. This requires changing tabs, which is easy to do with Browserflow, but not easy to do with a standard JavaScript script. That flow will be run on the website where I am reading the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other flow will be run while I&amp;rsquo;m reading my notes. It would be great if just clicking on a link in my notes could trigger this flow and take me to the correct spot in the article, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t possible (by default) with Browserflow today. One way to work around this limitation of Browserflow is to write an always-on flow that listens for when I&amp;rsquo;ve clicked the link. Unfortunately, always-on flows are not great with Browserflow&amp;rsquo;s pricing plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I run the flow to restore my spot in an old article, the flow will first open a new tab to that article&amp;rsquo;s webpage. Then it will scroll to the specified position. When the flow starts, it will first need a way to determine which of the links on the notes page to follow. With the current version of Browserflow that I have (0.72 I think), you can just click on the link to specify this. This option is removed unfortunately in the latest version of Browserflow. Instead, we can probably use a clever selector to select the user-selected link. This should work in later Browserflow versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these two flows are implemented, saving and loading my point in an article to and from my notes will become much easier. The next improvement will be adding in a bit of visual flourish (e.g. a visual marker in the article to draw my eye to where I left off). Certainly a smoother UX is feasible than the one I&amp;rsquo;ve planned here, but I think this Browserflow prototype hits a sweet spot of quality-to-effort ratio, and will be a satisfying prototype to build and use for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing a Twitter Discussion: Gathering Twitter Replies</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-twitter-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-20-twitter-replies/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bieber/status/1461128201485402112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; about spaced repetition earlier this week, sharing and summarizing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-11-02-improvements-to-spaced-repetition/&#34;&gt;my latest snippet on the subject&lt;/a&gt;. A bunch of people left thoughtful replies, and I was quite pleased with the discussion. Now I want to look over the discussion holistically, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see a great way to do this. I don&amp;rsquo;t even see a way to look at all the replies to my thread in one place. I want to see not just this, but also replies to replies. TweetDeck might be able to help, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what I&amp;rsquo;d like to do is write a little script that takes a tweet as input, and outputs links to all the replies and replies to replies in a little tree that I can put into Roam.
Then I can make notes on the full thread, and even link together different parts of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import twython
from messager import settings

client = twython.Twython(
        settings.TWITTER_CONSUMER_KEY,
        settings.TWITTER_CONSUMER_SECRET,
        settings.TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN,
        settings.TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET)

def get_replies(status_id):
  status = client.lookup_status(id=status_id)[0]
  return get_replies_to_status(status)

def get_replies_to_status(status):
  status_id = status[&#39;id&#39;]
  screen_name = status[&#39;user&#39;][&#39;screen_name&#39;]
  results = client.search(
      q=f&#39;to:{screen_name}&#39;, sinceId=status_id, count=128)
  candidates = results[&#39;statuses&#39;]
  replies = []
  for candidate in candidates:
    if candidate[&#39;in_reply_to_status_id&#39;] == status_id:
      replies.append(candidate)
  return replies

def get_recursive_replies(status_id):
  status = client.lookup_status(id=status_id)[0]
  all_replies = []
  to_search = [status]
  searched = set()
  while to_search:
    status = to_search.pop()
    if status[&#39;id&#39;] not in searched:
      replies = get_replies_to_status(status)
      all_replies.extend(replies)
      to_search.extend(replies)
      searched.add(status[&#39;id&#39;])
  return all_replies

status_id = 1461128201485402112
replies = get_recursive_replies(status_id)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: I would love for this file (the markdown file I&amp;rsquo;m writing this snippet in) to double as a Python file.
When I run it, just the Python code block(s) would get run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise the Twitter API did not make it easy to query for replies to a tweet. So, I&amp;rsquo;m using the workaround on display above.
To get all replies to a tweet, I query for all tweets to the tweet author, and then filter for those that are actually replies.
Since the number of search results is limited, this might not always work; it depends on what order Twitter decides to sort tweets by. If Twitter returns the oldest tweets first, this method will work consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does seem to be working for now, fortunately. There are 60 recursive replies to my tweet, and with this method I was able to lay them all out in a row. Pasting the urls into Roam, I find the default rendering of each tweet in Roam takes up a bit too much space though and provides too much context. So, I may need to modify the display a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that I can lay out the entire conversation compactly, and then start marking it up with my own notes, e.g. tagging replies that express similar ideas so I can reply to them together rather than individually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Automation Ideas for Note-taking</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-28-ml-and-automation-for-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-28-ml-and-automation-for-note-taking/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider machine learning first, and then automation. For each we brainstorm the potential value for note-taking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-of-markmachine-learningmark-for-note-taking&#34;&gt;The Value of &lt;mark&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/mark&gt; for Note-Taking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic &lt;strong&gt;transcription&lt;/strong&gt; of audio notes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker identification&lt;/strong&gt; during meetings or conversations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resurfacing of action items, surfacing relevant information, and performing actions (e.g running a google search or sending a message) in response to audio cues during meetings or conversations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic &lt;strong&gt;categorization&lt;/strong&gt; of notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic &lt;strong&gt;categorization of spaced repetition&lt;/strong&gt; flash cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic &lt;strong&gt;context-filling&lt;/strong&gt; of spaced repetition flash cards
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g. highlight a phrase to create a flash card; the necessary context is pulled in from surrounding paragraphs to make a coherent standalone flash card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic &lt;strong&gt;connections&lt;/strong&gt; and graph construction:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textual elements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entity extraction from notes (&amp;ldquo;implicit nodes&amp;rdquo;, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Bank of America&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attribute extraction from notes (e.g. &amp;ldquo;incredible presentation by Pierre-Antoine&amp;rdquo; gets tagged as incredible or wow (the canonical form).)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationship extraction (e.g. &amp;ldquo;Diamond Age by Neal Stephenson&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; creates an &amp;ldquo;author of&amp;rdquo; relationship)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background knowledge elements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g. knowing that Diamond Age is a book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing prompt generator / &lt;strong&gt;Writing assistant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overlap detection&lt;/strong&gt; between people&amp;rsquo;s graphs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Go Note Go &amp;ldquo;clink&amp;rdquo; scenario&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autocomplete&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. gmail tab completion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved &lt;strong&gt;spaced repetition algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistake detection / &lt;strong&gt;fact checking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summarization&lt;/strong&gt; of notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight extraction&lt;/strong&gt; from notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggesting &lt;strong&gt;new ideas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggesting &lt;strong&gt;new online resources&lt;/strong&gt; to read / explore
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incl. articles, papers, YouTube videos, Suggesting &lt;strong&gt;people to reach out to&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. because of their blog or Twitter or other things they&amp;rsquo;re written)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semantic search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversational chat bots&lt;/strong&gt; for exploring the knowledge in a notebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-of-markautomationmark-for-note-taking&#34;&gt;The Value of &lt;mark&gt;Automation&lt;/mark&gt; for Note-Taking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share notes&lt;/strong&gt; with people via their preferred messaging platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snooze notes&lt;/strong&gt; and ideas so you review them later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set pomodoros, alarms, and reminders to &lt;strong&gt;stay focused&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;stay on task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note-taking &lt;strong&gt;via highlights&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. with Browserflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note-taking &lt;strong&gt;via screenshots&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. from YouTube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic creation of &lt;strong&gt;spaced repetition from highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bulk refactors&lt;/strong&gt; of note-taking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pulling in context&lt;/strong&gt; from other sources (e.g. Warmly pulls LinkedIn info into Calendar, notes could pull info from wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sync notes&lt;/strong&gt; between other sources and your notebase
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people&amp;rsquo;s notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your email client, calendar, TODO app, spaced repetition app, GitHub issues, other messaging services, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing&lt;/strong&gt; of notes to a webpage (either publicly or privately), or to social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;data entry&lt;/strong&gt; mechanisms: &lt;strong&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/strong&gt;, terminal, email, text, browsing history, location history, terminal history, IoT devices, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spaced repetition&lt;/strong&gt; for studying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inactivity reminders&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s been three months since you&amp;rsquo;ve done a music activity&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s been over 6 months since you&amp;rsquo;ve spoken with David Dohan&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s been over a year since you&amp;rsquo;ve written about microbiology.&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rough Note-taking Interop Requirements</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-10-note-taking-interop-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-10-note-taking-interop-requirements/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I mused about 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/&#34;&gt;the benefits an interoperability standard could provide&lt;/a&gt; to note-taking systems. Today, I extract rough requirements for such a standard from that musing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note entry projects need to be able to insert notes into a notebase regardless of which note-taking system is storing the notebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is critical for projects like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-29-note-taking-flow/&#34;&gt;my Browserflow note-taking flows&lt;/a&gt; (which only support Roam right now) and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go/&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt; to be multi-vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Restricted note entry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; allows an application like Go Note Go to insert notes into an application-specific section of the notes. In a &amp;ldquo;daily notes&amp;rdquo; oriented notebase like Roam, this is a &amp;ldquo;Go Note Go&amp;rdquo;-specific section on each daily notes page. In a page-oriented notebase, this can instead be an application specific page or namespace (e.g. &amp;ldquo;Go Note Go/*&amp;quot;) that notes can be inserted into. When using restricted note entry, an application can only insert notes into their own region of the notebase. This prevents the application from performing disruptive insertions that lower the quality of the notes outside of this region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unrestricted note entry&lt;/strong&gt; allows an application to perform a broader set of inserts, not limited to a specific region of the notes. For a note-taking entry system that also allows browsing the notes, where a user might want to insert new notes alongside an existing note they&amp;rsquo;ve pulled up, this becomes important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual note reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batch note reading:&lt;/strong&gt; When notes are just text, reading large quantities of notes at a time becomes inexpensive. Often an entire text notebase is small enough to be kept in memory or transmitted over a network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incremental export&lt;/strong&gt; is critical for real-time features, such as collaborative note-taking across systems. Also necessary for this is support for a &lt;strong&gt;note view&lt;/strong&gt; and the ability to &lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt; to updates. Consider a collaborative note-taking experience. I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes in Roam, and one of my blocks is an embed of a page from your notes in Notion. As you make edits to the page in Notion, they should appear in my notes. If I have edit access on that page, I should be able to directly edit that page in my notes too, and you should see the results reflected in Notion in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this to work, both note-taking systems could need to support the necessary parts of the standard. If instead, Notion lacked the real-time import capability, a half-baked experience of cross-system collaborative note-taking could still be possible. As edits in Notion get saved, they appear in real-time in Roam. When edits are made in Roam, Notion would only render them upon reloading the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a conflict is introduced to the intermediate representation, it could be handled gracefully through a CRDT. If instead a conflict is introduced on the note-taking system side of things, then that note-taking system is responsible for handling the conflict resolution as it sees fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The above ideas taken together (and assumed idealized) can support the applications discussed yesterday: e.g. note entry systems like Go Note Go, advancements in spaced repetition, multiplayer spaced repetition, multiplayer note-taking, summarization features, highlight extraction features. What they don&amp;rsquo;t support is the development of UI widgets that can be developed once and deployed across any note-taking system. Supporting that type of integration would require a greater degree / different type of standardization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider someone wanting to implement a summarization feature for note-taking systems, agnostic to the specific note-taking system being used. They train a machine learning model that can take a bunch of text notes and produce a quality summary. They implement a way for a user to efficiently select a collection of notes. The UI they choose allows searching by tags and keywords, navigating through the search results with the arrow keys and marking notes and their children for inclusion by pressing enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the user indicates they&amp;rsquo;ve selected the notes for summarization, they submit them to the feature&amp;rsquo;s ML system, which produces a summary.
if the user likes the summary, they accept it. When accepted, the feature inserts the summary into a dedicated Summarization specific section of the notes, complete with references to each of those notes used to produce the summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This toy feature relies on having batch read access to the notes on the basis of a query, as well as restricted note entry permissions for writing notes back to the system. Using the hypothetical standard we are brainstorming toward in this snippet, such a system could be implemented once, but used by anyone with their notes in any of the note-taking systems that conform to these parts of the standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An even better summarization feature would be one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require the user to select the notes to summarize. It would automatically identify chunks of notes on a related topic, and summarize those. When it generates a summary, it would offer it to the user, along with mentioning which notes were used in the generation of the summary. The user could choose to accept the summary (in which case it would be saved as explained above), or not to. This version of the features requires whole-notebase access to implement, a slightly more permissive requirement than query-based access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does such a &lt;em&gt;standard&lt;/em&gt; look like in practice? Maybe a useful analogy is thinking of it as an &amp;ldquo;LLVM&amp;rdquo; for notebases &amp;ndash; an &amp;ldquo;LLNB&amp;rdquo; if you will (unofficially standing for low level notebase, but not officially standing for anything&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each note-taking system we could implement a lossless bidirectional transform to a standard &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo;. Tools and plugins could be written to operate on this shared representation, and they could then be deployed against any note-taking system with supported transformations to and from the shared representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo; compiler analogy isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect though, since I don&amp;rsquo;t think it captures the desired incremental export, view, and subscription features we&amp;rsquo;d like in the LLNB system. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to process an entire notebase to get it&amp;rsquo;s LLNB form, and we don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to overwrite an entire notebase to update it from a modified LLNB. Critical to this working is having the LLNB track its own updates and be able to export just what has changed, and similarly having the note-taking systems able to report either a full update (if no state about the notebase is known), or just an incremental update (if the notebase state was already exported recently). One way to achieve this would be to have an API that gives a diff between an earlier state of a notebase (say, indicated by a commit hash or timestamp) and the current state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about system-specific features? When features of a specific note-taking system X are used, they can appear in the intermediate representation as metadata. This metadata can be constituted appropriately when transferred back to X, or can be included as text if instead transferred to system Y. To make this concrete, support Notion has a geographic map feature that someone has used in their notes, but that is not supported by Roam. If the export their notes to LLNB, the map state is saved as e.g. {location: new jersey, zoom: 5}. If the notes are then imported back into Notion, the map will be restored. If instead the notes are imported into Roam, which lacks the map feature, the data about how the map feature will be included instead. So, if the notes are later exported from Roam and imported back into Notion, the map will be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the state of some feature is complicated and not practically serializable as a note, it can be stored outside the notebase, e.g. in Dropbox or Google Drive or whatever is appropriate, with a reference to that external storage medium used as the state.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking System Interoperability</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-10-09-note-taking-system-interop/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would be a good &lt;em&gt;standard&lt;/em&gt; for note-taking software to use to support development of system-agnostic tools like Go Note Go? In this snippet I discuss the value such a standard could provide; I expect it will be useful in future brainstorming for what exactly would go into such a standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am building Go Note Go as a note-taking entry point, possibly with some basic retrieval features (e.g. &amp;ldquo;read back the last two notes I took&amp;rdquo;). I currently use Roam Research as my main note-taking system, but I&amp;rsquo;m not wedded to it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m building Go Note Go to work with any note-taking system. To do so, I need a distinct uploader implementation for every note-taking system that I support. I&amp;rsquo;m reaching out to the developers at the note-taking systems to assist with this effort. It would be lovely if there was a standard, to reduce the amount of work required here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Go Note Go, only note &lt;em&gt;entry&lt;/em&gt; is required. If Go Note Go wanted to interact with the notes in a deeper way while continuing to support multiple note-taking systems (e.g. to support spaced repetition, or grocery lists, or reviewing a topic), then a standard would be even more important. Specialized implementations for each note-taking system would become largely untenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is both common and important that hobbyists develop tools for interacting with their notes. Roam Research has 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamjs.com/extensions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hundreds&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/#/app/roam-depot-developers/page/8yTj7WxQi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bjosephburch.com/ultimate-roam-tool-kit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;extensions&lt;/a&gt; developed by the Roam community. Obsidian has hundreds of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/plugins&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt;. This is part of what makes these tools so powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, no one has written a tool for both Roam and Obsidian simultaneously. I want people to be able to make tools for all of Roam, Obsidian, IdeaFlow, Mem, RemNote, Notion, Logseq, Athens, Dendron, all the ones I don&amp;rsquo;t know about, and whatever comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these tools will live inside the note-taking editor. Others, like Go Note Go, merely have to interact with the note-taking system, but do not need to become &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of the note-taking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key areas where standards could provide value are: note representation, entry, navigation, editing, and search. Also valuable, but conceptually separate, would be a standard for UI extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards would make the development of system-agnostic tools easier. This includes novel note entry systems (e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh-shell&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;, but also note entry systems for new domains, such as for doctor&amp;rsquo;s offices or for while you&amp;rsquo;re cooking, or for use in virtual reality). It also would support advancements in spaced repetition, multiplayer note-taking, and would enable new features like note summarization and highlight extraction to become available in all the different note-taking systems at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all these applications, standards will make import/export/backup tools easier to build. This can reduce vendor lock in, and more importantly can reduce data loss by enabling robust backups. Today, switching my notes to another system would be a small hassle (e.g. Handling block references in the transfer might require some specialized treatment. And I&amp;rsquo;d need to do some work to set up a spaced repetition system like the one I&amp;rsquo;m currently using in Roam.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll say a few words about some of these ideas that would benefit from standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) &lt;strong&gt;Advancements in spaced repetition.&lt;/strong&gt; Having a spaced repetition system inside of a note-taking system is far lower friction than a separate app. Improvements to SRS that work across all note-taking systems would be warmly welcomed. I believe there are also significant advances to be made in community-scale spaced repetition, where cards and knowledge are drawn from not just your own notes, but from your community&amp;rsquo;s notes (including peers and teachers), and where your review schedule is similarly influenced not only by your own learning progress, but also by the progress of your community. This deserves a separate snippet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll note here a possibility that community-scale spaced repetition enables: it allows for community-level learning priorities, which may include diversity of topic. For example the members of a community might decide they want to ensure that all of its history is adequately studied (or any other collection of topics), not just the most interesting parts. Deciding individually, the members of the community might choose to study overly overlapping parts of its history. Using a community-scale spaced repetition algorithm, the choice of what to study can still predominantly be left up to individuals, but with small guidance from the centralized algorithm the community can ensure complete coverage of all the desired topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) &lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Note-taking&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s say I&amp;rsquo;m doing research on a topic, and a colleague is doing research on a related topic. I might want to search through my colleague&amp;rsquo;s notes, and reference some of them from my own notes. This isn&amp;rsquo;t even possible in most note-taking systems today, but I think is either a future or work-in-progress feature of Roam, Athens, and Obsidian. Being able to do this cross-system would be so much better than only being able to do it within a system. A standard agreed upon by the different note-taking system developers would be necessary to support this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3) &lt;strong&gt;Summarization and highlight extraction&lt;/strong&gt; Summarization is a feature not yet present in any note-taking system, but surely one that will be added to many systems in the future. It is the ability to get a (machine generated) summary of a large chunk of notes automatically. This is marginally useful when reviewing your own notes, but is even more useful in conjunction with multiplayer features. Being able to view a summary of other people&amp;rsquo;s notes or an entire community&amp;rsquo;s notes will allow multiplayer systems to scale to larger groups of people while remaining useful. Highlight extraction is a related future feature, enabling users to quickly find the most important parts of a notebase. As with summarization, this is useful for an individuals notes, and doubly useful for a multiplayer notebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these ideas, standards would be useful for allowing feature development to benefit users of all systems simultaneously, and for allowing users of one note-taking system to benefit from notes taken in another system. The space of possible applications is also much larger than my brainstorming above indicates. Specifically, the set of domain-specific activities one might want to perform with their notes is quite large (planning a family gathering, studying for a med school exam, writing a novel, etc.) Specialized applications could be built for each of these, and it should not matter where the relevant notes were taken. Different systems will always have their pros and cons for different types of content, but we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reinvent the wheel so frequently for use-cases that make sense in the context of all these different systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go is public</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-09-26-go-note-go/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go Note Go is public! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this for two weeks now, and today I made it public!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Read all about it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it? Go Note Go is a note-taking system for when youre on the go, with a focus on driving and camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, it&amp;rsquo;s a portable keyboard with a microphone and speakers and a beautiful handheld button that you can use to take notes anywhere at all. Driving? Push the button and speak your notes. Camping? Type on the keyboard, powered by a battery pack. The battery lasts all day, and the notes will be uploaded to your central note-taking system as soon as internet becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look. Let me know what you think! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it as I develop it over the last two weeks and I &lt;em&gt;really love&lt;/em&gt; it. I keep it by my computer during the work day. I took it with me to my table tennis tournament yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;ve brought it to the beach. There&amp;rsquo;s no cognitive overhead. There&amp;rsquo;s no latency to slow down your thinking. Just speak, or type, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browserflow Note-taking Flow</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-29-note-taking-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-07-29-note-taking-flow/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick update on the note-taking Browserflow flow I&amp;rsquo;ve been building: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/51b5b7af-3124-4989-9771-36e9f236e1e7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://browserflow.app/shared/51b5b7af-3124-4989-9771-36e9f236e1e7&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run it, it injects some js into the page you&amp;rsquo;re viewing enabling a handful of keyboard shortcuts to enable clipping text into Roam from anywhere on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you navigate to a new page, it will run that js on the new page. So it keeps the keyboard shortcuts active even if you follow links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also removes the status overlay, so you can interact with the page more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-keyboard-shortcuts-currently-are&#34;&gt;The keyboard shortcuts currently are:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt;: saves the current selection as a note to Roam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;q, !, @, *, &amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: saves the current selection as a note to Roam tagged as a {question, &amp;ldquo;Wow&amp;rdquo;, Share, key idea, or block quote} (I don&amp;rsquo;t really use these)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt;: saves the paragraph containing the selection to Roam, with the selection highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt;: Asks for an element in browserflow. Saves a screenshot of the element to Roam. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. (hmm&amp;hellip; why not?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;: saves the sentence containing the selection to Roam, with the selection highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;: saves the sentence containing the selection to Roam as a &amp;ldquo;cloze&amp;rdquo; (fill-in-the-blank) task for spaced repetition, with the selection as the fill-in-the-blank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;: (big cloze) saves the paragraph containing the selection to Roam as a &amp;ldquo;cloze&amp;rdquo; (fill-in-the-blank) task for spaced repetition, with the selection as the fill-in-the-blank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;: quit (I use this to reenable keyboard shortcuts for tab switching)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-feature-requests--debug-things&#34;&gt;Some feature requests / debug things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would be nice to keep some status indicator, just in the corner or page title instead of blocking the full page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It depends on a couple other flows. Would be nice to be able to share just a single link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It switches to the roamresearch.com tab and back whenever you save a note. Would be nice if this worked even if roam were in a different window. The user shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to care about exactly where roam is open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the element screenshotting work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would be nice to allow tab switching in a flow without having to quit the flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a note-taking flow like this, it can easily be running for hours. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t mix super well with the free tier of billing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few of these could be solved with an &amp;ldquo;Enable interaction with page&amp;rdquo; action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dependency-flows-needed-to-check-it-out-are&#34;&gt;The dependency flows needed to check it out are:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/ba6eb2f0-a3d1-4bc3-9f21-5ca18af0b247&#34;&gt;https://browserflow.app/shared/ba6eb2f0-a3d1-4bc3-9f21-5ca18af0b247&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/486ef3eb-8d2b-48bf-8fee-22963dc74b88&#34;&gt;https://browserflow.app/shared/486ef3eb-8d2b-48bf-8fee-22963dc74b88&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app/shared/8e066128-2f87-468f-842f-3f006f0a2e71&#34;&gt;https://browserflow.app/shared/8e066128-2f87-468f-842f-3f006f0a2e71&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try out the flow, you&amp;rsquo;ll need Browserflow, an open Roam tab, and all four flows linked in this snippet. Run the first flow (&amp;ldquo;Roam: Highlights&amp;rdquo;) on a web page (with Roam open in a different tab in the same window). Highlight some text, (say, the words &amp;ldquo;some text&amp;rdquo; in this sentence), and hit enter. You can try any of the shortcuts listed above. Notice as the flow copies your selection into your daily notes organized by time and website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two more Browserflow flows for Roam Research</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-13-flows-for-roam-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-13-flows-for-roam-research/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote three Browserflow flows for Roam Research today. None of them took me more than 20-30 minutes to write. The first one was for saving the current webpage to Roam. I 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-13-saving-urls-to-roam-with-browserflow/&#34;&gt;wrote about that flow here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next flow I wrote is for saving any link you click on to Roam. The idea behind this flow is to prevent doing depth first exploration of the web. Better to look at a bunch of links and then later choose the most interesting, than to dive head first into the first link you click on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video of that flow here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KMxnws2Laww&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I also wrote a flow for saving highlights from any web page to Roam. You can see that flow in action here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MaV0GP4sZoM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this flow, whenever I press enter the text I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted is saved to my Roam Research Daily Notes page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to all the flows are in the video descriptions. Browserflow is currently in private beta. Looks like in the short-term DK will likely ask 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/dkthehuman/Day-404-Choosing-My-Users-2a6b2c9cfc194fd3b561c370a62c60d5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;$20&lt;/a&gt; for access to the private beta. You can join the waitlist at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserflow.app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;browserflow.app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving URLs to Roam with Browserflow</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-13-saving-urls-to-roam-with-browserflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-13-saving-urls-to-roam-with-browserflow/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2021-02-12-javascript-functions-for-inserting-blocks-in-roam/&#34;&gt;Roam JavaScript primitives I wrote yesterday&lt;/a&gt; it was extremely easy (less than 10 minutes, I think) to create a robust Browserflow flow for saving URLs to Roam Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I&amp;rsquo;m browsing the web, I can press cmd-J (Browserflow&amp;rsquo;s keyboard shortcut) and choose &amp;ldquo;Roam: Save URL&amp;rdquo; from the typeahead to save the current URL to my Roam Daily Notes page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s not already a &amp;ldquo;Saved URLs:&amp;rdquo; block on daily notes, it makes it. Then it nests the URL beneath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what the flow looks like in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ORpBuE4UYSA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what the flow itself looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;save-urls-flow.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice there are really only two meaningful lines of code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;let urls = await getOrCreateBlockOnPage($page, &#39;Saved URLs:&#39;, -1);
await createChildBlock(urls, $url)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line creates the &amp;ldquo;Saved URLs:&amp;rdquo; block, but only if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist. It returns the uid of that block. The second line saves the url. Nothing else to it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Notes While Browsing the Web: An Idea for a Roam Research Plugin</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-05-15-roaming-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-05-15-roaming-the-web/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m browsing the web, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to take notes in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Roam Research&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I share an idea I have for a plugin or browser extension that I think would improve the experience of taking notes in Roam while browsing the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin would do two main things automatically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would automatically insert some browsing history information into your Roam database while you browse the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you navigate the web, it would automatically bring you to the Roam page that corresponds to the web page you&amp;rsquo;re reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mind-the-details&#34;&gt;Mind the Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the implementation details matter! You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be whisked away from the notes you&amp;rsquo;re taking just because you&amp;rsquo;ve clicked a link in a different window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I&amp;rsquo;ll explain a few of the details I think would make this a good note taking experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m browsing the internet, all the websites I visit will get added to a page &amp;ldquo;{Date} Browsing History&amp;rdquo;. A new Roam page will be created for each new website visited. And there will be a Roam window that always stays open to the Roam page for the current website I have open in my browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What qualifies as a website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default there would be one Roam page per &lt;em&gt;domain&lt;/em&gt; visited. However, there are several exceptions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/strong&gt; it would be one Roam page per Wikipedia entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For websites reached from &lt;strong&gt;HackerNews&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Reddit&lt;/strong&gt;, it would be one Roam page per link followed from the aggregator (but links followed within the reached website would not count as new websites)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; it would be one Roam page per user, organization, or repo visited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Arxiv&lt;/strong&gt; it would be one Roam page per paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Roam&lt;/strong&gt; it would be one Roam page per Roam database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be great to have a window that always stays open to the Roam page for the current website I have open in my browser. This way if I visit a website I&amp;rsquo;ve been to before, I will see my notes from that website. And the websites I visit will be linked to the day I visit them on, and also to any other pages my notes reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the tool should add a little bit of metadata to the pages it&amp;rsquo;s generating. On each of the autogenerated Roam pages, it would be great to see &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; I visited the website, and what was the referring page. For websites visited multiple times, seeing the earliest and most recent visit times, and the number of times I visited that website would be useful too. Total time spent on the website would be a nice bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-this-a-reality&#34;&gt;Making this a Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous section I shared the details that I think would make this work well from a user experience perspective. How about from the technical side?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it would make sense to implement this as a browser extension (though a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tampermonkey.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;user script&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; could work too).

&lt;a href=&#34;http://dkthehuman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DK the Human&lt;/a&gt;, author of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/intention/dladanhaondcgpahgiflodhckhoeohoe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/a&gt; browser extension
has made his 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dkthehuman/extension-starter-kit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;browser extension starter kit&lt;/a&gt; freely available.
To notice when what web page you&amp;rsquo;re browsing and determine whether it constitutes a new page, the extension would need to request permission to view your activity on all websites.
For making additions to a Roam database automatically, I expect the extension would have to navigate to the appropriate Roam page in the background, and would then mimic the user actions to make the desired changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in turning this idea into a reality or want to discuss it further, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:david810&amp;#43;blog@gmail.com&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;d be excited to try a workflow like this, but don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate building it myself in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>