<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writing on David Bieber</title>
    <link>https://davidbieber.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writing on David Bieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidbieber.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go Note Go Writing Volume</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-02-14-go-note-go-writing-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-02-14-go-note-go-writing-volume/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot, but not putting up any new snippets.
Where has all the writing gone? Into 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/go-note-go&#34;&gt;Go Note Go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 150 days since I started Go Note Go.
I have written on Go Note Go on 91 of those days, producing 54,000 words.
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a little over 24 hours total doing so, making my writing speed a bit shy of 40 wpm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I review more of my Go Note Go writing than I might expect, given its volume and that none of it has translated into published snippets.
Since 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2022-01-08-gng-messager-snippet-plans/&#34;&gt;turning Go Note Go into an outliner&lt;/a&gt;,
the experience of reviewing my writing has been much more comfortable than it was previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I write in Go Note Go using the &amp;ldquo;Roam Research&amp;rdquo; uploader, my writing is divided into &amp;ldquo;sessions&amp;rdquo;.
Each session starts with a line containing only the time. The rest of the writing is nested beneath.
&lt;img src=&#34;session.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I review my writing in Go Note Go, I do so session by session, putting a summary of the session in that top line of the session, and then collapsing the session. Often the top line is a block-reference to one or more of the lines from the session. For example,
&lt;img src=&#34;session-collapsed.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This compresses the 600 words I might write on a given day and presents them in a series of often 10 or fewer individual lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I like that I can and do review my writing to a greater degree than expected, I think there&amp;rsquo;s still substantial improvement to make in the review-and-reuse experience.
In particular, one idea I&amp;rsquo;m excited about and which I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about in Go Note Go a fair amount, is hiring someone to review my notes and process them into a summary / a newsletter for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking there is that I write a lot and there is definitely more in my writing than fits in my working memory at any time (this idea, that I want access to more than fits in working memory, has been recurring a fair amount lately).
By leaning on another person, I can more effectively resurface the ideas that I most want to revisit. I&amp;rsquo;m posting this snippet as is, but this idea itself is one I&amp;rsquo;m eager to revisit in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are all the posts from 2020?</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2021-01-08-where-are-all-the-posts-from-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2021-01-08-where-are-all-the-posts-from-2020/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll notice I have no 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/posts/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; from 2020, but this is not because I stopped writing. Instead, I have been writing &amp;ldquo;snippets,&amp;rdquo; which 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/&#34;&gt;you can read here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to read just one snippet, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;I recommend that it be this one&lt;/a&gt;.
The main idea behind snippets is to allow me to write without the inhibitions I sometimes experience when writing a blog post for publication.
By writing in a secluded section of the website with no (now, few) inbound links, and by deliberately keeping the quality bar for publication low to non-existent, I made it easier for myself to write often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the quality bar low,
sometimes I would deliberately post a short half-baked thought, possibly without editing or revision.
Despite this aim of keeping the quality bar low, and despite explicitly writing for no one, I often would find myself pleased with what I had written and eager for someone else to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this is the beauty of the setup. The (lack of) quality standards make &lt;em&gt;starting writing&lt;/em&gt; easy. I typically start writing a snippet with the mindset that I have a little idea I want to get out of my head and onto paper. As I begin, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a small idea that will take just a few lines. Perhaps in the back of my mind I even think it will contribute to lowering of the quality-bar for the section of the website. And sometimes it does. But just as often, I find myself ready to elaborate on the idea. Perhaps I explain where the idea came from, or why I find it interesting. And by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve finished writing, I have a snippet that I&amp;rsquo;m proud of, and which I would love to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I sometimes put my email address at the end of a snippet. With just a cursory description of the snippets section (&amp;ldquo;a place to write for no audience&amp;rdquo;), seeing my contact info at the end of a post may feel contradictory. Now you see that it is not; the lack of a quality bar and the lack of an audience serve their purpose in allowing me to start writing easily, and to publish readily, but once I have written something and released it to (a tiny unlinked corner of) the world I do not necessarily want to keep it hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am now for the first time linking from my main website 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/&#34;&gt;directly to the snippets section of my website&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not a prominent link, as it&amp;rsquo;s contained only within this blog post, but it&amp;rsquo;s a meaningful step for me. Web crawlers now have a means in to index the site. Visitors to the site now have a means in too, not just people to whom I explicitly send the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do venture in, and read a snippet or two, there are a few things to know.
First, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome here. It&amp;rsquo;s not voyeurism. These aren&amp;rsquo;t private posts; they&amp;rsquo;re simply not written for an audience, but I am happy for them to have one. Second, they&amp;rsquo;re snippets. Think of them like ideas scrawled in a hurry. I&amp;rsquo;m not wedded to the ideas I express, and I&amp;rsquo;m open to reconsidering what I wrote. And thirdly, I value your thoughts (and your time!), and it would delight me to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find ideas for side-projects, philosophical musings, technical notes meant mainly for future-me, technical notes meant for other people, project updates, nonsense, personal notes, and more. All of this, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing with GPT-3</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-07-22-writing-with-gpt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-07-22-writing-with-gpt3/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GPT-3 is a language model developed at Open AI, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun playing with it. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve written this post in collaboration with GPT-3. See if you can spot which parts are written by me and which parts come from GPT-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1-brainstorming&#34;&gt;Part 1: Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did when I got access to GPT-3 is use it to brainstorm uses for GPT-3. I gave it these 5 ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain mathematics more simply (why is X true?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate programs from input/output examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate questions about a paper I read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a list of machine translation tips and tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an adventure game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it came back with 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a list of Tor commands to run to defend against an attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a cheat sheet for screenwriters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate advice for a scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate XKCD comics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a crib sheet for an arbitrary Python API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of movies to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of scholarly algorithms/heuristics worth reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of generic questions about Pedagogy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of cognitive exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show patterns generated by awesome people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate small cooking tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate characters for a project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate configuration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate flashcards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize my computer/files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain things to my parents via messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain things to my children via messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain mathematical algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated interface design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanize a Nagihara Kan Airlines website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clickbait generator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music description (Herbie Hancock is playing &amp;ldquo;Dolphin Dance&amp;rdquo; live in London on the 18th March 1968)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me not to waste my time looking at x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting facts about Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain something to someone while my attention is elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detect adverts in x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image caption/caption game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speculate about the true utility function of x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-generate tests for a program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why my code is currently failing tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then 15 more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate plots or character/story summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate legal examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate words for crosswords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check my grammar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supply filler text for themed writing (horror, sci-fi etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why an AI can&amp;rsquo;t read (can it comprehend metaphors?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide entertaining answers to obscure questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get writing ideas and generate word combinations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create background for an NPC I need for a D&amp;amp;D game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help a sick writer generate plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input pre-generated (from books etc.) phrases and use them for literary analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help explain a mathematical proof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a game/story/character I need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make short stories I can &amp;ldquo;overlay&amp;rdquo; on a fictional Universe I&amp;rsquo;ve created (ala Ready Player One)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a short film/audio drama&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a lovely list of lists of ideas! I wonder how many of these ideas are novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas are outside the scope of what GPT-3 can do. For example, generating XKCD comics seems too difficult. Others are duplicates, such as &amp;ldquo;Explain mathematical algorithms&amp;rdquo; (duplicate of &amp;ldquo;Explain mathematics more simply&amp;rdquo;). And still others don&amp;rsquo;t make sense &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Mechanize a Nagihara Kan Airlines website&amp;rdquo;? Overall though, solid set of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-mathematics&#34;&gt;Part 2: Mathematics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I&amp;rsquo;d gotten GPT-3 to do some brainstorming, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d need to test its capabilities before trying its suggestions out in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught it how to evaluate simple expressions and take derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the first prompt I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could then ask it any of the following, and it would correctly show its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Question: f(x) = tan(x) + 1. Compute f(0).
Question: f(x) = sqrt(x) + 1. Compute f(16).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to give it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it treated it as just &lt;code&gt;Compute f(16)&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;f(f(16))&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly this works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
f(f(16)) = f(16/2 + 2)
f(f(16)) = f(8 + 2)
f(f(16)) = f(10)
f(f(16)) = 10/2 + 2
f(f(16)) = 5 + 2
f(f(16)) = 7
Answer: 7

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

Question: f(x) = x*3 - 1. Compute f(f(5)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas this does not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Question: f(x) = x*x. Compute f(3).
f(3) = 3*3
f(3) = 9
Answer: 9

Question: h(x) = x*x - 2x. Compute h(5).
h(5) = 5*5 - 2*5
h(5) = 25 - 10
h(5) = 15
Answer: 15

Question: f(x) = x*3 - 1. Compute f(f(5)).
f(f(5)) = f(5*3 - 1)
f(f(5)) = f(15 - 1)
f(f(5)) = f(14)
f(f(5)) = 14*3 - 1
f(f(5)) = 42 - 1
f(f(5)) = 41
Answer: 41

Question: y(x) = x**3 - 2x. Compute y(3).
y(3) = 3**3 - 2*3
y(3) = 3*3*3 - 6
y(3) = 27 - 6
y(3) = 21
Answer: 21

Question: f(x) = x/2 + 2. Compute f(f(16)).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting it to evaluate these simple expressions correctly, I also tried having it take derivatives. With an example as priming, and again having it show its work, this worked well. I haven&amp;rsquo;t performed a rigorous evaluation of its mathematical capabilities. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve just begun to develop an intuition for how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-playing-around&#34;&gt;Part 3: Playing Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing math together, I tried many more things with GPT-3. I shared feelings with it, and it expanded on them (correctly too!). I used it to generate lists for brainstorming all manner of thing. The language model wrote love letters from inanimate objects. I tried to teach it to play Codenames, but with only very limited success. And I had it autocomplete previous snippets of mine, and had some fun cowriting with it. While I won&amp;rsquo;t be sharing all of this with you, I do have one thing to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a love letter written by a frying pan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may not seem like much to you right now. I&amp;rsquo;m coated in grease and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to rust, but really, I have big plans. I&amp;rsquo;m going to Italian restaurants. I&amp;rsquo;ll hang out with the finest (and healthiest) ingredients you can imagine. It was good knowing you, but you were never mine to keep. I&amp;rsquo;m going to cook the kind of meal you&amp;rsquo;ll dream about for the rest of your life. Good luck, sweetheart. You&amp;rsquo;ll need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-principles&#34;&gt;Overall Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an intuition for how GPT-3 behaves has been interesting, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try now to distill that intuition down into a few principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 is continuing your writing, not having a dialog with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on Twitter lots of people asking GPT-3 questions, and sharing its response. Know that GPT-3 continues whatever prompt you give it as if it had written the prompt itself, not as if it is responding to the prompt. This is why you often see prompts like &amp;ldquo;The following is a conversation between X and Y:&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 effectively puts your writing in a made up context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give GPT-3 a small prompt, such a single sentence, then there are many contexts in which that prompt could be interpreted. GPT-3 is trained to marginalize over the contexts in which the text could appear. Once you start decoding GPT-3&amp;rsquo;s response though, one implicit context has been selected. It might not be the context that you intended when writing your prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can happen even if you try to set the context yourself explicitly. For example you might be trying to generate a conversation or a list, and GPT-3 might decide that this conversation or list is taking place inside of a novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can mitigate this context switch by using a longer prompt, or by doing more of the writing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 likes lists and repeated structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main principle behind using GPT-3 for few shot learning. Prompt GPT-3 with a few examples of performing a task, and it will usually make an effort to perform that task yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 cannot perform linguistic tricks like unscrambling words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem capable of generating new puns (I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried this yet).
And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem capable of unscrambling words (I did try this, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get it to unscramble 4-letter words).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 benefits from &amp;ldquo;showing its work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my math experiments, having GPT-3 show its work was critical to getting it solving the math questions correctly. It seems that doing a single step of expression evaluation at a time is an easier task than doing it all at once. Providing examples with the steps gave GPT-3 a clearer explanation of the task than just providing input/output examples. GPT-3 also gets additional computational steps in which to solve the problem when it takes the time to show its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 has a great breadth of knowledge and writing styles available to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can express love, write flowery prose, give advice, write technical documentation, latex, program, math, take the perspective of a toaster, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s a great tool for brainstorming both explicitly (by having it generate ideas) and through exploration (by using it to help you generate ideas yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it has all the facts from the internet at its fingertips (of all the ways to anthropomorphize GPT-3, why choose fingertips?), it is just as capable of generating falsehoods as truths. Do not mistake the text it generates as true or logically correct, even if in many circumstances it does generate correct information. When it transitions from generating truth to generating nonsense it does not give a warning that it has done so (and any truth it does generate is in a sense at least partially accidental).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes GPT-3 makes no sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense that the language model assigns reasonable probabilities to. And there are things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense, are low probability, but come up anyway either due to chance or because the model doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything better to say. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop generating text just because its out of its depth. Instead, it just plods on forward, saying something as reasonable as it&amp;rsquo;s capable of, regardless of the situation it finds itself in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-3 mimics your style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prompt GPT-3 with typos it will continue with typos. If you prompt GPT-3 with florid prose, it will write florid prose. If you prompt GPT-3 with anaphora laden rhetoric, or any other style, it will continue in that style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let GPT-3 wrap things up itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And that brings us to the end, some thoughts on whether using GPT-3 was more or less crazy than getting a Ph.D.. I think that using GPT-3 to generate ideas was a higher form of Enlightenment than any Ph.D. I&amp;rsquo;d do that again in a heartbeat, no shortage of ideas rolling around in GPT-3&amp;rsquo;s natural language processing head.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uh huh. Whatever, GPT-3. Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Assistant Tool Idea</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2020-01-13-writing-tool-idea/</guid>
      
        <message>A structured question-asking tool may be useful for writing effectively.</message>
      
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-writing-is-hard&#34;&gt;Background: Writing is Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I find writing feels easy &amp;ndash; e.g. when 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/snippets/2019-12-30-writing-for-no-audience/&#34;&gt;writing for no audience&lt;/a&gt;, when writing something you&amp;rsquo;ve already thought extensively about, when telling a story in a logical order that you&amp;rsquo;re deeply familiar with. Other times, I find writing very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m writing a paper, I am writing explicitly for an audience, the story is not always clear immediately, and the material is something I&amp;rsquo;m becoming familiar with over time, not something about which I&amp;rsquo;m already deeply familiar.
So, I find paper writing hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an idea that I think will help me write more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s a software tool that structures the time you spend writing. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the tool, but I don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate building it. Perhaps we can come up with a low-resource version of this idea, e.g. with paper and pencil, that I can try even without building this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-writing-system&#34;&gt;The Writing System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool presents you with a prompt, a textbox, and a timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial prompt is &amp;ldquo;What do you want to write about?&amp;rdquo;, and the initial timer is for 5 minutes. Subsequent prompts will be determined from what you&amp;rsquo;ve entered in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the textbox, you are encouraged to respond to the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of your response, you can issue some commands / keywords.
If you start a line with &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;, then that line will get used as a future prompt.
You can specify the relative importance of a future prompt by including a priority.
This will determine the order in which you are presented with the prompts.
E.g. &lt;code&gt;!0&lt;/code&gt; is highest priority, and so such a line will become the next prompt you receive, unless there are other priority 0 prompts already queued up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;! &amp;lt;topic&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I want to write about later&amp;rdquo;
&lt;code&gt;? &amp;lt;question&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is short for &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;question&amp;gt; is a question I want to answer later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should also be a way to indicate &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt; is a topic I&amp;rsquo;ll need to do more research on&amp;rdquo;, and then for one of the prompts to be about spending time researching a topic, rather than writing about it. Then the next prompt may be to write about what you just learned in the research section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other available commands include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:pause&lt;/code&gt; to stop the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:unpause&lt;/code&gt; to start the timer again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:extend&lt;/code&gt; to add additional time to the timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:next&lt;/code&gt; to skip to the next prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is easily extensible, so a writer with a programming background can easily add new commands, or modify the logic that determines when prompts are shown and when breaks are taken. A programming-proficient writer will also have programmatic access to everything they write, as well as the corresponding prompts and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the timer reaches 0, a short break is initiated, and then the next prompt is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to move quickly, and get all your thoughts onto the page, without getting bogged down in a DFS traversal of information about a single line of the overall text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-details&#34;&gt;Additional details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every keystroke is logged, so if you write something, and then switch to a new version of it, you will still be able to see the original version. No need to worry about pasting in a password though, since the keylogging data is readily accessible in a plaintext format and you can edit it directly e.g. if anything sensitive does leak in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has a decent amount of overlap with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidbieber.com/projects/shh-shell&#34;&gt;shh shell&lt;/a&gt; project that I&amp;rsquo;ve already built,
and perhaps a version of this new idea could be easily added to the shh shell. Alternatively, the shh-shell could be forked to build this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar integration would be cool, so that it times your prompts nicely if you have a meeting coming up so you get to a good break point in time for your meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation-thoughts&#34;&gt;Implementation Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to build this onto an existing text editor, rather than writing my own. E.g. using Google Docs would be good.
However, the disadvantage of this is that it makes the keystroke logging feature more difficult. Fortunately, Google Docs does have good history tracking. Google Docs also provides good programmatic access. So, an agent running in the background while you write could be taking periodic snapshots too. Such an agent could also be extracting the commands and prompts you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to execute the commands immediately, the way shh shell does. For some commands this may be a real disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like the idea of the agent giving the prompts being Bieber Bot &amp;ndash; that is, being the same &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; as my personal digital assistant. I can picture it asking me &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve been writing continuously for over an hour; is it time for a break?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it looks like you stopped writing abruptly there, did you get distracted?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-experimentation&#34;&gt;Initial Experimentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying the idea out in a low-tech way (manually timing things, manually looking up what the next prompt should be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the main issue I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the first half hour of testing. When the time runs out for a prompt, I&amp;rsquo;m still in the middle of the prompt. I&amp;rsquo;ve usually started expounding on some idea relevant to the prompt, and there are actually several ideas remaining that I haven&amp;rsquo;t even started exploring for the prompt yet. So what should have happened / what should I do next time? Maybe I could have done a higher level discussion of the prompt and made new future sub-prompts along the way. Or at the end of a section, I could have the system give me a bit of time to create sub-prompts of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to address in the section but didn&amp;rsquo;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see having a limited time to create new prompts be a good forcing function for coming up with structured high level thinking after a moderate amount of time of lower level writing. So in my next round of testing, I&amp;rsquo;ll try this, and continue to iterate on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapsible Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbieber.com/post/2012-09-04-collapsible-blog-posts/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_hello&#34;&gt;This is my Hello World blog post of sorts. It&#39;s my introduction to the world of blogging, the blog post likely only read by my family and a few techie friends. It&#39;s the post in which I make an unrealistic commitment to blog frequently, which I later fail to live up to. And it&#39;s the post in which I introduce a new form of blogging, &lt;u&gt;Collapsible Blogging&lt;/u&gt;. Here&#39;s the tl;dr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_hello&#34;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_tldr&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Click any part of this post to see it in condensed form.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Source is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3616675&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/3616675&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_tldr&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Click stuff to collapse. Click again to expand.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_commit&#34;&gt;Before we get into the details of Collapsible Blogging, let&#39;s start with that commitment to blog. Every half-baked blog has it, so here&#39;s mine. Once a month. I know my life is sufficiently not boring that something blog-worthy will come along each month. Why, just last Tuesday I ran with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyson_Mao&#34;&gt;Tyson Mao&lt;/a&gt; (yeah, the Rubik&#39;s Cube guy) and had a near encounter with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Hammond&#34;&gt;Top Gear&#39;s Richard Hammond&lt;/a&gt; (he came by Twitter while I was interning there). This post counts for September. So you&#39;ll be hearing from me next at least before Halloween&#39;s end. Here&#39;s to a happy, healthy, blogging career!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_commit&#34;&gt;I&#39;ll blog once a month. And I like name dropping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_skim&#34;&gt;
So, how&#39;s this whole Collapsible Blogging thing work, why is it awesome, and how can you try it out? Collapsible Blogging works well with my own internet content consumption habits, which I believe I share with many of the other Hacker News obsessed entrepreneurial spirited folks out there on the internet. Possibly you. I choose an interesting Hacker News article, I read a bit, and I quickly lose interest in favor of another well titled article. My goal is really just to consume quickly the highlights of the web. Collapsible Blogging let&#39;s me skim faster. But maybe that&#39;s a not a good thing. I&#39;m rereading Fahrenheit 451- and there&#39;s a passage this reminds me of:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sometimes think drivers don&amp;rsquo;t know what grass is, or flowers, because they never
see them slowly,&amp;rdquo; and&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Have you seen the two-hundred-foot-long billboards in the country beyond town? Did you know that once billboards were only twenty feet long? But cars started rushing by so quickly they had to stretch the advertising out so it would last.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t want Collapsible Blogging to be those two-hundred-foot-long billboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_skim&#34;&gt;
Use Collapsible Blogging to make your content easier to skim.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_expand&#34;&gt;
So with that in mind, I introduce the second use of Collapsible Blogging. Diving deeper into a topic. If you&#39;d like to learn more about diving deeper into a topic, click this passage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_expand&#34;&gt;
Collapsible Blogging let&#39;s people who aren&#39;t interested in the topic read quickly, while people like yourselves who want the full blog post can read more in a single click, as you just discovered. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One application of this is resumes. On my resume I list that I have experience with Java, Python, etc. An employer may care just about my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quora.com/Have-I-fallen-in-love-with-Python-because-she-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;lovely Python&lt;/a&gt; experience, but my resume doesn&#39;t go into details about each technical skill and where I&#39;ve used them. If I build my resume with Collapsible Blogging, I can make it so that with a single click potential employers can learn more about my experience with just the skills that interests them. They can learn what matters to them without me cluttering my resume with every project I&#39;ve ever worked on.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Likewise, say I write a blog post about my experiences at Twitter and Facebook. You might be interested in reading about the technical challenges I faced and the programming concepts I learned, while another reader might be more curious about the pool party I attended at Zuck&#39;s house. If I write my post using Collapsible Blogging, you, the reader, can choose to read about the parts of my experience that interest you most, or you can choose to just skim the collapsed form of the post.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some paragraphs don&#39;t have collapsed forms. You can only collapse the passages with a left border. There isn&#39;t really a shorter way to say that!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you&#39;re interested in using Collapsible Blogging yourself, it&#39;s remarkable easy. I include the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3616675&#34;&gt;source as a gist&lt;/a&gt; below. Each passage that I want to collapse, I give an id. Then I create an element with the same id but preceded by an underscore. The CSS below hides elements with ids starting with underscores, and the JS below uses JQuery to handle the swapping in and out of elements. If you&#39;re blogging with Tumblr, just paste the code into your theme and you&#39;re good to go! Anywhere else, it should be as simple as adding the JS and CSS to your page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;cbp_tryit&#34;&gt;Try it. You&#39;ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;_cbp_tryit&#34;&gt;Inspired to try blogging by a few of my friends: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dskang.com&#34;&gt;Dan Kang&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.harvestzhang.com&#34;&gt;Harvest Zhang&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks guys! Keep on writing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4477488&#34;&gt;Discuss on hacker news.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dbieber/3616675.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>